hey guys this is mitch with
fine boy cgi and today we're
going to continue our nakama tutorial
series where i take you from
zero to understanding all the fundamentals
of nakama and in this video
we're going to talk about how
to do groups so that's going
to allow you to add users
to like
a guild or like a group
setting then we're going to talk
about doing chats and chatting between
each other so sending messages to
each other and finally due to
popular request i'm going
to talk about how to host
your nakama instance out on the
internet so that you can play
games
with your friends or of course
you can release your game out
to make it into a multiplayer
game
so that's what i have in
store for you guys today so
let's go ahead and get started
all right so this tutorial assumes
that you already completed the previous
tutorial where we
actually integrated nakama for the most
part so this one's going to
be going over more of
the features and things like that
so i'm going to go ahead
and get started so let's get
started
so let's go ahead and get
started with that and the first
thing we're going to talk about
is creating groups so groups are
basically like a guild or a
team of people that want to
play
with each other multiple times not
necessarily as a party but as
an actual group so after the
game is ended and everything is
done you still have access to
that group of people so the
first
thing that i'm going to do
is i'm going to come in
here and i'm going to hide
our friend section
because we're actually running out of
space here and i really should
name all of these but that's
probably going to brick all of
my code so we'll go ahead
and just hide that panel go
ahead and
add in a new panel like
so i'm going to go over
here make it about this big
give or take i'm
going to right click add a
child node we'll add in a
label like that we're going to
make it about
this big and we'll have a
name parameter there we'll
go ahead and duplicate it and
say description
and then we'll come in here
right click add a child node
and we'll add in a line
edit like so
and we'll make it about this
big give or take we'll control
duplicate that
and we'll make it about this
big i mean technically the description
should be a
little bit longer but that's okay
we'll make it work for what
we're gonna do so that's
fine
and i'll just kind of organize
this properly then we'll add in
a button and this button's
going to allow us to create
a group now i'm going to
need multiple buttons but for right
now we'll
just do one i think so
we'll go ahead and say create
group like so and i'll probably
need to
make this panel larger to be
honest i'm running out of space
here so we'll go ahead and
just make
this a touch bit bigger like
so now when we want to
create a group all we have
to do is if we grab
this button
name it create group like so
we'll go into our node button
down and we'll hook that to
our control
node just like that now you'll
see when i hook it to
the control node it should create
a create group button down function
it looks like i already did
this in a previous section
so i'm going to go ahead
and get rid of that that's
my fault that caught me off
guard real
quick but
To create a group, all we
have to do is say client
.createGroupAsync, and then we can pass
in our session like so, and
then we have to pass in
a name.
Now, the name is whatever the
name is that we put as
our line edit.
Now, if we take a look,
we have our name right here.
So we'll say group name and
then group description like so, and
then we'll go back to our
script
and we'll do dollar sign, group
name, comma, or dot text, comma,
dollar sign, group description,
dot text, comma, and then you'll
see that they have the option
for an avatar URL.
Now, you don't have to supply
one, but you can.
And that's really cool because it
basically would allow you to have
some kind of URL for
an image that you could load
for their group.
So I'm going to put that
as empty.
Comma, and then you'll see that
they have a language.
So we'll say their main language
is EN.
It doesn't really matter necessarily, but
it is a thing that exists.
And actually I need to, I'm
messing up my little things here.
We'll put an empty URL.
We'll put a EN for the
avatar title, and then you can
choose whether
or not it's an open or
if it's not.
So an open means if it's
a public group.
So if people can actually.
See it and index it for
other people.
So if you say false, then
it's a private group.
So if you don't want it
to be listable, which we'll discuss
listing in a little
bit, but it allows you to
basically say, is this a listable
group?
So I'm going to say true
because it makes sense to have
a listable group, and then
you can have a max number
of members.
Now, once this is set, you
can not change it.
So make sure you set it
to a value that you want.
So if a guild can only
have 64 members, then you set
it to 64.
If it's a hundred members, then
you can set it to a
hundred.
So in my case, I'm going
to say 32, just because 32
is just a good round number.
Now, after that, there is nothing
else that we can do.
So we'll go ahead and just
say 32.
Now, typically this also returns a
group API.
So you could say var group
is equal to await client asynchronous.
And then we can just go
ahead and print out that group.
Now you don't have to do
this, but it is a way
to get ahold of that
object, if that makes sense.
Okay.
So if you needed to go
ahead and make your group, you
know, visible or not
visible or something like that, you
could do that right here.
So now if we go ahead
and make sure that our Nakama
instance is running.
So if I take a look
at my containers, you can see
it is actually running.
So there we go.
We'll go ahead and hit play.
And then we're going to go
ahead and submit.
We're going to connect to our
game.
We're going to call our group
test group.
Description.
This is our test group and
we'll click create.
Now you'll see that we have
a error group name must be
set.
So I must've messed up on
my group name.
So let's take a look panel
five group name.
Oh, I made a mistake because
this is the original panel.
I did some recording earlier that,
um, I didn't keep it, but
I
never actually removed that panel.
So we'll change this to panel.
And then we'll go from there.
So we'll refresh this and try
this one more time.
That's my fault.
So we'll submit test group.
This is a test group, create
group, and you'll see that we
get a success right there.
So now I'm going to navigate
to one, two, seven Nakama console
right here.
So we'll go to our one,
two, seven, seven, three, five, one,
and then
we will connect into our Nakama
group.
If we go to groups, you
will see there is our test
group.
And you can see, this is
what we have.
If we take a look at
our members, you can see that
there is a super admin.
So what in the world is
a super admin?
Well, a super admin is a
person that has full control over
that group.
So this person, JJ RB V
W E X K I is
a super admin of that group.
So what that means is that
they have the ability to read.
They have the ability to delete
that group.
And when you are a super
admin, you have full control over
that group.
There are four different membership states.
They're super admin, which means that
you are basically God.
You can do whatever you want
to this group.
You can delete people.
You can do whatever you want.
Basically you can delete the group
and that's a big thing admin,
which allows
you to update your group.
And.
Allow you to accept.
Kick, promote, delete, ban, or promote
members.
And then they have members, which
allows you to actually have a
regular group member.
They don't have the ability to
do anything.
They cannot accept join requests, stuff
like that.
And then they have the join
request mode, which basically is when
a user wants to join,
they need to be accepted.
So you have to say, yes,
I will accept you as a
part of a group.
And that's how, you know, the
different states, if that makes sense.
So if we go to our
user.
Management, we look for the JJR
person.
If we go into accounts, I
have a bunch of usernames here
because I've
been doing a lot of testing
on my end.
But if I look for JJ,
let me see.
I think it's JJ.
Let me take a look.
Members name, JJRB, JJRB.
Well, that person, let me see
JJ.
I have 71 accounts.
So you can see, I have
a bunch of accounts cause I've
been doing a lot of testing.
On my end for my own
stuff and Nakama is being difficult.
So let me refresh JJRB.
Well, apparently JJ doesn't exist within
my vast number of people.
So I'm not sure why it
did that, but that's okay.
There's probably a master account that
it's using.
Actually it's right here.
JJRB.
Right here.
So I'm not sure why it
used this specific one, unless I
logged in and created it
with device authentication, which is possible,
but that's okay.
We'll figure that out in a
minute, but that's basically how we
create a group.
Now you can see, we also
printed out a group as well.
So you can see here, we
have our creator ID, which is
right here.
The creator ID is DB.
So this is the creator ID.
So our creator.
Is JJ.
So we must have logged in
with device authentication, which means I
probably
didn't reset my client authentication stuff.
So let me take a look
at that real quick.
My apologies.
I, um, may not have reset
some of my code so that
it worked properly.
Did user authentication instead of our,
um, device authentication.
So my guess is that's probably
what it is.
So if I go to log
in.
Yeah, right here, I'm doing a
unique device ID right here, and
I'm logging
in with that socket connection.
So that's, what's going on here.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to control K
to comment that out.
And I'm going to go ahead
and log in with my username.
So now I'm going to go
in here and I'll reset this
because it's going to be
kind of difficult to have a
group that, uh, exists that's not
tied to an actual user.
So I'll go ahead and do
that.
I'll refresh.
And then we're going to recreate
that group just because it makes
more sense.
So I'll say test group description.
This is a test group and
we'll go ahead and create that
group.
Now, if we take a look
at our Nakama console, you will
see that because this
was created by test, that person
is the super admin.
So whoever creates the group gets
super admin status.
Now, in order to add users,
it's actually relatively easy.
Also.
We need to do is go
in to our project here and
you can see right here,
we have the ability to create
a group.
So we'll just go ahead and
duplicate this and we will come
down here
and we'll right click disconnect.
We're going to go in here,
connect and say on add user.
We'll say add a underscore user,
underscore two group, like so button
down.
And we'll.
Go ahead and connect that.
And I'm going to rename this
to add user to group.
So with this for us to
be able to add users to
group, it's actually really easy.
All we need to do is
pass in the group ID that
we want to add ourselves to.
So unfortunately we have to actually
pull that user identifier.
So if you look at this,
you can see inside of our
groups, we have a user ID
right.
Here.
This is the identifier that we
need to give them to be
able to add ourselves to that
group.
So if we come in here
and copy this, we can come
down here, go back into Godot.
And then basically just say, await
client dot join group async, and
then do session comma.
And then we'll just pass in
that group identifier.
Now, if we come in here
and we hit play, you'll see
in.
A second, we'll go ahead and
log in as test two.
We will type test.
I mean, it doesn't really matter
and you can see the text
here is wrong, but that's okay.
We'll click create group, which is
technically ad group.
And you'll see that we get
an authorization token right here.
We got a four Oh four
group, not found.
So my guess is that I
have the wrong identifier, go to
group group ID.
I do.
So we'll go ahead and copy
that.
And we'll go back here.
We'll change this guy like, so
paste control S.
And the nice thing about Godot
is that if you just change
the code in here, you can
just click that and you can
see that it should work.
And that's because Godot is a
non-compiled language.
So you can actually get away
with changing it and re-executing
the code.
So now, if you look at
members, you can see test two
is now a member.
Now you might be wondering, okay.
So anybody can join.
My group.
Yes.
Anyone can join your group as
long as it is public.
If it's not public, then you
have to be approved.
So that's where the difference comes
in.
So if I come in here,
I remove test two, I go
to details and I change this
to not open and I save
it.
Now, if I go ahead and
I hit create group, or I
guess connect to the group, you
can see.
That there is a join request.
And that means that I have
to approve that before they can
be a part of the group.
So the question is, how do
you actually accept that join request?
Well, to accept a join request,
which you need to do is
you need to come in here
and actually code out a small
subroutine.
First thing first, I'm going to
come in here and change this
to add join group like that.
And then.
And then I'm going to go
ahead and duplicate this guy, drag
this guy down like, so, and
I'm going to say, add user.
To group like, so, and if
I just hit enter, that will
help with formatting this button a
little bit better.
Now we'll pull this name parameter
to allow ourselves to actually, you
know, go from there and this
should probably be called join group.
So.
It'll be fine, I guess for
now, but it's just something I'm
not a huge fan of, but
that's okay.
So we'll go ahead and click
node, right?
Click disconnect, connect, and then we'll
go ahead and create that little
function there.
Now to accept a join request,
you need to be able to
list your groups or your users
inside of that group.
And that's really easy to do.
We can basically just say var
users is equal to await client.
List group users, async like that,
we can pass in our session
token, and then we can pass
in our group ID.
Now our group ID is right
here.
So we'll go ahead and copy
that and paste it, and then
we'll hit comma, and then we
can actually have a different state.
So this is where that one,
two, or I guess, zero one,
two, and three is useful.
If you wanted to, you could
list everyone that is a member
of the group.
Everyone that's waiting to join the
group and anybody that's a super
user or an admin, just by
changing this from zero through three.
In our case, we're going to
be grabbing all the people that
are awaiting for their joins.
You can see the state is
three, so we will go ahead
and do that.
And then all we need to
do is come in here and
say for user in users dot
group, underscore users.
Okay.
And then we're going to go
ahead and say for user in
users, colon, var u is equal
to user dot user, and then
await client dot add group users,
async, pass in our session right
here, comma, what our group ID
is, which in this case is
this guy right here.
So we'll pass that guy in,
comma, and then we'll pass in
u.
And now we'll go ahead and
add.
Add that person.
So now if I refresh and
I go add user to group.
So if I submit, I log
in as the test user and
I click add user to group,
you'll see that we got an
error here, unable to convert, uh,
argument three to pack string array.
So you is not correct.
So let's take a look at
what you is real quick.
I don't think there's really an
easy way to handle this without
going bracket.
Bracket and then passing in dot
ID and then just using their
ID.
I think that that will work.
It's not the most ideal way
to fix it, but if I
log in, I hit add user.
You should see a nice request
here, and then we'll go ahead
and refresh this and you can
see that they are now a
member.
And that's because when we built
the group, we made it a
private group that you might be
wondering, is there a way for
us to make.
Make a group private or public
through code, right?
So that way it doesn't have
to happen immediately on start.
And the answer to your question
is yes, you can actually do
that pretty easily.
All you need to do is
come in here, go in here.
Let's grab this, make it slightly
bigger.
Again, the group section is going
to be very large for this.
So we'll add in a check
box here, like, so, and we'll
call it open.
Like that.
And then we're going to add
in a toggle switch.
So I'll just put this right
here for right now.
We'll call it open.
That's fine.
And then we'll go ahead and
say on button down, or I
guess on toggled, we'll toggle this
on our control node.
And basically when it gets toggled,
it'll show you yes or no.
So we'll say await client dot
update group asynchronously.
We'll pass in our.
Yes.
And then we'll pass in the
session token.
Comma, our group ID, which is
this guy right here.
And we'll talk about how to
get that group ID through code
in a second, comma, and then
the name of the group, which
I'll pass in.
No, because I don't want to
change it.
And then we'll pass in toggled
underscore on like that.
And you'll see that.
If I come in here.
here and I submit, and then
I click open.
You'll see if we refresh our
Nakama instance here.
So we'll refresh this page.
You'll see it's not open.
If we close it, it should
hopefully do it real quick.
Maybe not.
Let's take a look.
Let's do a break point here.
I could just be crazy.
So if I come in here,
toggle response code 400, specify at
least one field to update.
Let's see if we come in
here, comma, P name, P description,
variant null.
So no comma description, no comma
avatar, no comma language tag, en
comma.
Now this is how you update
any of your parameters, by the
way.
So now we have our P
open.
I think that's why.
So we'll come in here, submit,
we do that, and then we
take a look at our
user name, which is the user
name of the group, the description
of the group,
and the whether or not it's
open or not.
So you can actually really play
around here and update any of
these values.
So now if we hit play
in theory, it should just work.
So we'll come in here, submit.
We do that.
And then we take a look
at our user name.
And then if we go back
to our group here, we refresh,
you'll see that open is now
on.
If we set it to off
and we refresh, you'll see that
it is now closed.
So that's how you can open
and close it.
And that's really how you can
update any of these values.
So if I came in here,
if I come back to Godot
here and I grab my description,
I believe that's name, description, avatar,
URL.
So if I named this, the
And then I changed the description
to, we are the strong gamers,
exclamation point.
If I come in here and
I hit this little toggle here,
well, our session got DC.
So let me refresh this guy
real quick.
Let me re log in and
then I'll change it.
So now it's going to be
open and the titles and everything
has been changed.
Strong gamers.
We are the strong.
Gamers.
So that's how you can update
those values.
Now, again, typically you wouldn't use
a toggle switch to do this.
I'm just showing you guys how
to do that.
So I can show you the
open and close really quickly.
You can see now it's closed.
So that's how you can update
that group visibility.
That's how you can update the
group values, information values for your
group.
Now, something else that's pretty big
and pretty important to know is
how to
actually.
List groups.
So Nakama, uh, groups are a
resource like anything else, right?
So you can actually list them
and index them and pull back
information using them.
So what does that mean?
Well, that means that you can
use what's called list groups asynchronously
to
actually list out your groups.
So if I come in here,
I can show you guys how
that works.
So I'm going to write.
Click, add in a panel like,
so I'll drag this guy over
here like this, and I will
make an H box container, or
I guess it'd be a V
box container like so, and I'll
make that full wrecked so that
way it maximizes the full screen
now, granted
that being said, we only have
one group right now, so we
kind of need to make
multiple groups for us to be
able to see them all, but
we can at least show how
that works.
So if we come in here,
I grab this add user to
group button.
I duplicate it, bring it down
here and I type list groups
like so, and then
I'm going to grab this description,
duplicate it, pull it down here,
and
this is going to be group
query.
Like, so I'll change this to
list groups and I'll change this
to.
Group.
Query.
Now, what we can do is
hit control S we can go
into scripting.
We can grab our list group,
go to node, right click, disconnect,
right click,
connect and connect it.
Now, what we could do when
we want to list our groups
is we can set up a
limit.
So we can say var limit
is equal to, let's say 10.
Now we don't have 10 groups
to list, but we'll use that
as a default value.
Then we'll say var result is
equal to await client dot list
groups, async.
Now you'll need to pass in
your session just like usual, and
then you'll need to
pass in some kind of name
that you're trying to search up.
Now this is a variant.
So of course you can, you
know, get back whatever you're looking
for.
So in my case, I'm going
to hit dollar sign.
Group query dot text, and that'll
let me have that limit.
And then we'll pass in our
limit, which by the way, does
default to 10.
Now they have a cursor value
and that cursor value allows you
to say, I want the next
10.
So think of it kind of
like this.
When you do your query, you're
going to pull back the first
10, but what happens if the
person doesn't see the group that
they want on the first 10?
Well, that's where the cursor value
comes in.
So you can hit zero, make
that cursor value of zero.
All of this will interrupt.
Language tag will allow you to
pick a language.
In my case, I'm going to
do en.
And again, you don't have to
do that, but it's going to
filter out any groups
that are not English.
You can see right here, language
en, so that's going to allow
you to have
that limiting factor, right?
Because if they're Spanish, you don't
want to necessarily show them up
if
they're looking for an English group.
If they speak English, not Spanish,
it's going to be a problem.
And then.
You can.
can look up members which allows
you to pick members i'm going
to pass in null for that
and
then you could choose whether or
not it's an open group or
not so a lot of times
when you're doing
groups you might want to check
to see if it's a public
group not a private group because
sometimes
if you have a group like
a guild and you don't want
people to see your guild you
probably should
make sure that that is false
or true depending on your use
case so i'll make it true
and that's
pretty much everything that you need
to know here now with this
we should be relatively good to
go
so now we basically will have
our results we can say for
group in result dot groups like
that
and then we can basically come
in and print out
our groups so you can see
that we can go print group
dot name like that
and from here we should be
relatively good to go so now
we can hit play we can
log in as test
we can come in here and
say i believe our group name
is strong gamers so we can
say
strong and list groups and it'll
be a little bit less of
a mess but it'll be a
little bit more
should come back well it's not
happy so that's not a good
thing our p cursor query parameters
strong that's fine not going to
serialize escape
cannot convert argument one from int
to string
i wonder if it's mad because
our cursor is an int i
think there's an issue here with
how they
have their stuff set up so
what if we come back here
and we do null instead so
if we come in here
null just to see if that
fixes the problem so we'll come
in here we'll type strong
and it's still mad oh that's
because i didn't log in so
that's fair that's understandable so we'll
log in we will say strong
list groups and you can see
that we get a 400 the
error name filter cannot
be combined with any other filter
so it looks like according to
nakama's documentation you can
combine them but i guess you
can't inside of here so let's
try that and see if that
fixes it
because according to our documentation we
can't combine them but i guess
you can't
documentation you can do this but
i guess we can't so let's
try that
so we'll hit list groups and
you will see that we get
an authorization bearing right here i
don't
know if that came back with
really anything so let me see
what happens if i list groups
let's
see what our result comes back
with after i drop a breakpoint
here and it did it came
back with
nothing so nakama is not going
to be able to do that
so we're going to try that
again
not doing what i want it
to do because of course it's
not welcome to programming let's see
what
happens if i do capital s
it's probably capital
case sensitive so we'll come in
here and we'll take a look
at our result still got nothing
back
so we'll continue through what happens
if i do a percent sign
and see if that gives us
something back now
because it might be that it
needs to be a query of
some description so we can
check that out real quick yep
it needs to be a query
so you can see it pulled
back the one
that we're looking for so it
pulled back our group so when
you do a text just be
aware of
that you're going to need to
make it into an actual query
instead so you need to add
that
percent sign at the end so
that's just something to keep in
mind now you'll see when i
hit play
it's going to pull back our
group and it's going to pull
back our group and it's going
to pull back
our group and it's going to
print out strong gamers right there
so that's basically how you
can list and filter your groups
so that allows us to see
those groups and hunt down their
identifier
because if you look you can
see when i list the groups
you can see when i come
in here and i take
a look at my results here
the group i come back with
has their identifier right here so
if you
know where their um if you
know their name you can pull
back their id so that's how
we would
populate all these other values right
here is by listing it and
then pulling back that group
information now since we can pull
this information that means that we
can actually come in here and
use that info on our panels
and things like that so what
we could do is
we could come in here and
list out their information and populate
it in a vbox container
so we could do is we
could go var vbox is equal
to vbox container dot new like
that and then
if i need if i do
this correctly equals vbox container dot
new
and then we could come in
here and do the same thing
but for labels so we can
say
label so var name label is
equal to a label dot new
like that and then name label
dot text is
equal to if we take a
look at this right here we
can go name so it would
be group dot
let's take a look at this
what is result dot groups let's
see result dot groups so it's
going to come back with this
so
it would be dot name like
that and then we could say
vbox
dot add child and then we
could add our name label as
a part of that child and
then
we can come in here and
say dollar sign vbox and we
can find out which panel is
ours which
arguably we should come up with
a better naming convention here but
that's fine dot add child
and we could add in our
vbox right here like that and
that would allow us to effectively
add it as a
child for our project and then
if we refresh this in theory
providing that this is going to
work
and i don't know if it's
going to work this is kind
of me coding this a little
bit off the cuff
we can hit list groups and
you can see that we now
have strong gamers there so that's
something
that we can actually do and
pull back their information so that
could be really useful for
us to set up for like
a selection system or something like
that and speaking of that what
we could do is we could
come in here and say var
hbox is equal to hbox container
dot new like so and then
we can do hbox dot let's
see if we bring this down
here instead of doing
vbox dot add we could do
hbox and then we could add
our vbox
dot add child hbox like so
and then what that means is
that we could add in a
button
and i know this is kind
of weird because i'm actually coding
this and i'm not sure if
it's
a component instead of doing it
the other way but one of
the big things that people have
asked
me is if you could actually
do it this way and i
want to cover that and show
you guys yeah you can
actually build interface elements inside of
code and then actually have it
exist so that's kind of
what i'm showing here so if
we come in here and say
h var button is equal to
button dot new like so
then we can come in here
and do button dot text is
equal to select group like that
and then we can
come in here and say hbox
dot add child button like that
and then we can add that
hbox and that
should allow us to have all
of that information that we were
looking for before right here so
if
we hit submit list groups you
can see we have a button
right here
so now we can basically connect
its on button click right here
so you can say button dot
button down like that dot dot
connect and then we could just
say
and here we could call out
a function so if i come
in here and say funk on
group select button down and i
can pass
in the group like that and
i could come in here and
do dot connect and we could
do what's called
binding and binding is actually really
cool so we can say on
group select button like that
dot bind and then i can
bind parameters so i can actually
come in here and bind
group and now if we come
in here and we print out
that group you'll see
providing that we did this correctly
and i know that this is
like way beyond what the actual
tutorial is but i think that
this is pretty cool so i
figured i would show it off
if we do this we
can come in here and list
our groups and then select a
group and you'll see that it
passes in
that information right there it binds
the parameters so you could actually
come in here
and set a selected group parameter
right here and there you go
it would actually
work so what we could do
is we could come in here
and say all the way up
here set our
var selected group and then we
could come down here and just
say
selected group is equal to group
like that and then we could
come in here
and do i believe it's group
dot id so you could come
in here
go selected group.id like that
copy this bad boy go like
this paste and paste and paste
and then
you would be able to effectively
update the values in there without
needing to actually have that data
so if i come in here
i list my groups well first
i need to actually hook up
my session really quick
so if i submit that there
we go
i list my groups i select
it now i have that selected
i can come in here
and do a open and you
will see that if i come
in here and i refresh this
you'll see that that worked and
that's because we bound that parameter
right here well if i
could find it right here to
actually work so that's a way
that we can go about making
a
group selection system relatively simple and
that's how we can actually list
our groups
as well so i know that
that's kind of a complicated way
to show it but i figured
that it was an interesting way
to approach it and i figured
you guys would appreciate that
so now the question is what
if we want to promote a
user or maybe demote a user
or
kick or ban a user from
our group well in order to
do that first we need to
actually
get the user id of that
person so you can see here
this person is a member and
we want to get that
id back so if we come
back to godot here and we
go ahead and come down here
we need to basically
get a username go and fetch
their id and then basically promote
or demote that person so what
i'm going to do is i'm
going to right click my panel
i'm going to add in a
line edit like so i'm
going to drag this guy down
here we'll go like this make
it about i don't know about
that big
we'll come in here we'll say
user
user to manage we'll say and
then we'll come in here and
hopefully we won't run out of
space
if we do we'll figure something
out but let's right click add
in a child node let's add
in a
button we'll add in a button
for promoting right here like so
and if i think about it
for a second with groups we
need to promote demote kick and
ban something
and then also leave that group
so we'll need to figure out
a way to give ourselves a
little bit
more space here because i'm running
out so maybe i can drag
this guy up butt it up
a little bit
closer drag this guy down give
ourselves a little bit more space
but we can promote duplicate kick
demote
and then i blooded
we would need to ban somebody
and then finally the last interaction
that we need to do is
to
actually come in here and leave
so we could just come over
ah goodness we're running out of
space
here we have so much functionality
here it's actually hard to make
the space so we'll drag
this guy down a tiny bit
maybe give ourselves a bit more
space over here drag this guy
over like
so there we go and we
can change this one to leave
group like that now when we
want to promote
a user let's change the name
of this to promote user kick
user demote user and ban user
like that
and then leave free so i'm
going to go ahead and grab
promote user and i'm going to
change
my line edit to user to
manage and then i'll click on
promote user we're going to go
ahead
and connect that to our nakama
controller here we'll come down here
and we'll basically go ahead
and promote a user so first
things first we need to actually
get our user account now unfortunately
you need to actually go and
fetch that user account so first
we'll say var user is is
type
nakama api dot api
users is equal to await client
dot get users async and then
we can come in here and
go session
so we could pass in that
session and then we need to
pass in ids so when you
do this you can
pass in ids or usernames in
our case we're going to pass
in a username
but you can pass
in their actual id as well
so i'm just going to pass
in a blank and then for
the username i'll
just pass in a single parameter
and that's going to be dollar
sign user to manage dot text
comma
and you'll see that they also
have a facebook id in this
case we'll pass in null we
don't really
have a facebook id to manage
a user but they do separate
that out and i'm not really
sure why they
do that but that's a thing
so it's just something to keep
in mind now what we can
do is say for you
in users dot users and that's
a really bad way so we'll
say result and then we'll just
do result
dot users that's going to be
a little bit better than what
we're doing right now now once
we do
this we have the actual user
information so that's how you pull
back that user's information so you
can actually just do
you
dot id and that will be
their identification right that'll be their
actual information
so what we can do is
we can come in here and
promote that user so we'll come
in here and say
await client dot promote user and
group async you can pass in
our session token and then we
can pass
in our group id so in
our case that's going to be
our selected group dot id comma
and i believe it's
selected group dot id let me
double check really quick because sometimes
i forget things it is
and then we have to pass
in a user identifier so that's
going to be u dot id
like that
and now if we go ahead
and hit play you'll see in
a second that if i connect
to this
and then i list my groups
i select my group and then
i type in test 2 and
i click promote
well
we have an error so the
error is cannot convert argument 3
from string to a packed array
and
that's because this can be a
group of users it's not actually
just one group it's actually
multiple people so we can go
ahead and do that and then
try it again so it's because
we need
we can actually have multiples of
somebody so we'll go like that
we'll submit we'll list our
groups select group test 2 we'll
promote that person you'll see that
we've got a group of users
that that looks like that was
successful we'll head back to our
nakama console we'll refresh
and you will see that this
person is now an admin so
that's huge because it's going to
allow us to
be able to create admins and
now if we click it a
second time you'll see if we
refresh they are now
a super admin that means that
they can delete this uh group
if they want to now the
question might be
okay so i can promote users
how do i demote them right
well if we come in here
we go in right here
we go into demote user button
down let's connect that real quick
we come in here and basically
copy and paste this code so
we'll just copy this guy paste
it and instead of promote we
can just
pass in demote easy enough and
same thing for kick user right
we could just kind of
bring that in and let's do
ban user as well right so
we'll just bring that in as
well if we copy
this guy we can copy paste
and paste because they're all the
exact same functionality so we
can come in here and say
kick group users and then ban
group users
and now if i refresh this
you'll see if i submit list
groups
submit list groups
select my group test two i
go demote you'll see that that
worked if we come over here
we refresh
our users right here you'll see
that they are now an admin
and then i can go ahead
and ban a user
and you'll see non-existent function
ban groups that's probably my fault
group users async
and it looks like you actually
can't ban a user so we'll
remove that that's
my fault group users async and
it looks like you actually can't
ban a user so we'll remove
that that's
my fault i um was reading
the documentation earlier but it looks
like it got removed so
you're not actually able to ban
a user anymore from a group
so we'll come in here we'll
go ahead
and type submit list our groups
select our group we'll go to
test two we'll go ahead and
demote the
user so you'll see if we
refresh they are an admin if
we come in here we can
go ahead and kick them
and then if we refresh you
will see they have been removed
and then we can go ahead
and kick them and
then if we refresh you will
see they are an admin if
we come in here we can
go ahead and kick them and
removed from that group and that's
basically how you can actually manage
your users in here
and you can also delete a
group and leave a group so
if we want to leave a
group we can come in here
and go into our stuff here
we can click on leave group
button down on leave button down
we'll
connect that and to leave a
group it's actually relatively simple all
we need to do is type
await client dot leave group async
will pass in our session and
then we'll pass in our group
id
which is going to be our
selected group id now this will
allow us to leave our group
but the
problem is that if i leave
my group i will actually um
not have any more users in
that
group so what i'll do is
i'll log in as test two
i will come in here and
pass in my group name if
i remember correctly it's if we
list groups we can select the
group join group and then you
should
see that we will join that
group so you'll see as a
member we can refresh and there
we go we're in
that group and now we can
come in here and say leave
group and then if we refresh
we have
leave group and then if we
refresh we have we have a
refresh we
left that group right there and
now we can actually safely delete
our group right because
we now have shown that that
section works that's how you leave
a group it's actually really easy
you just do leave group asynchronously
so now what happens if you
want to delete a group well
we're going to need an additional
button for that so let's duplicate
our leave group we'll just pull
it down here i guess we're
kind of running out of space
here so i'll just put it
right here
i'll move open over we'll grab
leave group and we'll put delete
group now in order to delete
a
group we'll disconnect this connect in
order to delete a group it's
actually really simple as
well so when you delete a
group all you need to do
is type client await client dot
delete
group async and then you can
pass in the session
and the selected group
dot
And that's literally all you need
to do.
So now if I refresh my
screen here,
I log in as test the
super admin,
and then we'll log in as
test.
We'll come in here, we'll log
in as test two.
We'll submit.
We will go ahead and hit
list groups.
We'll select that group.
We're gonna join that group really
quick.
And remember, because this is an
open group,
that person should be able to
just join.
There we go.
So the person has joined.
And now you'll see if I
go in as test two, right
here,
and I go ahead and I
click delete group,
which this is leave group,
but it's delete group in our
code.
You'll see request has returned response
400.
Group not found, or you are
not allowed to delete.
And the reason why is because
that person
does not have the capability to
delete this group.
You can see it's still here.
However,
if I come in here as
test or as my super admin,
and I log in and I
click list groups,
I select my group,
and then I click delete group,
you'll see if we go back
to groups,
it has now been removed.
And that's basically everything
that you need to know about
groups.
Now, when it comes to chats,
which is actually a whole feature
inside of Nakama,
you can actually build chat rooms
right inside of Nakama.
And you can actually build chat
rooms right inside of Nakama.
So when it comes to chats,
how do we actually get that
to work?
Well, first things first,
we are majorly out of space.
So I am going to hide
the group section.
As you can see,
we have all sorts of different
areas here
where we can actually do our
Nakama work here.
So I'm actually just going to
come in here
and just start hiding a lot
of this
because we're running out of space
here.
So I'll hide this panel and
this panel,
and there we go.
So when it comes to,
so when it comes to,
we have three different types of
chats.
And we'll talk about all three
of them
and how to send messages and
stuff like that.
But we have three different chat
types.
We have dynamic rooms, group chats,
and direct chats.
Okay.
And we'll talk about the group
chats when we get there.
But one of the big ones
that a lot of people like
is the dynamic rooms.
The dynamic rooms is basically a
random chat room.
And it's a random room that
gets created for temporary,
for a temporary time span.
And it only stays open as
long as there are people
in that chat room.
So the nice thing about it
is,
let's say you have a match
or something like that,
you could put people in that
temporary room
and then have people communicate.
And then once the match is
over,
that room just gets dissolved over
time.
Whereas something like a group chat,
that stays for as long as
the group exists.
And then they also have direct
chats,
which is basically one-on-one
communications between people,
which persist once again, forever.
So in order to do dynamic
rooms,
let's first right click, add a
child node.
Let's add in a panel here
and let's make it about this
big.
Now we're going to have to
build a whole chat system.
So this will take a little
bit of time.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to right click,
add a child node.
I'm going to add in a,
button.
I'm going to right click, add
a child node,
add in a line edit right
here.
We're going to make the line
edit about yay big give or
take.
If my mouse will let me,
we'll do that.
We'll add in a button again,
providing that I can click on
this.
There we go.
We'll make it about yay big.
And for our line edit,
we'll just say chat name like
that.
And then we'll come in here
and say,
join chat.
Now you could automate this.
As soon as a person goes
into a match,
you could actually go set up
the room name
and automatically have them joined.
But in this case,
we're going to manually do it.
That way you guys get the
experience of how it works.
So what we'll do is we'll
change this to join chat room
like that.
And then the line edit will
be chat name like that.
And then I'm going to come
in here,
go over here, button down,
and then I will hit connect.
Now, when we want to join
a chat room,
all we have to do is
come up with a room name.
If it's persistent, if it's hidden,
and if it is a room
type.
So I will show you all
of those things.
So first things first,
let's go var channel is equal
to await socket dot join chat
asynchronously.
Now, what this is going to
do is we're going to have
a
target.
Now that target is what the
name of that chat room is
going
to be.
In this case, we'll just say,
actually, we already have a title
right here, right?
So dollar sign, chat, name, dot,
text, comma.
And then you'll see that we
have an int type.
So what does that actually take?
What is the type?
Well, the type is a Nakama
socket chat type
or a channel type.
So we'll say var type is
equal to,
Nakama socket dot channel type dot.
And you'll see that we have
different types,
direct message, group, and room.
And each one has a different
use.
So thankfully the code is basically
the same,
but what matters is if it
is going to be a room,
if it's going to be a
group,
or if it's going to be
a direct message.
In our case, it's going to
be a room.
So I'm going to come in
here and say type comma,
and then if it's persistent,
so in our case, we don't
want it to be persistent.
So false comma.
And then if it's hidden, it
will say false.
We want it to make it
a public messaging chat.
So people can actually go in
and message each other
and not have to authenticate or
be added to that chat.
And then what I'm going to
do is I'm going to print
that chat information.
So print channel like that.
So I'm going to print that
chat information.
Now this will basically print out
our chats information.
So if I refresh this and
I run this,
if I join and I say
test and I join,
you'll see that we now have
a chat that is right here.
You can see it has the
ID one.
It has ID here.
It says there's a user test,
user ID is this,
session ID is this.
So we can get all the
people that are inside of that
chat
right there.
Now, if somebody else joins test
two, submit,
and then they go test and
they join,
you can see here that we
also joined channel ID two,
user presence session, this status user
test.
So we just got back that
user's account information, right?
So we got test and test
two in this chat with each
other.
And that's basically what these guys
are saying here.
Now, in order to send a
message,
you need to actually be able
to receive that message, right?
So let's go to our script
here.
And let's scroll all the way
up to the top.
And the reason why I'm scrolling
all the way up to the
top
is because we need to subscribe
when we create our socket
to the ability to actually get
messages.
So what we need to do
is go find
where our socket gets created,
which is right here.
So we'll come in here and
we'll say socket dot,
and providing that Godot wants to
be nice to me,
it will auto complete.
Please, maybe not.
Well, we'll hit dot received underscore
channel underscore message dot connect like
that.
And then we'll pass in a
callable.
So what this is going to
be is it's just going to
be
a very basic function that prints
out that message currently,
at least.
So we'll say funk underscore on
underscore channel,
on channel message like that.
And we'll pass in a message.
Now this could be a type
if you want it to be,
which is going to be a
Nakama API dot API channel message
like that.
And then we can just go
ahead and print that message.
And there we go.
Now we're going to connect that
message.
So we'll just pass on channel
message like that.
And that will actually pass that
to this guy right here.
And we'll go ahead and send
out that signal.
Now, when we do our message,
when we want to send a
message,
we need to actually create a
panel for that.
So let's come in here.
Let's right click our panel and
add in another panel.
Like this.
So I'm going to drag this
guy over here,
make it about this big give
or take,
and we're going to create a
very basic message block system.
So it's going to be pretty
ugly,
my apologies,
but I want to try to
get this to work as quickly
as humanly possible.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to put in
a line edit like,
so I'm going to make this
go on the bottom stretched across.
I'm going to pull this back,
right click,
add a child node.
We'll add an up button.
I'm going to snap that guy
right in the bottom right where
we'll make it about,
if I can click on it
about yay big,
we'll put a send or maybe
just like an arrow like that.
I think that'll work.
We'll put a placeholder chat text
here.
We'll type this as chat text.
We'll make the panel title chat,
and then we'll make the button
submit chat like that.
I'm going to go ahead and
right click,
add a child node,
and I'm going to add in
a,
I am brain farting on what
it is.
It is a text edit like
that.
We'll make it full screen.
So full rect and we'll make
it about yay big.
That'll go ahead and make it
so that it's kind of scalable
and you know,
easy to use.
Now inside of here,
I'll scroll down and I will
do auto,
wrap, that's fine.
So that means that if I
put in a bunch of text
here,
it's going to auto wrap.
So you can see if I
do wrap,
mode boundary,
it will go ahead and wrap
that,
and then I will turn on
scroll as well.
So if this continues,
so we'll Control C,
Control V,
we'll paste it.
You'll see that it's going to
scroll.
We also want to.
We'll want to shut off editable,
and I think that will work
because I think this is placeholder
text.
So if I come in here,
here and we paste this text
in this will allow us to
scroll i'm curious if we can
make it follow the uh actual
scrolling but i don't think we
can i know there's a way
to do it
it's been a while since i've
done it but i think i'll
just go ahead and skip that
part but there
is a way to make it
so it automatically scrolls to the
bottom but that's okay right now
so this
is basically what our chat setup
is going to be it's going
to be relatively simple but
it's going to be something that
we can at least use now
i'm going to grab my submit
chat button
i'm going to go to node
button down i'm going to connect
that to my submit chat button
now
when we want to do a
message right we want to send
a message we can come in
here and say var
await socket dot
write chat message asynchronous now this
is going to require a id
so we have to actually
have some kind of chat name
in this case i'm just going
to go ahead and grab this
guy right here
copy it and paste it it's
not the most ideal situation because
once you're connected to that
channel you should probably just be
connected to that channel right instead
of passing in this
value here but we can basically
throw a value up at the
top and basically just save it
across different functions and that would
solve this problem but for right
now we'll go ahead and
do this and then we need
to pass in our message content
so what we can do is
do dollar sign
chat text dot text like that
now i think we should probably
change this to text edit instead
just do chat text box that
way we actually have that value
now if we hit play and
we go ahead and
okay if we come in here
we both submit join test test
number two submit join test if
we send a text
test send you'll see that it
is very mad at us cannot
convert argument to from string to
dictionary so it's going to require
a dictionary for us to be
able to do that so what
we need to do
is we need to pass in
an actual dictionary of objects so
we can come in here
Pass in this dictionary like so
and go quote message colon that.
And the reason why we have
to do this is because we
can actually do what's called emotes,
right?
And emotes are sent via JSON
data.
So that's the reason why it
requires it to be a dictionary
is so that we can actually
send over emote information.
Now, I'm not going to cover
that just because there's a whole
like loading emotes and stuff like
that that you need to do.
And that's way beyond the basics
of this tutorial.
So if you guys want to
look at that, you guys can
go check out their real time
chatting section and they'll go over
that.
But I'll go ahead and hit
submit test to submit, join, test,
join, test, test, send.
And you'll see that we actually
get an error.
So it says invalid chat identified.
So what's going on here, right?
Well, if you take a look
at your chat here, if we
take a look at our chat,
you'll see that our chat actually
has an identifier ID too.
You see that?
So when you have a chat,
it actually has an identifier associated
with that chat.
And so you don't want to
pass in the title of the
chat.
You want to pass in the
identifier.
You can see that we have
a channel right here.
So if I go channel.id,
we can go ahead and refresh
this guy and go submit, test,
submit.
And you'll see that we are
now printing out and you will
see that we have an ID
right here.
I added channel ID in post.
So that way it was nice
and quick, but you can see
right here, channel ID is two
dot, dot, dot test.
So two is the ID.
ID of the chat and test
is the actual ID that we
gave it.
So we need to pass that
value in right here for us
to be able to send messages.
So what we can do is
we can come in here, copy
this var channel, go all the
way up to the top.
And go var current channel like
that.
And then we go all the
way back down to the bottom
and do current channel.
Is equal to that.
And then we'll go ahead and
copy this.
We'll paste it right here.
Dot ID.
And then we can go ahead
and do current channel dot ID
right here as well.
Now, what that will do is
that it should allow us to
actually send it to the proper
ID.
So we'll hit submit, test to
submit, test, join, test, join, test,
send.
And you should see right here,
we no longer have an error,
but instead we have an.
An actual message right here.
I probably should not have used
the word test.
I should probably use, this is
a test message.
That way we can actually see
what it is.
And you can see here that
I send a message and you
see right here, channel ID test
code is zero content message.
This is a test message.
And that's basically how we can
send and receive messages.
Now, the nice thing is that
if, since we typed our message.
In the message section, and unfortunately
this is getting pretty large, so
I might want to abstract some
of this out, but if we
go to right here, where our
on-channel message is at, we
have our different messages that we
can message information here that we
can actually use.
So if we type message dot,
you'll see that it's going to
automatically give us some information here
that we can work with.
So you can see that we
have sender.
ID.
Username, all sorts of information.
So the nice thing is I
can come in here and I
can go dollar sign chat, text
box dot text plus equals message
dot user name plus colon space
plus message dot.
And then if we take a
look, there should be a.
Content dot message like that, like
that, and we should probably also
go ahead and pass in a
new line because we want the
user to have a new line
here now.
So let's try this VAR content
is equal to.
Message.
Message dot content.
And then I wonder if content
dot message will work instead.
Okay, there we go.
We'll try that and see if
that works.
Also, I'm going to want to
put a new line at the
end of this.
So we'll go ahead and do
that slash end for a new
line.
That way, every time somebody sends
a message, it's going to be
a new lined message.
And now if I refresh this
in theory, this should work.
So we'll go ahead and do
submit test.
Join.
Test to submit, test, join, test,
send, and it is very unhappy.
So let's take a look.
You can see the content here
is a string data.
So it looks like we're going
to need to JSON parse this
information.
So go JSON dot parse string,
and we'll go ahead and pass
that in.
And there we go.
And that should fix that problem.
Basically content is a JSON value.
So that's something that I didn't
think.
About I'm talking without thinking as
I'm doing this tutorial.
So forgive me, but we need
to actually parse that data.
So now if we hit send,
you'll see test, test, test.
This is a test message like,
so test two, this is a
test message.
And that's basically how you could
do a very basic communication system.
So now the question is, okay,
great.
That's fine.
But how do I actually do
group chats?
And in order to do group
chats, what we need to do
is we need to come in
here.
And we need to go ahead
and grab another joint chat here.
And what I'm going to do
is I'm going to unhide my
group section and I
guess I'll just move it over.
So we have a little bit
more space.
Let's grab this guy.
We'll drag them over like this.
It's getting a little on the
cramped side with our setup here.
So I might.
I might need to readjust some
stuff, but I don't think I
can fit it really up here.
So we'll just kind of push
it over here and that should
just work.
I mean, it's a little tight,
but it will work for the
demonstration we're trying to do here.
So if I grab this guy
here, I right click disconnect inspector,
change this to join a group
chat.
Like, so when you want to
do a group chat, all you
gotta do is come in and
basically.
I move this guy over.
There we go.
All you really need to do
is you need to come in
here, connect your button down.
So go ahead and connect that
over here.
And then we can come in
here and basically just grab this
exact code right here.
It's almost a duplication, right?
It's almost exactly the same.
We'll just drop that guy in
there.
And all we really need to
do is come in here and
when we do our join,
socket asynchronously, we just basically need
to pass in our group ID.
So we'll say, and I believe
we have a group, if I
remember correctly.
So selected group dot ID, and
then we can pass in type
for persistence.
We're going to want to say
true because we want to keep
that group around.
Right.
And then we want it to
be persistent.
And we also want to change
this to a type group chat.
And then what we can do
is we can come in here,
hit play.
Come over here, submit test.
We will go ahead and create
a group.
So that way now our group
actually exists.
So if we refresh our groups
off to re log in, because
this is another recording
session and you can see, we
now have a test group and
we are now a part of
it.
Now from here, we can join
that group with test two.
So we'll come in here and
I already did this once.
We'll do test to test, join
group.
And it.
I got mad at me because
our selected group is not correct
and that's my fault.
So that's totally fine.
So I will have to refresh
real quick.
So we'll say submit test.
We will go ahead and list
our groups.
We'll select our test group.
We'll do test to list our
groups, select it, join that group.
And then when we join our
chat, we could just join group
chat, growing group chat,
and then test, and you will
see that this guy now gets
it.
And if we go, this is
a test message and we send
that guy.
You can see that that message
gets sent.
Now you might be going, okay,
so why does this matter, right?
What is the benefit of a
group chat versus a dynamic chat?
Well, where a group chat matters
and why it's important is because
you can do
what's called listing the message history.
So because it's a persistent chat,
we're going to be.
So the reason why that's cool
is because we can come in
here and we can say, okay,
when the user joins a group,
which we'll have to scroll down
here to right here,
and we'll need to go ahead
and come in here and list
out that information.
So we'll say far result is
equal to a weight client dot
list channel.
And we're going to say, okay,
we're going to go ahead and
list that information.
And again, the first thing we'll
do is we're going to have
a fried
time, which if you check out
there, when we get there, it
looks fine.
It's super fresh and we've got
so much we don't do in
onsite,
and what I'm going to do
is I'll click on
product
period.
and that's what forward is is
forward is the newest so we'll
say forward so we'll say true
comma and then i believe they
have a cursor value as well
and cursor is if i remember
correctly it's
defaulted let's double check really quick
if we hit comma cursor variance
is null so cursor allows
you to say i want you
to start at this point so
if you're picking up the next
100 values let's say
you have 500 messages you can
pass in number 200 and then
it'll grab from 200 to 300
if that makes
sense so in our case i'll
just leave that as null because
it's just going to be easier
for us to
work with it now we can
go for message in result dot
message like that messages like that
and then
we can basically just go exactly
what we did before
so
we can come up here and
grab if you remember how we
actually parsed out our data which
arguably i
should move this down closer to
my actual message functionality so let's
go ahead and just do that
really quick we'll come down here
and just drop it right let's
see this is group stuff this
is chat
stuff so we'll go ahead and
just drop it right there and
that'll just kind of keep it
within
the group area so that way
i can basically
come in here and do this
and say chat room code right
here and that'll give me somewhere
to actually
look at this now what we
could do is we could basically
just grab this copy it and
paste and
that's all we need to do
and then in theory this should
just work so now if we
hit play
in theory if we're lucky it
will work so we'll go here
we'll say list groups select group
join group
chat and we got an error
message return response invalid channel id
so we have a failure here
that
says that our channel id is
incorrect so let's see join chat
asynchronously list channel messages
that should be correct is it
printing out what i expect let's
see so i don't think that
this
worked 100 here so let's try
submitting list groups select group that
should select our group
and then i should be able
to join group chat but it
did not take it so the
question is is
it because i failed to join
the group chat or did it
fail here so if we do
this the id of the group
id is string get return
return string if not string else
string await list channel messages try
refresh and it's going
to run through that real quick
but it didn't do anything as
expected so i drop a break
point here
what is result result is an
object id cacheable null null so
we got a nakama exception invalid
channel id
did our channel get saved let's
go ahead and take a look
at nakama really quick chat messages
group chat no messages found so
our group chat just doesn't exist
so that's not great so that
means something went wrong with how
we initialized our group chat i
think okay so i figured out
the
issue so basically when we do
our list channel messages async we
need to actually do our current
channel dot id instead so when
we do our join chat asynchronous
we pull back a channel and
that's the channel that we're currently
in and basically we need to
go and list those message
right here and then i have
a section here for messages in
result messages if the message
content does not contain an empty
so if for some reason a
message gets in there that's empty
when
we try to parse it it's
going to break so i have
this little if statement right here
that basically
just checks to see if it's
empty if it is ignore it
and there's no reason to have
it so now if i hit
play you'll notice that when i
come in here and i hit
submit i list my groups i
select my groups
and i join my group chat
you'll see i pull back those
messages and that's one of the
big cool
features of nakama is that it
keeps track of all of that
information because this is after we
removed and rebooted the system right
it actually
came back with the proper messages
that's basically what persistence does right
here
this true right here causes it
to be saved and to be
reusable later that's one of the
big cool
advantages here so now the question
is okay so how do i
do peer-to-peer messaging well
it's not
technically peer-to-peer but how
do i send messages directly to
a user well again
it's relatively simple if we come
into our stuff here we ctrl
c ctrl v join group chat
and then instead of join group
chat we have a join direct
chat i go ahead and grab
our where
is it join group chat right
here and i change this to
join direct chat like that we
can come in here
disconnect right click connect and connect
now in order to do a
direct chat it's actually
relatively easy it's exactly the same
as everything else you come in
here you go join chat room
right
here copy it come down here
paste well really actually we probably
should just grab this to
be honest it's going to save
us a bit of trouble so
if we paste this guy in
here change the channel
type to direct message like that
instead of having a selected group
id we need to
grab the user id in terms
of persistence we want to keep
true we also want to keep
false for hidden
but for this join chat asynchronous
we can go ahead and pass
in a user id so we
need to get
our actual user identifier and the
easiest way to do that is
by using the get users asynchronous
call if you remember we did
that earlier so we'll just say
var users is equal to await
dot get users asynchronous and then
we'll pass in our session and
we need to pass in a
id pack
string array and then the user
name that we're going to be
passing in so in our case
i think if
we take a look at our
user interface we have a chat
name we could probably just take
that i think
that will work so for the
chat name what i'll do is
i'll just pull this guy which
is chat name so
we'll come into our script and
we're going to have a chat
name and we're going to have
a chat name
we'll hit dollar sign chat name
dot text and then that should
bring back our users so now
we know
that it's going to bring back
one user and that's it so
since it's going to bring back
one user we
can basically just do if users
dot size is greater than zero
then we can do the rest
of this bit of
code here
and then we're going to have
a chat name and we're going
to have a chat name and
we're going to
and then we can just pass
in and say users bracket bracket
zero dot id and that'll pass
back a user id
that we can actually communicate with
so now in theory this should
work and of course as always
with theory it doesn't always work
but we'll see so we'll submit
as test we'll submit as test
two
and then we'll go test two
join direct chat it's mad and
that's because users came back
and that's because users came back
so we'll say users dot users
and i should probably just do
this as result then
or perhaps user result because we
don't want to mess with our
current code down here that has
results already we'll just do that
and then for this we'll just
say user result dot
users or perhaps user result dot
users and then we'll just do
that
users bracket bracket zero because we
now know that we need to
go a little bit deeper than
what
we expected so now if we
go ahead and submit test to
join direct chat now we're in
a direct chat
if we go into test two
and we go to test join
direct chat we pass test in
okay so i think i figured
out what's going on here so
i commented this out
just so we could check it
out but what i think is
going on here is remember in
our previous tutorial
we had test block test two
and because they're blocked they can't
send them messages
so it completely stops them from
being able to communicate with each
other
and that's why we're in a
direct chat so we're going to
go ahead and submit test to
join direct chat
why this is happening so if
i remove this let's see what
happens if i do that so
we'll go ahead
and come in here we'll ctrl
s we'll hit play and then
we'll try it one more time
so we'll do
submit test to submit test join
direct chat test to join direct
chat test we will send a
message
and that will now work now
the reason why this didn't work
was because
because test had test2 blocked.
So since they're blocked, they can't
communicate at all.
So that's the reason why this
happened.
So it was my fault, but
that was basically the reasoning.
Now, if we go ahead and
stop this,
and then we come in here
and uncomment this with control K,
and then we run this bad
boy,
in theory, we should be able
to see our previous communications.
So test2, join direct chat,
and you will see there's all
of our messages.
Now I'm getting a little bit
additional messages,
mostly because of my testing,
not because of a problem with
Nakama.
That's just something that I did
on my own by accident.
But you can see here are
all of the messages that we
have.
So that's basically how you do
messages back and forth.
Inside of Nakama.
Hey guys, editor Mitch here.
So something that you should do
once you do your chat system
and you get that guy settled,
when you have this chat right
here,
what you should also do is
subscribe to everybody's channels.
So if you have friends or
some kind of channel system,
you need to subscribe to that
channel.
So what I'm going to do
is come up to my online
login, login button down.
So when I press my login,
I'm going to go ahead and
come in here
and I'm going to have sub
to
friend channels like that.
Now I'm going to scroll down
and I have a chat section
in here.
So you can see we have
our little group section right here.
We scroll down.
We have a chat room code
right here.
So this is our chat section.
So right here, just somewhere in
this general section here,
we're going to go ahead and
add in the ability
to sub to the friend channels,
right?
So we'll say funk sub to
friends channels like that.
And then what I'm going to
do is say var results
is equal to await client dot
list friends asynchronously.
I'm going to pass in my
session
and that'll just bring in all
of my friends.
And then from here,
I can go ahead and subscribe
to their channels.
So for I in result dot
friends.
Like that.
And then I'm going to go
ahead and say var type is
equal to Nakama
socket dot channel type dot direct
message.
And then I can go ahead
and pull back my chat that
I have.
So I can sub to that
channel.
So I can say await socket.
Oh, I have sub to friends
sub to friend.
So we'll do friend channels
and that'll fix that little function
not found.
So socket dot join chat async.
And then I'll go ahead and
pass an I dot user
dot ID comma type
comma true comma false.
And that'll basically allow me to
pull those sockets back.
Now this should return if I
remember correctly a channel.
So if we actually hit control
F you can see we have
a couple of me see we
have current channel right here.
So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to come in
here and say
chat channels is equal to a
weight socket.
Okay, and actually
now that I think about this,
let's do this.
So we'll do
channel.
Let's do this channel is equal
to this and then we can
come down here and just say
chat channels.
Bracket Bracket I dot user.
ID.
Actually, I wonder if I should
do dot user name instead that
way.
It's just a more common value
and I could go is equal
to channel.
Like that and that'll basically hook
our channel here to this object.
So I'll say var and then
there we go and chat channels
doesn't exist yet.
But now we have a key.
Value pair here that we can
use and that's going to be
really big for us if we
want to use those channels later.
So now I can go ahead
and grab chat channels.
I can go up to the
top var chat channels like that
and I can actually come in
here and now I have access
to all of my chats right
here.
So if I have like a
hundred chats, I could actually pull
back the channel information and switch
between them really easily using this
object.
And I'll probably go through that
later, but it's a way to
extend our chat to be a
bit more useful.
If that makes sense.
So if you think about it
like this, basically what we could
do is we could add in
a tab.
Container right here, make that guy
full screen and then underneath that
tab container.
You can actually switch between different.
Tabs right and I think what
we could do.
And again, this is going to
be a lot of coding and
then we could actually come in
here.
Make this about I don't know
about this big give or take
then we can put that chat
text underneath here, right?
And this would allow us to
in theory do this and then
change the title of this to
username like so you can see
here.
Here's the user.
Name.
So what we could do at
least in theory is on startup.
Once we subscribe to all of
those channels, it would just fill
this out.
So for instance, if we come
in here and we go and
subscribe to those friend channels.
So if we grab this guy,
bring it down here, come in
here and then basically just say
tab container, or I guess it's
going to be dollar sign tab
container.
Dot.
Add child and then we can
add a child of this text
box here.
So basically if we add a
child of this text box and
I'm just kind of thinking this
through as I talk to you
guys.
So my apologies for how confusing
this is probably going to end
up being.
But we could do a.
Text box.
So this is going to be
a text edit.
So VAR.
Current edit is equal to text
edit dot new like that.
And then we could pass in
our current edit like that to
make that a object.
And then we could do current
edit.
Dot name is equal to our
username right here.
So I dot user dot user.
Name like so.
And then when we log in,
you'll see that I'm going to
have a tab right here called
username.
But if I click on login
and it's mad at me, so
you can see invalid index test
too.
So let's take a look at
this.
So create chat.
No.
So this is a null object.
It needs to be a type
dictionary.
That's my guess at least.
So we'll come in here.
We'll say colon equals bracket bracket
like that.
And that'll make it into an
object.
And now if we try it,
it should in theory work.
There we go.
And you can see we have
test to and username right here.
And that means that we would
be able to go and fetch
any messages that we want from
that person.
So if we were to go
in here sub to friend chat,
go down here.
We could actually go and fetch
that person's information.
If you remember, we actually do
that right here.
We pull back the messages right
here.
So what we could do is
if we list channel messages asynchronously,
we should probably pull this out
and just do a list messages
like that.
Do this.
It's going to want to have
a current channel dot ID.
So current channel like that, and
then we could come in here
and just do current edit dot
text is equal to.
List messages.
And then we have to pass
in our current channel.
So that would be our, let's
see channel right here.
So channel.
So we'll pass it that channel.
That'll pass back all of the
text in that channel.
This is a co-routine.
So it must be called with
a weight.
That makes sense.
So a weight.
And then instead of doing this,
we'll just return that value.
So we'll just say bar text.
Oh, I guess I'm going to
have to create a text.
So var text is equal to
quote, and then we'll need to
just do text plus equals blah.
And then we can just return
our text like that.
And then that will return text
right here.
And then instead of doing this,
when we join a chat group,
we can just go dollar sign.
Or we could just go in
here.
And add in a panel, like
what we're doing right here.
You can see how we're joining
chat asynchronously.
So we really could just grab
this.
Section here.
And just paste it right here.
On this guy, like, so, and
that'll basically solve that problem right
there.
Now, technically this is duplicated code
and that's probably not the most
ideal situation, but that's probably okay
for right now.
And instead of.
Doing our.
Chat channel, I username.
What we would do is we
would do something like current channel
and then selected group.
So.
Selected group to ID.
The current name would also be
the selected group ID.
I guess we'd probably want to
come up with a better way.
Maybe we could just call it
current group, right?
Instead of the name.
Like, so, and then we could
probably come in.
Here and list our current channel
as well.
And in theory, that would work.
So now if we hit play
in theory, we would have a
tabular messaging system.
Now we can hit submit and
there's all of our messages right
there.
And we have different tabs that
we can work with.
I think if I do test,
it's probably going to get mad
at me in ballot index ID.
That makes sense because current channel.
Dot ID.
Current channel is no, my guess
is because I'm not in a
channel yet, so that would make
sense.
So what we would need to
do is we need to make
our tab container handle that when
the tab gets switched, which I
think there is a on tab
changed right here.
So we would have to keep
track of which index our stuff
is actually located in.
So I think that that's okay.
So we could actually just do
this on tab change.
Like, so, and then we could
just keep track of what index
we're on when the user changes
their tab, it kind of keeps
track of that.
So how I would do that
is if I go into where
the tabs are located, so you
could see here, and I know
this is probably a little bit
confusing and my apologies.
I'm just kind of working through
it with you guys.
But so you can see right
here.
We have a channel selected group
ID.
Current channel.
So what we could do is
when we do our tab container,
we could actually connect our tab
changed event and then bind the
user ID to it.
So we could do is we
could do dollar sign panel tab
container dot add child like so.
But we could do dot tab
changed dot.
Container.
Connect.
And then we can put on
tab changed, and I guess I
should do on chat.
Tab changed dot bind.
And I can pass in the
selected group ID like so.
And then we could come in
here and just say funk on
chat tab changed like so.
And then we could pass an
int.
tab, comma, or I guess it'd
be, I'm sorry, I'm trying to
code in C sharp, tab, colon,
int, comma, and then we could
pass in group ID or channel
ID like that. And that would
pass in
that value like that. And there
we go. So what that's going
to do is allow us to
print,
print, quote, tab, comma, channel ID
like that. And that will give
us the ability to work with
this. Now, we join a chat
group, that's how we have to
handle that. But when we do
our sub to
friends channel, we got to do
that as well. So that way
we can do it on both.
So now if I hit
play, in theory, if I do
submit, it's mad at me unable
to get index ID on base
nil, that's because
selected group is not available. So
that's why we have to do
that. So that's why we have
to do
is null. And that's because I'm
dumb, and I chose the wrong
bind, it's going to be I
dot user dot
username. So grab that, and paste
it right here. Let's try that
one more time. So I'm going
to come
in here, I'm going to go
submit. And it once again, is
going to be mad on non
existent function bind
on base int. That's mad about,
let me see. I think I
might have figured it out. What
if I do this
instead?
And then I have to go
and find my other bind, which
should be, I think I need
to put it out
inside the the signal connection. So
I'm connecting, I'm binding this to
the signal,
not to the connection function. I
think that's what's doing it. So
let's try that. Let's grab
the other one. So you can
see how this one connect dot
bind. Instead, I think I need
to bind and then
do that. And then I should,
be able to make that work.
And I believe it is index
and then channel ID. So let's
try that. Let's
see what that does. There we
go. And then if I click
test two, it should have displayed
test two
right there. So that's perfect. So
what that means is that we
can go current channel is equal
to
chat channels, bracket bracket channel ID.
Like that.
And then what that means is
now we should be able to,
since we're binding those parameters,
I should be able to send
a message and it should just
take it in theory, invalid, get
text on null.
That's fine. My guess is that's
because chat text box doesn't exist
anymore because now we're going
the opposite direction, right? So we're
sending a message. If you see
here, if you look at the
content messages, test type is zero.
And if you take a look
at this,
object, it has the channel ID,
sender ID, user ID, one, two,
and then user name. Now, if
we take
a look at our channel objects
right here, so chat channels, you
can see test two is our
parameter
here. That's going to be our
players information, if that makes sense.
So I think we could probably
get away with.
Since this is going to give
us test as its content and
the message is going to say
sender ID is right
here. The channel ID is right
here. I wonder if we should
pull because it has a username
right here,
but that's not going to hook
us up to our channel code.
So I'm curious if we need
to change how we
send our data across. So we
send our data, we're sending the
message and then the current channel
ID. Okay. So I think I
know what I'm going to do
here. So we're actually going to
change up a little
bit, how we're doing this. And
the reason why I'll show you,
if we take a look at
right here, we're
passing in our current channel. What
I'm going to do is I'm
going to come in here and
pass in, instead
of just a current channel, I'm
going to pass in channel like
that.
Colon current.
Channel. And then I'm also going
to pass in a label value
just so I can have the
label if I need it for
whatever reason. And the label in
the selected group ID will probably
just be group chat because it
really
doesn't need to have anything special.
And if we go to the
other one, so channel chats, we
go to the other
one, which is right here.
So this one.
Needs to go dot channel because
we're making that adjustment real quick.
You can see right here, we're
doing channel.
So you can see we'll need
to make that adjustment and then
we'll just copy this guy right
here.
We'll paste it like, so, and
then I'm going to go ahead
and pass in control X channel
like that.
And that will allow us to
have an object that has a
label here.
And then for the actual label
itself,
I'll just pass this guy in
like that.
And then I'll just do channel
dot ID like that.
And then if we have this,
then we should be able to
use this to pull back that
channel information instead.
And I know what you're thinking.
That doesn't sound like it's going
to work, but it's probably not
going to work.
So let's go ahead and say
on tab changed.
Spine selected group ID.
If I do on tab changed
bind channel ID like that.
And then when we produce our
message here, we're going to be
fetching back this on channel message,
parse the content.
And right here, we will have
a chat box.
So you can see we have
chat.
Chat.
Chat box.
It'll be tab container dot get
node like that content dot.
And if we take a look
at what our message is going
to be right here, see how
we have our right message asynchronous,
we'll just say content dot ID
like so.
And then here we can pass
in quote ID colon and fetch
back our channel information.
So chat channel.
Like, so.
Channel ID.
So it'd be current channel.
Dot ID right here.
Like that.
And that will pass back our
channel information.
And then from here, we could
just go dot.
Label.
And that should allow us to
fetch back the correct node and
set the proper information right there.
And in theory, that would work.
work. Let's try that and see
how that works. So if we
hit submit test to test send,
you'll see that
we now get our test information.
So this is a test message
like that. And we click go,
you'll see
this is a test message just
like that. And that's basically how
we can make a tabbed system
as well
that should actually work for our
chat system. So now that we
have a basic chatting system that
fully works, let's talk about how
we can host this out on
the cloud. Because the best way
to get your
networking working is by hosting it
out on the cloud. That means
that you have to pay a
server
to host that information. So if
you want a multiplayer game, you
need to actually pay to
host that data somewhere.
Right. And that is where DigitalOcean
comes in. DigitalOcean is a pretty
great tools kit that will
allow you to host your projects
right here on their servers. And
it's relatively cheap. If you
take a look at the pricing,
you can see they have some
pretty cheap droplets. So if you
wanted a
cheap like $5 server to host
your game, that's more or less
what this is for is it
allows you to
actually host.
Stuff out in the cloud for
relatively cheap. And I will drop
a link in the description below
that if
you guys use it, it will
give me credits to be able
to host my own stuff. Now
I will be hosting stuff
for this tutorial here. I'll be
giving you guys an IP address
and you guys can use it
for your testing.
But just know that if you
want to go out into production,
you need to use your own
server and something
to keep in mind.
You can host your own server
as well locally, but it's a
lot harder. It's not as safe
and people can hack into your
networks and things like that. So
it's really nice just to use
something like this to host it
for you so that you can
get your game out there and
get people playing it and playing
together. So let's go ahead and
create an account or
log in whichever one you guys
have. So I'm going to go
ahead and log in real quick.
So this is DigitalOcean and
basically the nice thing here is
that you can host your own
server. So if you want to
host your own server, you can
do this in your browser clipboard
but in this case that I'm
just running it from my laptop
here.
So this is the DigitalOcean dashboard.
If you're a big developer, this
has to be cool for you.
It has to be let that
person explain everything to you, and
it's got certain parameters to be
with at a time so that
you
can't just move the view member
for whatever it is that you're
using so if you get a
whole new location it may not
be
going to be a comfortable time
so you can make some adjustments,
but it's going to allow you
to hang out, surf there for
As well as just showing people
that you're camping, or store a
lot on the plane, or whatever
you're the case,
or whatever you're using on your
vlogging mission or other, but only
as far it's going to help
you to host your own server
or
actually create your own server or
having a live server.
right here so if you're using
nakama you can actually store your
database outside of your
droplet and allow for load balancing
they actually have a full built
-in load balancing system right
here spinning up a load balance
so you can actually choose different
data regions and pass
data in between different regions and
things like that by using their
load balancers now that being
said that's way beyond the scope
of this tutorial but that's what
i'm trying to say is digital
ocean
has a bunch of stuff for
you to use that can help
you get up to the point
where you can use nakama
premium and actually have them handle
a lot of that for you
but this is a good way
to kind of
get started into that if that
makes sense so let's go ahead
and talk about how to create
a droplet so
let's go up here to the
upper right hand corner click on
create click on droplet you could
do an
app platform that's technical
going to be cheaper but it's
a lot harder to get everything
set up properly so i'm just
going to do
a droplet for right now and
so we can pick what region
we want our droplet in so
right here i'm
going to choose new york new
york is the closest to me
so we'll choose that we'll come
down here
and you could choose an image
now if you have a specific
image that you're looking for go
ahead
and pick it right here in
my case i'm going to go
with ubuntu but if you want
to you can also look
at the marketplace and you can
pick different stuff so
docker on ubuntu probably would be
a good image to get or
maybe something like lamp if you're
trying to do a lamp server
or wordpress or something like that
they have so many different
droplets that you can actually use
have at your disposal you can
see here you can also do
custom images so if you have
an image
you can actually just spin it
up and have it work now
in my case i'm going to
go with os ubuntu
we're going to start from base
even though
technically docker on ubuntu probably is
a better option so i'm going
to go
so so i'm going to go
with marketplace docker on ubuntu that's
going to save us a lot
of trouble
and get it all set up
for us right so all we
have to do is get our
docker compose and then set up
our
firewall rules and we'll be good
to go so we'll go ahead
and add that guy now if
you come in here you
can see that you have a
bunch of different options for size
now it depends on what you're
trying to do
and typically what i tell people
is you want to pick the
lowest value that you can
and plus one so for instance
if you think that your game
is going to be really small
and not a
lot of people are going to
play it then something like the
14 a month one is probably
pretty good
if you're looking for something really
cheap just for testing if you
go to regular and you
kick it over you can see
that you can just do something
like the six dollar one and
that's it
if you're looking for something really
cheap you can just do something
like the six dollar a month
one
or even the four dollar a
month one if you can get
away with under 10 gigabytes if
you were to come
up here and choose os ubuntu
then you could go down to
four dollars a month at 512
megabytes now
once you get down that low
this is basically only used for
testing you want to at minimum
have six
dollars a month of one gigabyte
one cpu just because it's going
to allow you to have a
lot
more flexibility for your project now
since i'm doing a marketplace image
of
and now since this is going
to be a tutorial i should
probably just do ubuntu with the
four
because odds are you're not going
to have the funding to do
this or something like that so
we'll try the four we might
have to upgrade to six we'll
see and then you can see
here that you
can add a volume which will
allow you to expand your disk
space now in our case we
don't need that because it's fine
for right now and you can
see that we have authentication so
we
have ssh key and password now
in my case we're just going
to do so i'm going to
set my password
right here and we'll scroll down
here and you can see that
we can do improve metrics and
monitoring
for free so may as well
turn that on and i don't
think we need to do a
database cluster here but
we can look at that in
the future so you can see
here is our host name right
here which i'll call
it youtube2 tags i'm not worried
about it and then you'll see
that it has a project right
here now
this project is where it's going
to get build under so don't
worry it'll just get built under
your
account and then we'll click create
droplet now this is going to
allow us to have a droplet
once
it gets built which should be
relatively quick there we go you
can see it's in the middle
of
building it and it is now
completed so it actually created your
little droplet right here so now
at
this point what we're going to
do is we're going to go
ahead and create a new one
and we're going to
see how our project is going
to look like once we click
into it you can see here
is our youtube2
doplet you can see we have
our graphs for our bandwidth cpu
usage stuff like that we have
access
which allows us to adjust our
access to it we have power
which allows you to turn it
off and on we
have volumes which allow you to
have block storage resize which allows
you to change how big and
strong that droplet is so you're
welcome to go in and actually
upgrade this later so if you
need that one gig of memory
or that one 10 gigabyte ssd
right that's all stuff that right
here is available and then you
can come in here and go
into networking you can change your
network
ip address your firewall stuff you
can come in here and back
it up you can get snapshots
of it
so that way if you need
this droplet to be perfect and
snapshotted for backup purposes
this is what this is for
it allows you to basically go
back to that point in time
and
apply it to your image so
the nice thing is is if
you create snapshots and your stuff
gets hacked
or something like that you can
roll back to that snapshot and
stop that hack from happening kernel
is something that you're not going
to be using but basically it
allows you to upgrade your linux
kernel history
history is the history of it
destroy allows you to destroy that
droplet tags allows you to tag
it
and recovery allows you to try
to recover your droplet now that
we've gone through all of this
let's go up to our console
here and click on that you'll
see that that's going to pop
up a droplet
console now this is pretty cool
because you actually have a full
linux machine here so if
you don't know linux now is
the time to learn because linux
is very important to know so
first
thing first thing first thing first
thing first thing first
things first inside of ubuntu to
install docker what you need to
do is you need to type
sudo apt-get update and that's
going to update all of your
mirrors out there and then we
need to go
in and actually add the repository
because docker doesn't actually exist in
the repo by default
so we'll say sudo apt-get
install ca-
certificates curl like that and that's
going to go ahead and make
sure that we have curl installed
and then we'll sudo install dash
m 0755 dash d slash etc
slash apt slash key rings
and then we're going to go
in and curl out to the
docker linux ubuntu i will actually
leave
these in the browser and then
we're going to go in and
curl out to the docker linux
ubuntu i will
leave these commands in the comments
below by the way so you
guys can use it but sudo
curl
dash f s s dash l
f s capital s l https
colon slash slash download dot docker
dot com slash
linux slash ubuntu slash gpg dash
o space slash etc
slash apt slash key rings
slash docker dot asc and what
that's going to do is it's
going to actually create a docker
gpg apt repo for you so
that way you can actually go
and install docker and then we
need to allow
access to it so sudo ch
mod a plus r slash etc
slash apt slash key rings docker
asc and that basically allows us
to
execute and use that data that's
right there so basically linux is
a permission
system that is very very aggressive
so you need to make sure
that you keep that stuff under
wraps
if that makes sense so uh
linux by default does not give
you permissions to anything and you
have
to give yourself permissions to it
so that's kind of what we're
doing right here so then
we can come in here and
finally fire off our apt resources
now this command is going to
be
really difficult to do so we'll
do echo slash enter and that's
going to allow us to kind
of
get a actual script going here
so we'll say quote deb space
bracket arch equals dollar sign
dpkg dash dash print dash architecture
side by
equals slash etc slash apt slash
key rings
slash docker dot asc bracket https
colon slash slash download dot docker
dot com slash linux slash ubuntu
and then we're going to put
that in dollar sign dot slash
etc slash os dash release
and we're going to echo our
version code name
and we're going to pull back
the stable version like that we're
going to pass in a pipe
and we're
going to pipe that into sudo
t slash etc slash apt slash
source dot list dot d
slash docker dot list greater than
sign slash dev
slash null
use full than nut verify
and that was it for this
episode of docker reasons
so guys if you guys were
curious about some of the array
you can just go to each
writing
from han
So let me double check this
command
and make sure that I'm happy
with it.
So we have arch $dpackage, our
print architecture.
We're going to sign it by
our Docker ASC file
and we're going to go out
to our Docker Linux Ubuntu
and we're going to pull back
the OS release
and I misspelled echo right here.
You can see I made a
mistake.
As always, you make a million
mistakes when you do this.
So echo.
So that's E-C-H-O.
And then we have our version
code name
that we are echoing into our
release.
We're pulling back the stable edition.
We're going to pipe that into
sudo t right here
into our Docker lists and we're
greater than slash dev null.
And we'll run that.
Command E-C-O is not
found.
That's because I just typed it
in.
I spelled echo wrong.
So I guess it's good thing
that it failed immediately.
So E-C-H-O and
we will try running it.
Hopefully this doesn't blow up.
All right.
So we have no such file
or directory.
So, all right.
So I think I figured it
out.
Basically there was an issue with
the command for,
I think it was this area
here.
So don't worry, just copy what
I have.
In my description and just use
that.
And it will just work for
you.
So now all I got to
do is type sudo apt-get
update like that.
And that's going to update all
of our packages in our repo.
And it's going to go and
fetch out to the Docker system
and pull back the actual Docker
packages.
So you can see right here,
it's actually pulling down that information
right there.
And then we're going to go
ahead and install Docker.
So sudo apt-get update.
You have sudo apt-get install
docker-ce docker-ce-cli
container.io docker-build-plugin and
finally,
the most important one of the
group,
docker-compose-plugin, and that's the
big one.
That's the one that's actually going
to matter for our,
project for the most part i
mean the rest of these are
obviously important docker ce is the
docker
runtime docker ce cli is this
command line interface the uh containered
is the actual
container uh system docker build plugins
is to build your own docker
containers and then docker
compose allows you to actually compose
dockers based off of a docker
composition file if you
remember before when we talked about
how to build nakama that was
one of the big things that
you
needed to use so we'll hit
enter it's going to go ahead
and try to pull it it
says that it cannot
locate the docker build plugin my
guess is i spelled something wrong
here so let's see docker
build x plugin there we go
hit go and it should go
ahead and download and install docker
now we might need to upgrade
to the next step up to
the one gigabyte edition but we're
going to
see if we can get away
with the four dollar a month
version
first and if we can't then
we'll upgrade to the six dollar
a month version and then we
can run our
docker setup here so we'll see
how this works but we'll go
from there so it looks like
it is
running if we type ps you
will see that we have a
bash and ps running
so if we type docker is
it going to pop up and
there we go so we do
have docker running so we're
going to docker build and then
we're going to docker build and
then we're going to docker build
so now from here we need
to get a docker compose file
on to here so if we
type ls right here
you can see that we have
nothing going on so what we
can do is we can type
mkdir nakama cd nakama
like that and that's going to
get us into that directory so
mkdir makes the directory cd nakama
just brings us into the nakama
directory so we're going to type
mkdir nakama and then we're going
to
now we can come in here
and basically compose our docker file
so if we're lucky we'll be
able
to just copy and paste our
composition file so if we go
out here we go to documents
and we find
our nakama instance i believe i
have a nakama server tutorial docker
compose dot yaml so if
we open this guy up you'll
see this is what our docker
compose file looks like
you can see right here this
is what it looks like so
if we hit ctrl a ctrl
c and then we go
into our web browser here and
we type nano docker dash compose
dot yml and then we right
click paste
it should paste all that data
right into here so that way
we don't actually have to set
up file
zilla because one of the things
that's unfortunate is a lot of
times if you're doing
godot networking you need to actually
put files up into file zilla
and into the ftp and bring
them
over to digital oceans to your
digital ocean droplet so thankfully we
can just copy and paste
this in ctrl x y and
it'll be docker compose dot yaml
and now from here we should
be able to just
get it to run if we're
lucky so what we'll do come
in here and we're going to
go to our docker compose
and type docker compose up and
you'll see it's going to go
ahead and attempt to pull
and build our docker instance right
here now we might run out
of ram it just kind of
depends
but hopefully with 512 megs of
ram it's going to be really
tight i don't know if this
is going to
work we're probably going to need
a gig but we can see
so we'll let this run and
we'll attempt
to run it and it looks
like it might have worked so
what we can do is if
we go out
to our youtube 2 we grab
our public ip we go to
our nakama console and we just
put in actually i'll
just make a new thing colon
and we'll put in 7351 so
7351 enter does it do anything
that's the first
question it doesn't look like it's
going to so now we got
to figure out is it this
guy's fault
it looks like this is
running so my question is server
is ready to receive web requests
so it did spin up properly
it started the rule manager properly
so that's good news oh you
can see it is just absolutely
chugging though so if we take
a look at our youtube docker
container let's see it looks
like our cpu utilization is pretty
high our disk io is relatively
high as well we probably need
to
upgrade
to the
have one gig of ram but
at least it is running so
there is that the question is
so i was able
to get it to stop so
what we'll do is we'll close
it we'll go to our youtube
we'll go over to upgrade
droplet and then we'll go ahead
and just upgrade that up to
one size larger to the one
gigabyte
edition so we'll do that and
then we'll click cpu ram when
it's going to ask us to
turn off
our droplet so we'll go up
to power we'll power it off
because there's nothing on here anyway
so
we can just power cycle it
pretty hard there we go it's
powered down we'll go to resize
and we'll
adjust it up one size just
to let it be the proper
size that it needs to be
we're gonna let that run
you'll see it's thinking about it
there we go and now we
got a one size bigger droplet
now we can go
ahead and power cycle that bad
boy back on let's go into
our networking let's come back to
our
firewall and create a firewall now
the firewall is just going to
be test firewall and what we'll
do is we'll have an inbound
of ssh we're also going to
allow a custom one and we're
going to
allow for 7351 so we'll copy
that bad boy and we'll go
ahead and paste it like that
and then
we'll do the same thing for
as well and then we're going
to allow another one which is
going to be 7351 udp and
7350 udp
that way we can have all
of our stuff all of our
ducks in a row and everything
kind of covered
now you can see here all
outbound is good and we should
be good to go so we'll
go ahead and hit
create firewall and that should create
that firewall onto that networking system
so if we
go to our droplet and we
go to youtube 2 you should
see that it's going to be
7351 and we're
going to see right here under
our firewall networking no firewalls are
applied to this
droplet so i need to apply
this firewall so let's see if
we need droplets we can choose
our
droplet add droplet and then we
will search for youtube 2 and
we'll go ahead and connect it
to
that droplet so now that should
give our droplet the firewall it
needs to do its job so
now we
should be able to go to
console
and fire that up and then
hit cd nakama and then docker
compose up and in theory it
should run a
lot faster which it is you
can see it's actually firing off
just well the init node was
successfully
done cockroach database is up so
now we're starting to get the
proper logs that we expect so
my guess is it had something
to do with the lack of
ram that we had so let's
try that we'll refresh
it and see if we can
get it up and running and
there we go so you can
see now we have nakama
running out on our website which
is 198-199-80-118 and
you guys of course can go
to this and use it
so if you type admin password
you can see we have our
nakama instance just like before and
it's
exactly the same so you guys
can actually use this for your
own project providing that it doesn't
get
down immediately because for some reason
it gets shut down sometimes and
that causes some issues
but that's how easy it is
to get this to fire off
now and in order to detach
let's hit ctrl c
we'll stop our docker connection right
here and you'll see in a
second it's going to gracefully
stop so we'll give it a
minute to kill everything we'll hit
docker compose up dash dash detach
and with that
should do is it should allow
us to fire this up and
be detached and there you go
so now we're
detached so if we hit ps
you'll see that it's not running
but if i come in here
and i refresh you
can see that nakama is running
if i close this and i
refresh you'll see that nakama is
running
even though we are no longer
connected to our docker instance so
that's how we can actually
get that to run without needing
to keep that window open because
it should do is it should
allow us to fire this up
and be detached and there you
go so now we're
if you were to have closed
the window when nakama's running like
that previously without
running the dash dash detach then
it would have closed that docker
instance and then your whole
project would have been gone so
that's basically how that works so
now if we head out to
godot here
we can come up to here
and change this value to our
nakama instance so if we come
in here
you can see here is our
nakama instance right here so we'll
copy that we'll paste
this like so and then if
we hit play you'll see that
we can now submit and log
in so you'll see
that i have logged in so
now if i take a look
at my nakama instance out here
on the web if i refresh
you'll see that when we go
to accounts i have an account
right here just like as if
i was playing
the game locally so this is
how that works if i go
to my account i have an
account right here
and you can come in here
and go test two and you'll
see that if i click name
of match test
join create test join create we
just joined our match and then
if the host says start game
and
then start game you'll see that
we both started our game now
something here is broken but i
don't
think that that's a nakama issue
i think that's just a my
code issue so you can see
that we are
transferring the data to our game
and then we're going to go
to our game and we're going
to
as expected here in our nakama
instance so we do have the
presences as expected but i feel
like
something here is wonky a little
bit and i think that's because
i'm not in the right scene
to do
this i think i have to
go to game manager.tscn if
you remember this is our game
manager here so
let's refresh this guy let's try
rerunning it so we'll hit test
test two test
join create test join create start
game start game and you can
see that our game is now
running
not locally anymore so this will
work with your friends across the
web and what i'm going to
do
is i'm going to go get
one of my friends and i
will have him hold my code
and then he will also
do this and i'll show you
guys that it does work out
on the internet so i will
be right back
okay and then hit start game
and as you guys can see
right here my friend and i
are both working together and playing
the same
game at the same time over
the internet using our nakama instance
now you can see here that
there is a little bit of
lag and i think the reason
for that is because we're flooding
the
actual nakama instance because it has
a bunch of data that it's
passing through so we should
probably figure out a better way
to optimize this but at least
we have it we're going to
be able to
work for now so at this
point we've gone through quite a
few things we talked about groups
we
talked about chatting and we talked
about how to get our stuff
to work out on the internet
for our
project and allow us to work
on multiple networks with each other
so if you like this video
go and
hit that like button hey you
know if you dislike this video
go and hit that dislike button
because
i am here to make content
for you guys this video was
a viewer suggested video so if
you have any
suggestions please leave them in the
comments below and i'll see you
in the next one bye bye
comments below or jump on my
github link is in the description
and put in a service ticket
and i'll be
more than happy to add it
to my list of tutorials for
the future and hey if you
have any questions
or comments about this video go
ahead and leave them in the
comments below or jump on my
discord
link is in the description and
i'll be more than happy to
help you out but that is
all i have for
you guys today so thank you
so much again for watching i
will see you all next time
thanks
so
you