Hey guys, this is Mitch with
Fineboy CGI and today we're going
to continue our Nakama tutorial
series where I take you from
zero to understanding all the fundamentals
of Nakama and in this video
we're going to talk about how
to do groups so that's going
to allow you to add users
to like
a guild or like a group
setting then we're going to talk
about doing chats and chatting between
each other so sending messages to
each other and finally due to
popular requests I'm going to talk
about how to host your Nakama
instance out on the internet so
that you can play games with
your
friends or of course you can
release your game out to make
it into a multiplayer game so
that's what
I have in store for you
guys today so let's go ahead
and get started all right so
this tutorial assumes
that you already completed the previous
tutorial where we actually integrated Nakama
for the most
part so this one's going to
be going over more of the
features and things like that that
are
available to you so let's go
ahead and get started with that
and the first thing we're going
to talk
about is creating groups so groups
are basically like a guild or
a team of people that want
to play
with each other multiple times not
necessarily as a party but as
an actual group so after the
game is
ended and everything is done you
still have access to that group
of people so the first thing
that
I'm going to do is I'm
going to come in here and
I'm going to hide our friends
section because we're
actually running out of space here
and I really should name all
of these but that's probably going
to break all of my code
so we'll go ahead and just
hide that panel go ahead and
add in a new panel
like so I'm going to go
over here make it about this
big give or take I'm going
to right click add
a child node we'll add in
a label like that we're going
to make it about this big
and we'll have a
name parameter there we'll go ahead
and duplicate it and say description
and then we'll come in here
right click add in a child
node and we'll add in a
line edit like so
and we'll make it about this
big give or take we'll control
duplicate that and we'll make it
about
this big I mean technically the
description should be a little bit
longer but that's okay we'll make
it work for what we're gonna
do so that's fine and I'll
just kind of organize this properly
then we'll
add in a button and this
button is going to allow us
to create a group now I'm
going to need multiple
buttons but for right now we'll
just do one I think so
we'll go ahead and say create
group like so
and I'll probably need to make
this panel larger to be honest
I'm running out of space here
so we'll go
ahead and just make this a
touch bit bigger like so now
when we want to create a
group all we have to
do is if we grab this
button name it create group like
so we'll go into our node
button down and we'll
hook that to our control node
just like that now you'll see
when I hook it to the
control node it
should create a create group button
down function it looks like I
already did this in a previous
section so I'm going to go
ahead and get rid of that
that's my fault that caught me
off guard real
quick but to create a group
all we have to do is
say client dot create group async
and then we can
pass in our session like so
and then we have to pass
in a name now the name
is whatever the name
is that we put as our
line edit now if we take
a look we have our name
right here so we'll say
group name and then group description
like so and then we'll go
back to our script and we'll
do
dollar sign group name comma or
dot text comma dollar sign group
description dot text
and then you'll see that they
have the option for an avatar
url now you don't have to
supply one
but you can and that's really
cool because it basically would allow
you to have some kind of
url for an image that you
could load for their group so
I'm going to put that as
empty comma and
then you'll see that they have
a language so we'll say their
main language is en it doesn't
really matter
necessarily but it is a thing
that exists and actually I need
to I'm messing up my little
things
here we'll put an empty url
we'll put a en for the
avatar title and then you can
choose whether or not
it's an open or if it's
not so an open means if
it's a public group so if
people can actually see
it and index it for other
people so if you say false
then it's a private group so
if you don't
want it to be listable which
we'll discuss listing in a little
bit but it allows you to
basically say
is this a listable group so
I'm going to say true because
it makes sense to have a
listable group and
then you can have a max
number of members now once this
is set you cannot change it
so make sure you
set it to a value that
you want so if a guild
can only have 64 members then
you set it to 64 if
it's
100 members then you can set
it to 100 so in my
case I'm going to say 32
just because 32 is just a
good
round number now after that there
is nothing else that we can
do so we'll go ahead and
just say 32 now
typically this also returns a group
api so you could say var
group is equal to await client
asynchronous and then we can just
go ahead and print out that
group now you don't have to
do this
but it is a way to
get a hold of that object
if that makes sense so if
you needed to go ahead and
make your group you know visible
or not visible or something like
that you could do that right
here
so now if we go ahead
and make sure that our nakama
instance is running so if I
take a look at my
containers you can see it is
actually running so there we go
we'll go ahead and hit play
and then we're going to go
ahead and submit we're going to
connect to our game we're going
to call
our group test group description this
is our test group and we'll
click create now you'll see that
we
have a error group name must
be set so I must have
messed up on my group name
so let's take a look
panel five group name oh I
made a mistake because this is
the original panel I did some
recording
earlier that um I didn't keep
it but I never actually removed
that panel so we'll change this
to panel
six and then we'll go from
there so we'll refresh this and
try this one more time that's
my fault
so we'll submit test group this
is a test group create group
and you'll see that we get
a success
right there so now I'm going
to navigate to one two seven
nakama console right here so we'll
go to our
one two seven seven three five
one and then we will connect
into our nakama group if we
go to groups you
will see there is our test
group and you can see this
is what we have if we
take a look at our members
you can see that there is
a super admin so what in
the world is a super admin
well a super admin is
a person that has full control
over that group so this person
jj rb v w e x
k i is a super admin
of that
group so what that means is
that they have the ability to
delete that group and when you
are a
super admin you have full control
over that group there are four
different membership states there's
super admin which means that you
are basically god you can do
whatever you want to this group
you can
delete people you can do whatever
you want and basically you can
delete the group and that's a
big
thing admin which allows you to
update your group and allow you
to accept kick promote delete ban
or
promote members and then they have
members which allows you to actually
have a regular group member
they don't have the ability to
do anything they cannot accept join
requests stuff like that and then
they have the join request mode
which basically is when a user
wants to join they need to
be accepted
so you have to say yes
i will accept you as a
part of a group and that's
how you know the different
states if that makes sense so
if we go to our user
management we look for the jj
r person if we go into
accounts i have a bunch of
usernames here because i've been doing
a lot of testing on my
end but if i look
for jj rb jj rb well
that person let me see jj
i have 71 accounts so you
can see i have a bunch
of
accounts because i've been doing a
lot of testing on my end
for my own stuff and nakama
is being
difficult so let me refresh jj
rb well apparently jj doesn't exist
within my vast number of people
so
i'm not sure why it did
that but that's okay there's probably
a master account that it's using
actually it's right here jj rb
right here so i'm not sure
why it used this specific one
unless i logged
in and created it with device
authentication which is possible but that's
okay we'll figure that out in
a minute but that's basically how
we create a group now you
can see we also printed out
a group as well
so you can see here we
have our creator id which is
right here the creator id is
db so this is the
creator id so our creator is
jj so we must have logged
in with device authentication which means
i probably didn't reset my client
authentication stuff so let me take
a look at that real quick
my
apologies i may not have reset
some of my code so that
it worked properly did user authentication
instead of our um device authentication
so my guess is that's probably
what it is so if i
go to log in
yeah right here i'm doing a
unique device id right here and
i'm logging in with that socket
connection so
that's what's going on here so
what i'm gonna do is i'm
gonna control k to comment that
out and i'm
going to go ahead and log
in with my username so now
i'm gonna go in here and
i'll reset this because
it's going to be kind of
difficult to have a group that
uh exists that's not tied to
an actual user
so i'll go ahead and do
that i'll refresh and then we're
going to recreate that group just
because it
makes more sense so i'll say
test group description this is a
test group and we'll go ahead
and create
that group now if we take
a look at our nakama console
you will see that because this
was created
by test that person is the
super admin so whoever creates the
group gets super admin status now
in
order to add users it's actually
relatively easy all we need to
do is go in to our
project here and you
can see right here we have
the ability to create a group
so we'll just go ahead and
duplicate this
and we will come down here
and we'll right click disconnect we're
going to go in here connect
and say
on add user we'll say add
underscore user underscore to group like
so button down and we'll go
ahead and
connect that and i'm going to
rename this to add user to
group so with this for us
to be able to add
users to group it's actually really
easy all we need to do
is pass in the group id
that we want to
add ourselves to so unfortunately we
have to actually pull that user
identifier so if you look at
this you can see inside of
our groups we have a user
id right here this is the
identifier that we
need to give them to be
able to add ourselves to that
group so if we come in
here and copy this we can
come down here go back into
godot and then basically just say
await client dot join group async
and then do
session comma and then we'll just
pass in that group identifier now
if we come in here and
we hit play
you'll see in a second we'll
go ahead and log in as
test 2 we will type test
i mean it doesn't really
matter and you can see the
text here is wrong but that's
okay we'll click create group which
is
technically add group and you'll see
that we get an authorization token
right here we got a 404
group
not found so my guess is
that i have the wrong identifier
go to group group id i
do so we'll go
ahead and copy that and we'll
go back here we'll change this
guy like so paste control s
and the nice
thing about godot is that if
you uh just change the code
in here you can just click
that and you
can see that it should work
and that's because godot is a
non-compiled language so you can
actually get
away with changing it and re
-executing the code so now if
you look at members you can
see test 2 is now
a member now you might be
wondering okay so anybody can join
my group yes anyone can join
your group as
long as long as it is
public if it's not public then
you have to be approved so
that's where the
difference comes in so if i
come in here i remove test
2 i go to details and
i change this to not open
and i save it now if
i go ahead and i hit
create group or i guess connect
to the group you can see
that there is a join request
and that means that i have
to approve that before they can
be a part of
the group so the question is
how do you actually accept that
join request well to accept a
join
request what you need to do
is you need to come in
here and actually code out a
small subroutine first
thing first i'm going to come
in here and change this to
add join group like that and
then i'm going
to go ahead and duplicate this
guy drag this guy down like
so and i'm going to say
add user
to group like so and if
i just hit enter that will
help with formatting this button a
little bit better
now we'll pull this name parameter
to allow ourselves to actually you
know go from there
and this should probably be called
join group so it'll be fine
i guess for now but it's
just something
i'm not a huge fan of
but that's okay so we'll go
ahead and click node right click
disconnect connect
and then we'll go ahead and
create that little function there now
to accept a join request you
need
to be able to list your
groups or your users inside of
that group and that's really easy
to do we can
basically just say var users is
equal to await client dot list
group users async like that we
can pass in our
session token and then we can
pass in our group id now
our group id is right here
so we'll go ahead and
copy that and paste it and
then we'll hit comma and then
we can actually have a different
state so
this is where that one two
i guess zero one two and
three is useful if you wanted
to you could list
everyone that is a member of
the group everyone that's waiting to
join the group and anybody that's
a super user or an admin
just by changing this from zero
through three in our case we're
going to be
grabbing all the people that are
awaiting for their joins you can
see the state is three so
we will
go ahead and do that and
then all we need to do
is come in here and say
for user in users dot group
underscore users colon var you is
equal to user dot user and
then await client dot add group
users async
pass in our session right here
comma what our group id is
which in this case is this
guy right here
so we'll pass that guy in
comma and then we'll pass in
you and now we'll go ahead
and add that person
so now if i refresh and
i go add user to group
so if i submit i log
in as the test user and
i click add
user to group you'll see that
we got an error here unable
to convert uh argument three to
pack string
array so u is not correct
so let's take a look at
what u is real quick i
don't think there's really
an easy way to handle this
without going bracket bracket and then
passing in dot id and then
just
using their id i think that
that will work it's not the
most ideal way to fix it
but if i log in i
hit add user you should see
a nice request here and then
we'll go ahead and refresh this
and you can
see that they are now a
member and that's because when we
built the group we made it
a private group
now you might be wondering is
there a way for us to
make a group private or public
through code right
so that way it doesn't have
to happen immediately on start and
the answer to your question is
yes you
can actually do that pretty easily
all you need to do is
come in here go in here
let's grab this make
it slightly bigger again the group
section is going to be very
large for this so we'll add
in a check
box here like so and we'll
call it open like that and
then we're going to add in
a toggle switch so
i'll just put this right here
for right now we'll call it
open that's fine and then we'll
go ahead and
say on button down or i
guess on toggled we'll toggle this
on our control node and basically
when
it gets toggled it'll show you
yes or no so we'll say
await client dot update group asynchronously
we'll pass in our session token
comma our group id which is
this guy right here and we'll
talk about
how to get that group id
uh through code in a second
comma and then the name of
the group which
i'll pass in null because i
don't want to change it and
then we'll pass in toggled underscore
on like
that and you'll see that if
i come in here and i
submit and then i click open
you'll see if we refresh
our nakama instance here so we'll
refresh this page you'll see it's
not open if we close it
it should
hopefully do it real quick maybe
not let's take a look let's
do a break point here i
could just be
crazy so if i come in
here toggle response code 400 specify
at least one field to update
okay let's see if we come
in here comma p name p
description variant null so null comma
description
null comma avatar null comma language
tag en comma now this is
how you update any of your
parameters by the
way so now we have our
p open i think that's why
toggled on and you can see
here we have null null null
so
this is the username right the
name of the group the description
of the group and the whether
or not it's
open or not so you can
actually really play around here and
update any of these values so
now if we hit
play in theory it should just
work so we'll come in here
submit we do that and then
we take a look
at our group here we refresh
you'll see that open is now
on if we set it to
off and we refresh you'll see
that it is now closed so
that's how you can open and
close and that's really how you
can update any of
these values so if i came
in here if i come back
to godot here and i grab
my description i believe
that's name description avatar url so
if i name this the
strong gamers and then i change
the description to we are the
strong gamers exclamation point
if i come in here and
i hit this little toggle here
well our session got dc'd so
let me refresh this guy real
quick
let me re-log in and
then i'll change it so now
it's going to be open and
the titles and everything
has been changed strong gamers we
are the strong gamers so that's
how you can update those values
now
again typically you wouldn't use a
toggle switch to do this i'm
just showing you guys how to
do that
so i can show you the
open and close really quickly you
can see now it's closed so
that's how you can
update that group visibility that's how
you can update the group values
information values for your
group now something else that's pretty
big and pretty important to know
is how to actually list
groups so nakama groups are a
resource like anything else right so
you can actually list them and
index
them and pull back information using
them so what does that mean
well that means that you can
use what's
called list groups asynchronously to actually
list out your groups so if
i come in here i can
show you guys
how that works so i'm going
to right click add in a
panel like so i'll drag this
guy over here like
this and i will make an
h box container or i guess
it'd be a v box container
like so and i'll make that
full rect so that way it
maximizes the full screen now granted
that being said we only have
one group
right now so we kind of
need to make multiple groups for
us to be able to see
them all but we
can at least show how that
works so if we come in
here i grab this add user
to group button i duplicate
it bring it down here and
i type list groups like so
and then i'm going to grab
this description duplicate
it pull it down here and
this is going to be group
query like so i'll change this
to list groups
and i'll change this to group
query now what we can do
is hit ctrl s we can
go into scripting
we can grab our list group
go to node right click disconnect
right click connect and connect it
now what we could do when
we want to list our groups
is we can set up a
limit so we can say var
limit is equal to let's say
10 now we don't have 10
groups to list but we'll use
that as a default value
then we'll say var result is
equal to await client dot list
groups async now you'll need to
pass in
your session just like usual and
then you'll need to pass in
some kind of name that you're
trying to
search up now this is a
variant so of course you can
you know get back whatever you're
looking for
so in my case i'm going
to hit dollar sign group query
dot text and that'll let me
have that limit
and then we'll pass in our
limit which by the way does
default to 10. now they have
a cursor value
and that cursor value allows you
to say i want the next
10. so think of it kind
of like this when you
do your query you're going to
pull back the first 10 but
what happens if the person doesn't
see the
group that they want on the
first 10. well that's where the
cursor value comes in so you
can hit zero
make that cursor value of zero
language tag will allow you to
pick a language in my case
i'm going
to do en and again you
don't have to do that but
it's going to filter out any
groups that are not
english you can see right here
language en so that's going to
allow you to have that limiting
factor right
because if they're spanish you don't
want to necessarily show them up
if they're looking for an english
group if they speak english not
spanish it's going to be a
problem and then you can look
up members
which allows you to pick members
i'm going to pass in null
for that and then you could
choose whether
or not it's an open group
or not so a lot of
times when you're doing groups you
might want to
check to see if it's a
public group not a private group
because sometimes if you have a
group like a
guild and you don't want people
to see your guild you probably
should make sure that that is
false
or true depending on your use
case so i'll make it true
and that's pretty much everything that
you
need to know here now with
this we should be relatively good
to go so now we could
basically
we'll have our results we can
say for group in result dot
groups like that and then we
can basically
come in and print out our
groups so you can see that
we can go print group dot
name like that
and from here we should be
relatively good to go so now
we can hit play we can
log in as test we can
come in here and say i
believe our group name is strong
gamers so we can say strong
and list groups
and it should come back well
it's not happy so that's not
a good thing our p cursor
query parameters
strong that's fine nakama serialize escape
and not convert argument one from
int to string
i wonder if it's mad because
our cursor is an int i
think there's an issue here with
how they have
their stuff set up so what
if we come back here and
we do null instead so if
we come in here
null just to see if that
fixes the problem so we'll come
in here we'll type strong
and it's still mad oh that's
because i didn't log in so
that's fair that's understandable so we'll
log
in we will say strong list
groups and you can see that
we get a 400 the error
name filter cannot be
combined with any other filter so
it looks like according to nakama's
documentation you can combine
them but i guess you can't
inside of here so let's try
that and see if that fixes
it because according
to our documentation you can do
this but i guess we can't
so let's try that
so we'll hit list groups and
you will see that we get
an authorization bearing right here i
don't know
if that came back with really
anything so let me see what
happens if i list groups let's
see what
our result comes back with after
i drop a breakpoint here and
it did it came back with
nothing so nakama
is not doing what i want
it to do because of course
it's not welcome to programming let's
see what happens
if i do capital s it's
probably capital
case sensitive so we'll come in
here and we'll take a look
at our results still got nothing
back
so we'll continue through what happens
if i do a percent sign
and see if that gives us
something back
now because it might be that
it needs to be a query
of some description so we can
check that out real
quick yep it needs to be
a query so you can see
it pulled back the one that
we're looking for so it
pulled back our group so when
you do a text just be
aware of that you're going to
need to make it into
an actual query instead so you
need to add that percent sign
at the end so that's just
something to
keep in mind now you'll see
when i hit play it's going
to print out strong gamers right
there so
that's basically how you can list
and filter your groups so that
allows us to see those groups
and hunt down their identifier because
if you look you can see
when i list the groups
you can see when i come
in here and i take a
look at my results here the
group i come back with has
their identifier right here so if
you know where their um if
you know their name you can
pull back
their id so that's how we
would populate all these other values
right here is by listing it
and then
pulling back that group information now
since we can pull this information
that means that we can
actually come in here and use
that info on our panels and
things like that so what we
could do is we
could come in here and list
out their information and populate it
in a vbox container so we
could do
is we could go var vbox
is equal to vbox container dot
new like that and then if
i need if i do this
correctly equals vbox container dot new
and then we could come in
here and do the same thing
but for
labels so we can say label
so var name label is equal
to a label dot new like
that and then name label dot
text
is equal to if we take
a look at this right here
we can go name so it
would be group dot
dot let's take a look at
this
what is result dot groups let's
see results dot groups so it's
going to come back with this
so
then it would be dot name
like that and then we could
say vbox
dot add child and then we
could add our name label as
a part of that child and
then we can come in here
and say dollar sign vbox and
we can find out which panel
is ours which arguably we should
come up with a
better naming convention here but that's
fine dot add child and we
could add in our vbox right
here
like that and that would allow
us to effectively add it as
a child for our project and
then if we
refresh this in theory providing that
this is going to work and
i don't know if it's going
to work this
is kind of me coding this
a little bit off the cuff
we can hit list groups and
you can see that we now
have
strong gamers there so that's something
that we can actually do and
pull back their information
so that could be really useful
for us to set up for
like a selection system or something
like that
and speaking of that what we
could do is we could come
in here and say var hbox
is equal to hbox
container dot new like so and
then we can do hbox dot
let's see if we bring this
down here instead of
doing vbox dot add we can
do hbox and then we could
add our vbox
dot add child h box like
so and then what that means
is that we could add in
a button
and i know this is kind
of weird because i'm actually coding
a component instead of doing
it the other way but one
of the big things that people
have asked me is if you
could actually do
it this way and i want
to cover that and show you
guys yeah you can actually build
interface elements
inside of code and then actually
have it exist so that's kind
of what i'm showing here so
if we come
in here and say h var
button is equal to button dot
new like so then we can
come in here and do button
dot text is equal to select
group like that and then we
can come in here and say
h box dot add child
button like that and then we
can add that h box and
that should allow us to have
all of that information
that we were looking for before
right here so if we hit
submit list groups you can see
we have
a button right here so now
we can basically connect its on
button click right here so you
can say button dot
button down like that dot dot
connect and then we could just
say and here we could call
out a function
so if i come in here
and say funk on group select
button down and i can pass
in the group
like that and i could come
in here and do dot connect
and we could do what's called
binding and
binding is actually really cool so
we can say on group select
button like that dot bind and
then i can
bind to parameters so i can
actually come in here and bind
group and now if we come
in here and we
print out that group you'll see
providing that we did this correctly
and i know that this is
like way beyond what the actual
tutorial is but i think that
this is pretty cool so i
figured i would
show it off if we do
this we can come in here
and list our groups and then
select a group and you'll see
that it passes in that information
right there it binds the parameters
so you could actually come in
here and set a selected group
parameter right here and there you
go it would actually work so
what we
could do is we could come
in here and say all the
way up here set our
var var selected group and then
we could come down here and
just say selected group is equal
to group
like that and then we could
come in here and do i
believe it's group dot id so
you could come in here
and go selected group dot id
like that copy this bad boy
go like this paste and paste
and paste and
then you would be able to
effectively update the values in there
without needing to actually have
that data so if i come
in here i list my groups
well first i need to actually
hook up my session really
quick so if i submit that
there we go i list my
groups i select it now i
have that selected i can
come in here and do a
open and you will see that
if i come in here and
i refresh this you'll see that
that worked and that's because we
bound that parameter right here well
if i could find it right
here
to actually work so that's a
way that we can go about
making a group selection system relatively
simple and that's how we can
actually list our groups as well
so i know that that's kind
of a
complicated way to show it but
i figured that it was an
interesting way to approach it and
i figured you
guys would appreciate that so now
the question is what if we
want to promote a user or
maybe demote a
user or kick or ban a
user from our group well in
order to do that first we
need to actually get
the user id of that person
so you can see here this
person is a member and we
want to get that user id
back so if we come back
to godot here and we go
ahead and come down here we
need to basically get a
user name go and fetch their
id and then basically promote or
demote that person so what i'm
going to
do is i'm going to right
click my panel i'm going to
add in a line edit like
so i'm going to drag this
guy down here we'll go like
this make it about i don't
know about that big we'll come
in here we'll
say user user to manage we'll
say and then we'll come in
here and hopefully we won't run
out of space
if we do we'll figure something
out but let's right click add
in a child node let's add
in a button we'll
add in a button for promoting
right here like so and if
i think about it for a
second with groups
we need to promote demote kick
and ban somebody and then also
leave that group so we'll need
to
figure out a way to give
ourselves a little bit more space
here because i'm running out so
maybe i
can drag this guy up butt
it up a little bit closer
drag this guy down give ourselves
a little bit more
space but we can promote duplicate
kick
demote
and then i believe we would
need to ban somebody
and then finally the last interaction
that we need to do is
to actually come in here and
leave so we could just come
over ah goodness we're running out
of space here we have so
much
functionality here it's actually hard to
make the space so we'll drag
this guy down a tiny
bit maybe give ourselves a bit
more space over here drag this
guy over like so there we
go
and we can change this one
to leave group like that now
when we want to promote a
user let's
change the name of this to
promote user kick user demote user
and ban user like that and
then leave
free so i'm going to go
ahead and grab promote user and
i'm going to change my line
edit to user to
manage and then i'll click on
promote user we're going to go
ahead and connect that to our
nakama
controller here we'll come down here
and we'll basically go ahead and
promote a user so first
things first we need to actually
get our user account now unfortunately
you need to actually
go and fetch that user account
so first we'll say var user
is is type nakama api dot
api
users is equal to await client
dot get users async and then
we can come in here and
go session so we
could pass in that session and
then we need to pass in
ids so when you do this
you can pass in ids or
usernames in our case we're going
to pass in a username but
you can pass in their actual
um id as well so i'm
just going to pass in a
blank and then for the username
i'll just pass in a single
parameter and that's going to be
dollar sign user to manage dot
text comma and you'll see that
they
also have a facebook id in
this case we'll pass in null
we don't really have a facebook
id to manage
a user but they do separate
that out and i'm not really
sure why they do that but
that's a thing so
it's just something to keep in
mind now what we can do
is say for you in users
dot users and that's a
really bad way so we'll say
result and then we'll just do
result dot users that's going to
be a little
bit better than what we're doing
right now now once we do
this we have the actual user
information
so that's how you pull back
that user's information so you can
actually just do you dot id
and that will
be their identification right that'll be
their actual information so what we
can do is we can come
in here and promote that user
so we'll come in here and
say await client dot promote user
and group async
you can pass in our session
token and then we can pass
in our group id so in
our case that's going
to be our selected group dot
id comma and i believe it's
selected group dot id let me
double check really
quick because sometimes i forget things
it is and then we have
to pass in a user identifier
so that's
going to be u dot id
like that and now if we
go ahead and hit play you'll
see in a second that if
i
connect to this and then i
list my groups i select my
group and then i type in
test two and i click
promote well we have an error
so the error is cannot convert
argument three from string to a
packed array
and that's because this can be
a group of users it's not
actually just one group it's actually
multiple people so we can go
ahead and do that and then
try it again so it's because
we need we can
actually have multiples of somebody so
we'll go like that we'll submit
we'll list our groups select
group test two we'll promote that
person you'll see that that looks
like that was successful we'll
head back to our nakama console
we'll refresh and you will see
that this person is now an
admin
so that's huge because it's going
to allow us to be able
to create admins and now if
we click it a
second time you'll see if we
refresh they are now a super
admin that means that they can
delete this
group if they want to now
the question might be okay so
i can promote users how do
i demote them
right well if we come in
here we go in right here
we go into demote user button
down let's connect that
real quick we come in here
and basically copy and paste this
code so we'll just copy this
guy paste it
and instead of promote we can
just pass in demote easy enough
and same thing for kick user
right we
could just kind of bring that
in and let's do ban user
as well right so we'll just
bring that in as
well if we copy this guy
we can copy paste and paste
because they're all the exact same
functionality
so we can come in here
and say kick group users and
then ban group users
and now if i refresh this
you'll see if i submit list
groups select my group test two
i go demote
you'll see that that worked if
we come over here we refresh
our users right here you'll see
that they
are now an admin and then
i can go ahead and ban
a user and you'll see non
-existent function ban
groups that's probably my fault group
users async and it looks like
you actually can't ban a user
so
we'll remove that that's my fault
i um was reading the documentation
earlier but it looks like it
got
removed so you're not actually able
to ban a user anymore from
a group so we'll come in
here we'll
go ahead and type submit list
our groups select our group we'll
go to test two we'll go
ahead and demote
the user so you'll see if
we refresh they are an admin
if we come in here we
can go ahead and kick
them and then if we refresh
you will see they have been
removed from that group and that's
basically how
you can actually manage your users
in here and you can also
delete a group and leave a
group so
if we want to leave a
group we can come in here
and go into our stuff here
we can click on leave group
button down on leave button down
we'll connect that and to leave
a group it's actually relatively simple
all we need to do is
type
await client dot leave group async
we'll pass in our session and
then we'll pass in our group
id which
is going to be our selected
group id now this will allow
us to leave our group but
the problem is that
if i leave my group i
will actually um not have any
more users in that group so
what i'll do is i'll
log in as test two i
will come in here and pass
in my group name if i
remember correctly it's if we
list groups we can select the
group join group and then you
should see that we will join
that group so
you'll see as a member we
can refresh and there we go
we're in that group and now
we can come in here
and say leave group and then
if we refresh we have left
that group right there and now
we can
actually uh safely delete our group
right because we now have shown
that that section works that's
how you leave a group it's
actually really easy you just do
leave group asynchronously so now what
happens if you want to delete
a group well we're going to
need an additional button for that
so let's
duplicate our leave group we'll just
pull it down here i guess
we're kind of running out of
space here
so i'll just put it right
here i'll move open over we'll
grab leave group and we'll put
delete group
now in order to delete a
group we'll disconnect this connect in
order to delete a group it's
actually
really simple as well so when
you delete a group all you
need to do is type client
await client dot delete group async
and then you can pass in
the session
and the selected group dot id
and that's literally all you need
to do so now if i
refresh my screen
here i log in as test
the super admin and then we'll
log in as test we'll come
in here we'll log in as
test two we'll submit we will
go ahead and hit list groups
we'll select that group we're going
to join
that group really quick and remember
because this is an open group
that person should be able to
just
join there we go so the
person has joined and now you'll
see if i go in as
test two right here and i
go ahead and i click delete
group which this is leave group
but it's delete group in um
our code you'll see
request has returned spot response 400
group not found or you are
not allowed to delete and the
reason why is because that person
does not have the capability to
delete this group you can see
it's still here however if i
come in here as test or
as my super admin and i
log in and i click list
groups i select my group and
then i click delete group you'll
see if we go back to
groups it has now
been removed and that's basically everything
that you need to know about
groups
now when it comes to chats
which is actually a whole feature
inside of nakama you can actually
build chat rooms right inside of
nakama so when it comes to
chats how do we actually get
that to work
well first things first we are
majorly out of space so i
am going to hide the group
section as you can
see we have all sorts of
different areas here where we can
actually do our nakama work here
so i'm
actually just going to come in
here and just start hiding a
lot of this because we're running
out of
space here so i'll hide this
panel and this panel and there
we go so when it comes
to chats we have three
different types of chats and we'll
talk about all three of them
and how to send messages and
stuff like
that but we have three different
chat types we have dynamic rooms
group chats and direct chats okay
and we'll talk about the group
chats when we get there but
one of the big ones that
a lot of people
like is the dynamic rooms the
dynamic rooms is basically a random
room that gets created for temporary
for a temporary for a temporary
time span and it only stays
open as long as there are
people in
that chat room so the nice
thing about it is let's say
you have a match or something
like that you could
put people in that temporary room
and then have people communicate and
then once the match is over
that room just gets dissolved over
time whereas something like a group
chat that stays for as long
as the
group exists and then they also
have direct chats which is basically
one-on-one communications between
people which persist once again forever
so in order to do dynamic
rooms let's first right click add
a
child node let's add in a
panel here and let's make it
about this big now we're going
to have to build a
whole chat system so this will
take a little bit of time
so what i'm going to do
is i'm going to right
click add a child node i'm
going to add in a button
i'm going to right click add
a child node add in a
line edit right here we're going
to make the line edit about
yay big give or take if
my mouse will let
me we'll do that we'll add
in a button again providing that
i can click on this there
we go
we'll make it about yay big
and for our line edit we'll
just say chat name like that
and then we'll
come in here and say join
chat now you could automate this
as soon as a person goes
into a
match you could actually go set
up the uh room name and
automatically have them join but in
this case
we're going to manually do it
that way you guys get the
experience of how it works so
what we'll do
is we'll change this to join
chat room like that and then
the line at it will be
chat name like that
and then i'm going to come
in here go over here button
down and then i will hit
connect now when we
want to join a chat room
all we have to do is
come up with a room name
if it's persistent if it's hidden
and if it is a room
type so i will show you
all of those things so first
things first let's go var
channel is equal to await socket
dot join chat asynchronously now what
this is going to do is
we're
going to have a target now
that target is what the name
of that chat room is going
to be in this
case we'll just say actually we
already have a title right here
right so
dollar sign chat name dot text
comma and then you'll see that
we have an int type so
what does
that actually take what is the
type well the type is a
nakaba socket chat type or a
channel type so we'll
say var type is equal to
nakaba socket dot channel type dot
and you'll see that we have
different types
direct direct message group and room
and each one has a different
use so thankfully the code is
basically the
same but what matters is if
it is going to be a
room if it's going to be
a group or if it's going
to be
a direct message in our case
it's going to be a room
so i'm going to come in
here and say type
comma and then if it's persistent
so in our case we don't
want it to be persistent so
false comma and then
if it's hidden it will say
false we wanted to make it
a public messaging chat so people
can actually go
in and message each other and
not have to authenticate or be
added to that chat and then
what i'm going to do is
i'm going to print that chat
information so print channel
like that now this will basically
print out our chats information so
if i refresh this and i
run this
if i join and i say
test and i join you'll see
that we now have a chat
that is right here you can
see
it has the id one it
has id here it says there's
a user test user id is
this session id is this so
we
can get all the people that
are inside of that chat right
there now if somebody else joins
test
to submit and then they go
test and they join you can
see here that we also joined
channel id 2 user
presence session this status user test
so we just got back that
user's account information right so we
got test and test 2 in
this chat with each other and
that's basically what these guys are
saying here
now in order to send a
message you need to actually be
able to receive that message right
so let's go
to our script here and let's
scroll all the way up to
the top and the reason why
i'm scrolling all
the way up to the top
is because we need to subscribe
when we create our socket to
the ability to actually
get messages so what we need
to do is go find where
our socket gets created
which is right here so we'll
come in here we'll say socket
dot and providing that godot wants
to be
nice to me it will auto
complete please
maybe not well we'll hit dot
received underscore
channel underscore message dot connect
like that and then we'll pass
in a callable so what this
is going to be is it's
just going to be a
very basic function that prints out
that message currently at least so
we'll say funk
underscore on underscore channel on
channel
message like that and we'll pass
in a message
now this could be a type
if you want it to be
which is going to be a
nakama api dot api
channel message like that and then
we can just go ahead and
print that message
and there we go now we're
going to connect that message so
we'll just pass on channel message
like
that and that will actually pass
that to this guy right here
and we'll go ahead and send
out that
signal now when we do our
message when we want to send
a message we need to actually
create a panel
for that so let's come in
here let's right click our panel
and add in another panel like
so i'm going
to drag this guy over here
make it about this big give
or take it we're going to
create a very basic
message block system so it's going
to be pretty ugly my apologies
but i want to try to
get this to
work as quickly as humanly possible
so what i'm going to do
is i'm going to put in
a line edit like
so i'm going to make this
go on the bottom stretched across
i'm going to pull this back
right click add
a child node we'll add in
a button i'm going to snap
that guy right in the bottom
right where we'll
make it about if i can
click on it about yay big
we'll put a send or maybe
just like an arrow like
that i think that'll work we'll
put a placeholder chat text here
we'll type this as chat text
we'll
make the panel title chat and
then we'll make the button submit
chat like that i'm going to
go ahead
and right click add any child
node and i'm going to add
in a
i am brain farting on what
it is it is a text
edit like that we'll make it
full screen so full wrecked
and we'll make it about yay
big that'll go ahead and make
it so that it's kind of
scalable and you
know easy to use now inside
of here i'll scroll down and
i will do auto wrap that's
fine so that means
that if i put in a
bunch of text here it's going
to auto wrap so you can
see if i do wrap mode
boundary
it will go ahead and wrap
that and then i will turn
on scroll as well so if
this continues so we'll
ctrl c ctrl v we'll paste
it you'll see that it's going
to scroll we also want to
we'll want to shut
off editable and i think that
will work because i think this
is placeholder text so if i
come in here
and we paste this text in
this will allow us to scroll
i'm curious if we can make
it follow
the uh actual scrolling but i
don't think we can i know
there's a way to do it
it's been a while since
i've done it but i think
i'll just go ahead and skip
that part but there is a
way to make it so it
automatically scrolls to the bottom but
that's okay right now so this
is basically what our chat setup
is
going to be it's going to
be relatively simple but it's going
to be something that we can
at least
use now i'm going to grab
my submit chat button i'm going
to go to node button down
i'm going to connect
that to my submit chat button
now when we want to do
a message right we want to
send a message we can come
in here and say var await
socket dot write chat message asynchronous
now this is going to require
a id so we have to
actually have some kind of chat
name in this case i'm just
going to go ahead and grab
this guy right here copy it
and paste it it's not the
most ideal situation because once you're
connected
to that channel you should probably
just be connected to that channel
right instead of
passing in this value here but
we can basically throw a value
up at the top and basically
just
save it across different functions and
that would solve this problem but
for right now we'll go ahead
and do this and then we
need to pass in our message
content so what we can do
is do dollar sign
chat text dot text like that
now i think we should probably
change this to text edit instead
just do
chat text box that way we
actually have that value now if
we hit play and we go
ahead and hit play
if we come in here we
both submit join test test number
two submit join test if we
send a text
test test send you'll see that
it is very mad at us
cannot convert argument to from string
to
dictionary so it's going to require
a dictionary for us to be
able to do that so what
we need to do
is we need to pass in
an actual dictionary of objects so
we can come in here pass
in this dictionary
like so and go quote message
colon that and the reason why
we have to do this is
because we can
actually do what's called uh emotes
right and emotes are sent via
um json data so that's the
reason why
it requires it to be a
dictionary so that we can actually
send over emote information now i'm
not going to
cover that just because uh there's
a whole like loading emotes and
stuff like that that you need
to do and that's way beyond
the basics of this tutorial so
if you guys want to look
at that you
guys can go check out their
real-time chatting section and they'll
go over that but i'll go
ahead
and hit submit test to submit
join test join test test send
and you'll see that we actually
get an
error so it says invalid chat
identifier so what's going on here
right well if you take a
look at your
chat here if we take a
look at our chat you'll see
that our chat actually has an
identifier id2
you see that so when you
have a chat it actually has
an identifier associated with that chat
and so
you don't want to pass in
the title of the chat you
want to pass in the identifier
you can see that we
have a channel right here so
if i go channel.id we
can go ahead and refresh this
guy and go submit
test submit and you'll see that
we are now printing out and
you will see that we have
an id right here
i added channel id in post
so that way it was nice
and quick but you can see
right here channel id is
two dot dot dot test so
two is the id of the
chat and test is the actual
id that we gave it so
we need
to pass that value in right
here for us to be able
to send messages so what we
can do is we can come
in
here copy this var channel go
all the way up to the
top
and go var current channel like
that and then we go all
the way back down to the
bottom
and do current channel is equal
to that and then we'll go
ahead and copy this
we'll paste it right here dot
id and then we can go
ahead and do current channel dot
id right here as
well now what that will do
is that it should allow us
to actually send it to the
proper id so we'll
hit submit test to submit test
join test join test send and
you should see right here we
no longer
have an error but instead we
have an actual message right here
i probably should not have used
the word
test i should probably use this
is a test message that way
we can actually see what it
is and you can
see here that i send a
message and you see right here
channel id test code is zero
content message
this is a test message and
that's basically how we can send
and receive messages now the nice
thing
is that if since we typed
our message section and unfortunately this
is getting pretty large so i
might
want to abstract some of this
out but if we go to
right here where our on channel
message is
at we have our different messages
that we can message information here
that we can actually use so
if
we type message dot you'll see
that it's going to automatically give
us some information here that
we can work with so you
can see that we have sender
id username all sorts of information
so the nice
thing is i can come in
here and i can go dollar
sign chat text box dot text
plus equals message dot user name
plus colon space plus message dot
and then if we take a
look there should be a
content dot message like that like
that and we should probably also
go ahead and pass in a
new line
because we want the user to
have a new line here now
so let's try this var content
is equal to
message dot content and then i
wonder if content dot message will
work instead
okay there we go we'll try
that and see if that works
also i'm going to want to
put a new line at
the end of this so we'll
go ahead and do that slash
n for a new line that
way every time somebody sends a
message it's going to be a
new lined message and now if
i refresh this in theory this
should work
so we'll go ahead and do
submit test join test to submit
test join test send and it
is very unhappy
so let's take a look you
can see the content here is
a string data so it looks
like we're going to need
to json parse this information so
we'll go json dot parse string
and we'll go ahead and pass
that in
and there we go and that
should fix that problem basically content
is a json value so that's
something that i didn't think about
i'm talking without thinking as i'm
doing this tutorial so
forgive me but we need to
actually parse that data so now
if we hit send you'll see
test test test
this is a test message like
so test to this is a
test message and that's basically how
you could do
a very basic communication system so
now the question is okay great
that's fine but how do i
actually do group chats and in
order to do group chats what
we need to do is we
need to come in here
and we need to go ahead
and grab another join chat here
and what i'm going to do
is i'm going to unhide
my group section and i guess
i'll just move it over so
we have a little bit more
space let's grab
this guy we'll drag him over
like this it's getting a little
on the cramped side with our
setup here so
i might need to readjust some
stuff but i don't think i
can fit it really up here
so we'll just kind
of push it over here and
that should just work i mean
it's a little tight but it
will work for
the demonstration we're trying to do
here so if i grab this
guy here i right click disconnect
inspector change this to join a
group chat like so when you
want to do a group chat
all you got to do
is come in and basically i
move this guy over there we
go all you really need to
do is you need to come
in
here connect your button down so
go ahead and connect that over
here and then we can come
in here
and basically just grab this exact
code right here it's almost a
duplication right it's almost
exactly the same we'll just drop
that guy in there and all
we really need to do
is come in here and when
we do our join socket asynchronously
we just basically need to pass
in
our group id so we'll say
and i believe we have a
group if i remember correctly so
selected group dot id
and then we can pass in
type for persistence we're going to
want to say true because we
want to keep
that group around right and then
we want it to be persistent
and we also want to change
this to a type
group chat and then what we
can do is we can come
in here hit play come over
here submit test we will
go ahead and create a group
so that way now our group
actually exists so if we refresh
our groups
i'll have to re-log in
because this is another recording session
and you can see we now
have a
test group and we are now
a part of it now from
here we can join that group
with test too so we'll come
in
here and i already did this
one so we'll do test to
test join group and it got
mad at me because our
selected group is not correct and
that's my fault so that's totally
fine so i will have to
refresh real
quick so we'll say submit test
we will go ahead and list
our groups we'll select our test
group we'll do
test to list our groups select
it join that group and then
when we join our chat we
can just join
group chat growing group chat and
then test and you will see
that this guy now gets it
and if we go
this is a test message and
we send that guy you can
see that that message gets sent
now you might be
going okay so why does this
matter right what is the benefit
of a group chat versus a
dynamic chat
well where a group chat matters
and why it's important is because
you can do what's called listing
the message history so because it's
a persistent chat we're going to
be able to pull back all
of that
information so the reason why that's
cool is because we can come
in here and we can say
okay when the
user joins a group which we'll
have to scroll down here to
right here and we'll need to
go ahead and
come in here and list out
that information so we'll say far
result is equal to await client
dot list
channel messages asynchronous we'll pass in
our session and then we'll pass
in our currently
selected groups so selected group dot
id we could pass in a
limit value so in our case
we'll just do
100 that's a very decent value
forward basically forward is forward or
backwards right so we can
grab the oldest or the newest
and that's what forward is is
forward is the newest so we'll
say forward
so we'll say true comma and
then i believe they have a
cursor value as well and cursor
is if i remember
correctly it's defaulted let's double check
really quick if we hit comma
cursor variance is null so
cursor allows you to say i
want you to start at this
point so if you're picking up
the next 100 values let's
say you have 500 messages you
can pass in number 200 and
then it'll grab from 200 to
300 if that makes
sense so in our case i'll
just leave that as null because
it's just going to be easier
for us to work
with it now we can go
for message in result dot message
like that messages like that and
then
we can basically just go exactly
what we did before so we
can come up here and grab
if you remember how
we actually parsed out our data
which arguably i should move this
down closer to my actual message
functionality so let's go ahead and
just do that really quick we'll
come down here and just drop
it right let's see this is
group stuff this is chat stuff
so we'll go ahead and just
drop it right there
and that'll just kind of keep
it within the group area so
that way i can basically come
in here and do
this and say chat room code
right here and that'll give me
somewhere to actually look at this
now what
we can do is we can
basically just grab this copy it
and paste and that's all we
need to do and then
in theory this should just work
so now if we hit play
in theory if we're lucky it
will work so we'll go
here we'll say list groups select
group join group chat and we
got an error message return response
invalid channel id so we have
a failure here that says that
our channel id is incorrect so
let's see
join chat asynchronously list channel messages
that should be correct
is it printing out what i
expect let's see so i don't
think that this worked 100 here
so let's try
by submitting list groups select group
that should select our group
and then i should be able
to join group chat but it
did not take it so the
question is is it because
i failed to join the group
chat or did it fail here
so if we do this the
id of the group
id is string get return if
not string else string await list
channel messages try refresh
and it's gonna run through that
real quick but it didn't do
anything as expected so
if i drop a breakpoint here
what is result result is an
object id cacheable null null so
we got a
nakama exception invalid channel id so
the question is is did our
channel get saved let's go ahead
and
take a look at nakama really
quick chat messages group chat no
messages found so our group chat
just
doesn't exist so that's not great
so that means something went wrong
with how we initialized our
group chat i think okay so
i figured out the issue so
basically when we do our list
channel messages
async we need to actually do
our current channel dot id instead
so when we do our join
chat asynchronous
we pull back a channel and
that's the channel that we're currently
in and basically we need to
go and
list those message right here and
then i have a section here
for messages in result messages if
the
message content does not contain an
empty so if for some reason
a message gets in there that's
empty
when we try to parse it
it's going to break so i
have this little if statement right
here that
basically just checks to see if
it's empty if it is ignore
it and there's no reason to
have it
so now if i hit play
you'll notice that when i come
in here and i hit submit
i list my groups i
select my groups and i join
my group chat you'll see i
pull back those messages and that's
one of the
big cool features of nakama is
that it keeps track of all
of that information because this is
after we
removed and rebooted the system right
it actually came back with the
proper messages that's basically
what persistence does right here this
true right here causes it to
be saved and to be reusable
later
that's one of the big cool
advantages here so now the question
is okay so how do i
do peer-to-peer
messaging well it's not technically peer
-to-peer but how do i
send messages directly to a user
well again it's relatively simple if
we come into our stuff here
we control c control v join
group chat
and then instead of join group
chat we have a join direct
chat i go ahead and grab
our where is it
join group chat right here and
i change this to join direct
chat like that we can come
in here
disconnect right click connect and connect
now in order to do a
direct chat it's actually relatively
easy it's exactly the same as
everything else you come in here
you go join chat room right
here copy it
come down here paste well really
actually we probably should just grab
this to be honest it's going
to
save us a bit of trouble
so if we paste this guy
in here change the channel type
to direct message
like that instead of having a
selected group id we need to
grab the user id in terms
of persistence
we want to keep true we
also want to keep false for
hidden but for this join chat
asynchronous we can
go ahead and pass in a
user id so we need to
get our actual user identifier and
the easiest way to do
that is by using the get
users asynchronous call if you remember
we did that earlier so we'll
just say
var users is equal to await
client dot get users asynchronous and
then we'll pass in our session
and we need to
pass in a id pack string
array and then the user name
that we're going to be passing
in
so in our case i think
if we take a look at
our user interface we have a
chat name we could probably just
take that i think that will
work so for the chat name
what i'll do is i'll just
pull this guy which
is chat name so we'll come
into our script we'll hit dollar
sign chat name dot text
and then that should bring back
our users so now we know
that it's going to bring back
one user and that's it so
since it's going to bring back
one user we can basically just
do
if users dot size is greater
than zero then we can do
the rest of this bit of
code here and then we
just pass in and say users
bracket bracket zero dot id and
that'll pass back a user id
that we can
actually communicate with so now in
theory this should work and of
course as always with theory it
doesn't always work but we'll see
so we'll submit as test we'll
submit as test two and then
we'll go test
test two join direct chat it's
mad and that's because users came
back let's see with an array
it looks like it's users dot
users so that's my fault so
we'll say users dot users and
i should
probably just do this as results
then or perhaps user results because
we don't want to mess with
our
current code down here that has
results already we'll just do that
and then for this we'll just
say
user result dot users bracket bracket
zero because we now know that
we need to go a little
bit deeper
than what we expected so now
if we go ahead and submit
test two join direct chat now
we're in a direct
chat if we go into test
two and we go to test
join direct chat we pass test
in
okay so i think i figured
out what's going on here so
i commented this out
just so we could check it
out but what i think is
going on here is remember in
our previous tutorial we had
test block test two and because
they're blocked they can't send them
messages so it completely
stops them from being able to
communicate with each other and that's
why this is happening so if
i remove
this let's see what happens if
i do that so we'll go
ahead and come in here we'll
control s we'll hit play
and then we'll try it one
more time so we'll do submit
test to submit test join direct
chat test to
join direct chat test we will
send a message and that will
now work now the reason why
this didn't
work was because test had test
two blocks so since they're blocked
they can't communicate at all so
that's the reason why this happened
so it was my fault but
that was basically the reasoning now
if
we go ahead and stop this
and then we come in here
and uncomment this with control k
and then we run
this bad boy in theory we
should be able to see our
previous communications so test to join
direct chat
and you will see there's all
of our messages now i'm getting
a little bit additional messages
mostly because of my testing not
because of a problem with nakama
that's just something that i
did on my own by accident
but you can see here are
all of the messages that we
have so that's basically
how you do messages back and
forth inside of nakama
hey guys editor mitch here so
something that you should do once
you do your chat system and
you get
that guy settled when you have
this chat right here what you
should also do is subscribe to
everybody's
channels so if you have friends
or some kind of channel system
you need to subscribe to that
channel so
what i'm gonna do is come
up to my on login login
button down so when i press
my login i'm gonna go
ahead and come in here and
i'm gonna have sub to
friend channels like that now i'm
gonna scroll down and i have
a chat section in here so
you can see
we have our little group section
right here we scroll down we
have a chat room code right
here so this is
our chat section so right here
just somewhere in this general section
here we're gonna go ahead and
add
in the ability to sub to
the the friend channels right so
we'll say funk sub to friends
channels channels like that and then
what i'm gonna do is say
var results is equal to await
client dot list friends asynchronously i'm
gonna pass in my session and
that'll just bring in all of
my
friends and then from here i
can go ahead and subscribe to
their channel so for i in
results dot friends
like that and then i'm gonna
go ahead and say var type
is equal to nakama socket dot
channel type dot direct
message and then i can go
ahead and pull back my chat
that i have so i can
sub to that channel so i
can
say await socket oh i have
sub to friends sub to friend
so we'll do friend channels and
that'll fix that
little function not found so socket
dot join chat async and then
i'll go ahead and pass an
i dot user
dot id comma type comma true
comma false and that'll basically allow
me to pull those sockets back
now
this should return if i remember
correctly a channel so if we
actually hit ctrl f you can
see we have a
couple of them you can see
we have current channel right here
so what i'm going to do
is i'm going to come
here and say chat channels is
equal to a weight socket okay
and actually now that i think
about
this let's do this so we'll
do channel let's do this channel
is equal to this and then
we can come down
here and just say chat channels
bracket bracket i dot user dot
id actually i wonder if i
should do dot
user name instead that way it's
just a more common value and
i could go is equal to
channel like that
and that'll basically hook our channel
here to this object so i'll
say var and then there we
go
and chat channels doesn't exist yet
but now we have a key
value pair here that we can
use
and that's going to be really
big for us if we want
to use those channels later so
now i can go ahead
and grab chat channels i can
go up to the top var
chat channels like that and i
can actually come in
here and now i have access
to all of my chats right
here so if i have like
100 chats i could actually
pull back the channel information and
switch between them really easily using
this object
and i'll probably go through that
later but it's a way to
extend our chat to be a
bit more useful if that
makes sense so if you think
about it like this basically what
we could do is we could
add in a tab
container right here make that guy
full screen and then underneath that
tab container you can
actually switch between different tabs right
and i think what we could
do
and again this is going to
be a lot of coding and
then we could actually come in
here make this about
i don't know about this big
give or take and then we
could put that chat text underneath
here right
and this would allow us to
in theory do this and then
change the title of this to
username like so
you can see here here's the
username so what we could do
at least in theory is on
startup once we
subscribe to all of those channels
it would just fill this out
so for instance if we come
in here
and we go and subscribe to
those friend channels so if we
grab this guy bring it down
here come in here
and then basically just say tab
container or i guess it's going
to be dollar sign tab container
dot
add child and then we can
add a child of this text
box here so basically if we
box and i'm just kind of
thinking this through as i talk
to you guys so my apologies
for how confusing this
is probably going to end up
being but we could do a
text box so this is going
to be a text edit so
var
current edit is equal to text
edit dot new like that and
then we could pass in our
current edit like that
so i dot user dot user
name like so and then when
we log in you'll see that
i'm going to have a tab
right
here called username but if i
click on login and it's mad
at me so you can see
invalid index test 2
so let's take a look at
this so create chat null so
this is a null object it
needs to be a type
dictionary that's my guess at least
so we'll come in here we'll
say colon equals bracket bracket like
that and that'll make it into
an object and now if we
try it it should in theory
work there we go and
you can see we have test
2 and username right here and
that means that we would be
able to go and
fetch any messages that we want
from that person so if we
were to go in here sub
to friend chat go down
here we could actually go and
fetch that person's information if you
remember we actually do that
right here we pull back the
messages right here so what we
could do is if we list
channel messages
asynchronously we should probably pull this
out and just do
list messages like that do this
it's going to want to have
a current channel dot id so
current channel like that and then
we could come in here and
just do current edit dot text
is equal to
list messages and then we have
to pass in our current channel
so that would be our let's
see
channel right here so channel so
we'll pass to that channel that'll
pass back all of the text
in that
channel this is a coroutine so
it must be called with await
that makes sense so await
and then instead of doing this
we'll just return that value so
we'll just say var text oh
i guess
i'm gonna have to create a
text so var text is equal
to quote and then we'll need
to just do text plus
equals blah and then we can
just return our text like that
and then that will return text
right here
and then instead of doing this
when we join a chat group
we can just go dollar sign
or we could just go
in here and add in a
panel like what we're doing right
here you can see how we're
joining chat
asynchronously so we really could just
grab this section here
and just paste it right here
on this guy like so and
that'll basically solve that problem right
there
now technically this is duplicated code
and that's probably not the most
ideal situation but that's
probably okay for right now and
instead of doing our chat channel
i username what we would do
is we
would do something like current channel
and then selected group so selected
group.id the current name
would also be the selected group
id i guess we'd probably want
to come up with a better
way maybe
we could just call it current
group right instead of the name
like so and then we could
probably
come in here and list our
current channel as well and in
theory that would work so now
if we hit play
in theory we would have a
tabular messaging system now we can
hit submit and there's all of
our messages
right there and we have different
tabs that we can work with
i think if i do test
it's probably going
to get mad at me invalid
index id that makes sense because
current channel.id
current channel is null my guess
is because i'm not in a
channel yet so that would make
sense so what
we would need to do is
we need to make our tab
container handle that when the tab
gets switched which
i think there is a on
tab changed right here so we
would have to keep track of
which index our stuff
is actually located in so i
think that that's okay so we
could actually just do this on
tab changed like
so and then we could just
keep track of what index we're
on when the user changes their
tab it kind of
keeps track of that so how
i would do that is if
i go into where the tabs
are located so you can see
here and i know this is
probably a little bit confusing and
my apologies i'm just kind of
working
through it with you guys but
so you can see right here
we have a channel uh selected
group id current
channel so what we could do
is when we do our tab
container we could actually connect our
um tab changed
event and then bind the um
user id to it so we
could do is we could do
dollar sign panel tab container dot
add child like so but we
could do dot tab changed dot
connect and then we could put
on tab changed and i
guess i should do on chat
tab changed dot bind and i
can pass in the selected group
id like so
so and then we could come
in here and just say func
on chat tab changed like so
and then we could pass in
int tab comma or i guess
it would be i'm sorry i'm
trying to code in c sharp
tab colon int comma and then
we could pass in group id
or channel id like that and
that would pass in that value
like that and there
we go so what that's going
to do is allow us to
print well uh tab comma channel
id like that and that
will give us the ability to
work with this now when we
join a chat group that's how
we have to handle
that but when we do our
sub to friends channel we got
to do that as well so
that way we can do it
on
both so now if i hit
play in theory if i do
submit it's mad at me unable
to get index id on base
nil
that's because selected group is null
and that's because i'm dumb and
i chose the wrong bind it's
going
to be i dot user dot
username so we'll grab that and
paste it right here let's try
that one more time
so i'm going to come in
here i'm going to go submit
and it once again is going
to be mad a non-existent
function bind on base int that's
mad about let me see i
think i might have figured it
out what if i do
this instead and then i have
to go and find my other
bind which should be i think
i need to put it
out inside the the signal connection
so i'm connecting i'm binding this
to the signal not to
the connection function i think that's
what's doing it so let's try
that let's grab the other one
so you
see how this one connect dot
bind instead i think i need
to bind and then do that
and then i should be
able to make that work and
i believe it is index and
then channel id so let's try
that let's see what
that does there we go and
then if i click test two
it should have displayed test two
right there so
that's perfect so what that means
is that we can go current
channel is equal to
chat channels bracket bracket channel id
like that and then what that
means is now we should be
able to
since we're binding those parameters i
should be able to send a
message and it should just take
it
in theory invalid get text on
null that's fine my guess is
that's because chat text box doesn't
exist
anymore because now we're going the
opposite direction right so we're sending
a message if you
see here if you look at
the content message is test type
is zero and if you take
a look at this object
it has the channel id sender
id user id 12 and then
user name now if we take
a look at our channel objects
right here so chat channels you
can see test two is our
parameter here that's going to be
our players
information if that makes sense so
i think we could probably get
away with since this is going
to give
us test as its content and
the message is going to say
sender id is right here the
channel id is right
here i wonder if we should
pull because it has a username
right here but that's not going
to hook us
up to our channel code so
i'm curious if we need to
change how we send our data
across
so we send our data we're
sending the message and then the
current channel id okay so i
think i know
what i'm going to do here
so we're actually going to change
up a little bit how we're
doing this and
the reason why i'll show you
if we take a look at
right here we're passing in our
current channel
what i'm going to do is
i'm going to come in here
and pass in instead of just
a current channel i'm
going to pass in channel like
that colon current channel and then
i'm also going to pass in
a label
value just so i can have
the label if i need it
for whatever reason
and the label in the selected
group id will probably just be
group chat because it really
doesn't need to have anything special
and if we go to the
other one so channel chats we
go to the
other one which is right here
so this one needs to go
dot channel because we're making that
adjustment
real quick you can see right
here we're doing channel so you
can see we'll need to make
that
adjustment and then we'll just copy
this guy right here we'll paste
it like so and then i'm
going to go
ahead and pass in ctrl x
channel like that and that will
allow us to have an object
that has a label here and
then for the
actual label itself i'll just pass
this guy in like that and
then i'll just do channel.id
like that
and then if we have this
then we should be able to
use this to pull back that
channel information instead and i know
what you're thinking that
doesn't sound like it's going to
work but it's probably not going
to work so let's go ahead
and
say on tab change bind selected
group id if i do on
tab changed bind channel id
like that and then when we
produce our message here we're going
to be fetching back this on
channel
message parse the content and right
here we will have a chat
box so you can see we
have chat chat box
it'll be tab container dot get
node like that content dot and
if we take a look at
what our message is
going to be right here so
we have our right message asynchronous
we'll just say content dot id
like so
and then here we can pass
in quote id colon and fetch
back our channel information so chat
channels
like so channel id so it'd
be current channel dot id right
here
like that and that will pass
back our channel information and then
from here we could just go
dot
label
and that should allow us to
fetch back the correct node and
set the proper information right there
and in theory that would work
let's try that and see how
that works so if we hit
submit test to
test send you'll see that we
now get our test information so
this is a test message like
that
and we click go you'll see
this is a test message just
like that and that's basically how
we can make
a tabbed system as well that
should actually work for our chat
system so now that we have
a basic
chatting system that fully works let's
talk about how we can host
this out on the cloud because
the
best way to get your networking
working is by hosting it out
on the cloud that means that
you have to pay
a server to host that information
so if you want a multiplayer
game you need to actually pay
to host
that data somewhere right and that
is where digital ocean comes in
digital ocean is a
pretty great tools kit that will
allow you to host your projects
right here on their servers and
it's
relatively cheap if you take a
look at the pricing you can
see they have some pretty cheap
droplets so if you
wanted a cheap like five dollar
server to host your game that's
more or less what this is
for is it
allows you to actually host stuff
out in the cloud for relatively
cheap and i will drop a
link in the
description below that if you guys
use it it will give me
credits to be able to host
my own stuff now
i will be hosting stuff for
this tutorial here i'll be giving
you guys an ip address and
you guys can use
it for your testing but just
know that if you want to
go out into production you need
to use your own
server and something to keep in
mind you can host your own
server as well locally but it's
a lot harder
it's not as safe and people
can hack into your networks and
things like that so it's really
nice
just to use something like this
to host it for you so
that you can get your game
out there and get people
playing it and playing together so
let's go ahead and create an
account or log in whichever one
you
guys have so i'm going to
go ahead and log in real
quick so this is digital ocean
and basically the nice
thing here is this is your
dashboard right so this is the
digital ocean dashboard so here is
where you
can manage all of your resources
now you can see up here
you have your profile information and
then
you have whatever droplets you have
now in digital ocean droplets are
considered machines okay and
you can see that they have
all sorts of really cool features
here they have spaces which is
basically like
storage they have database stuff so
if you actually come in here
you can see that you can
spin up
databases right here so if you're
using nakama you can actually store
your database outside of your
droplet and allow for load balancing
they actually have a full built
-in load balancing system right here
spinning up a load balance so
you can actually choose different data
regions and pass data in between
different regions and things like that
by using their load balancers now
that being said that's way beyond
the scope of this tutorial but
that's what i'm trying to say
is digital ocean has a bunch
of stuff for you to use
that can help you get up
to the point where you can
use nakama premium and actually have
them handle
a lot of that for you
but this is a good way
to kind of get started into
that if that makes sense
so let's go ahead and talk
about how to create a droplet
so let's go up here to
the upper right
hand corner click on create click
on droplet you could do an
app platform that's technically going
to be cheaper but it's a
lot harder to get everything set
up properly so i'm just going
to do a droplet for right
now
and so we can pick what
region we want our droplet in
so right here i'm going to
choose new york new
york is the closest to me
so we'll choose that we'll come
down here and you could choose
an image
now if you have a specific
image that you're looking for go
ahead and pick it right here
in my case i'm going to
go with ubuntu but if you
want to you can also look
at the marketplace
and you could pick different stuff
so docker on ubuntu probably would
be a good image to get
or
maybe something like lamp if you're
trying to do a lamp server
or wordpress or something like that
they
have so many different droplets that
you can actually use have at
your disposal you can see
here you can also do custom
images so if you have an
image you can actually just spin
it up and have it
work now in my case i'm
going to go with os ubuntu
we're going to start from base
even though
technically docker on ubuntu probably is
a better option so i'm going
to go
so so i'm going to go
with marketplace docker on ubuntu that's
going to save us a lot
of trouble
and get it all set up
for us right so all we
have to do is get our
docker composed and then set up
our
firewall rules and we'll be good
to go so we'll go ahead
and add that guy now if
you come in here you
can see that you have a
bunch of different options for size
now it depends on what you're
trying to do
and typically what i tell people
is you want to pick the
lowest value that you can and
plus one so
for instance if you think that
your game is going to be
really small and not a lot
of people are going
to play it then something like
the 14 a month one is
probably pretty good if you're looking
for
something really cheap just for testing
if you go to regular and
you kick it over you can
see
that you can just do something
like the six dollar a month
one or even the four dollar
a month one
if you can get away with
under 10 gigabytes if you were
to come up here and choose
os ubuntu
then you could go down to
four dollars a month at 512
megabytes now once you get down
that low
this is basically only used for
testing you want to at minimum
have six dollars a month
the one gigabyte one cpu just
because it's going to allow you
to have a lot
more flexibility for your project now
since i'm doing a marketplace image
of
and now since this is going
to be a tutorial i should
probably just do ubuntu with the
four because odds are
you're not going to have the
funding to do this or something
like that so we'll try the
four we
might have to upgrade to six
we'll see and then you can
see here that you can add
a volume which will
allow you to expand your disk
space now in our case we
don't need that because it's fine
for right now
and you can see that we
have authentication so we have ssh
key and password now in my
case we're just going to do
so i'm going to set my
password right here and we'll scroll
down here and you can see
that we can do improved metrics
and monitoring for free so may
as well turn that on and
i don't think
we need to do a database
cluster here but we can look
at that in the future so
you can see here is
our host name right here which
i'll call it youtube2 tags i'm
not worried about it and then
you'll see that
it has a project right here
now this project is where it's
going to get built under so
don't worry
it'll just get built under your
account and then we'll click create
droplet now this is going to
allow us to have a droplet
once it gets built which should
be relatively quick there we go
you can see
it's in the middle of building
it and it is now completed
so it actually created your little
droplet
right here so now at this
point once we click into it
you can see here is our
youtube 2 droplet you can
see we have our graphs for
our bandwidth cpu usage stuff like
that we have access which allows
us to
adjust our access to it we
have power which allows you to
turn it off and on we
have volumes which allow
you to have block storage resize
which allows you to change how
big and strong that droplet is
so you're welcome to go in
and actually upgrade this later so
if you need that one giga
memory or
that one 10 gigabyte ssd right
that's all stuff that right here
is available and then you can
come
in here and go into networking
you can change your network ip
address your firewall stuff you can
come
in here and back it up
you can get snapshots of it
so that way if you need
this droplet to be perfect
and snapshotted for backup purposes this
is what this is for it
allows you to basically go back
to
that point in time and apply
it to your image so the
nice thing is is if you
create snapshots and your
stuff gets hacked or something like
that you can roll back to
that snapshot and stop that hack
from
happening kernel is something that you're
not going to be using but
basically it allows you to upgrade
your
linux kernel history is the history
of it destroy allows you to
destroy that droplet tags allows you
to tag it and recovery allows
you to try to recover your
droplet now that we've gone through
all of this
let's go up to our console
here and click on that you'll
see that that's going to pop
up a droplet
console now this is pretty cool
because you actually have a full
linux machine here so if you
don't know
linux now is the time to
learn because linux is very important
to know so first things first
inside
of ubuntu to install docker what
you need to do is you
need to type
sudo apt-get update and that's
going to update all of your
mirrors out there and then we
need to go in
and actually add the repository because
docker doesn't actually exist in the
repo by default
so we'll say sudo apt-get
install ca-certificates curl like that
and that's going to go ahead
and
make sure that we have curl
installed and then we'll sudo install
m 0755-d
slash etc slash apt slash key
rings and then we're going to
go in and curl out to
the docker
linux ubuntu i will actually leave
these commands in the comments below
by the way so you guys
can use it
but sudo curl
dash f s s dash l
f s capital s l https
colon slash slash download dot docker
dot com slash linux slash ubuntu
slash gpg dash o space slash
etc
slash apt slash key rings
slash docker dot asc and what
that's going to do is it's
going to actually create a docker
gpg apt repo for you so
that way you can actually go
and install docker
and then we need to allow
access to it so sudo ch
mod a plus r slash etc
slash apt slash key rings docker
asc and that basically allows us
to
execute and use that data that's
right there so basically linux is
a permission
system that is very very aggressive
so you need to make sure
that you keep that stuff under
wraps
if that makes sense so uh
linux by default does not give
you permissions to anything and
you have to give yourself permissions
to it so that's kind of
what we're doing right here
so then we can come in
here and finally fire off our
apt resources
now this command is going to
be really difficult to do so
we'll do echo slash enter and
that's going
to allow us to kind of
get a actual script going here
so we'll say quote deb space
bracket arch
that's going to be really difficult
to do so we're going to
do so we're going to do
so we're going to
docker dot docker dot com slash
linux slash ubuntu
and then we're going to put
that in dollar sign dot slash
etc
etc slash os dash release and
we're going to echo our version
code name
and we're going to pull back
the stable version like that we're
going to pass in a pipe
and we're
going to pipe that into sudo
t slash etc slash apt slash
source dot list dot d
slash docker dot list greater than
sign slash dev
slash null and i know that
that's a terrible command but basically
all this command is doing
is we're going and we're adding
in we're going deb all of
this information and we're piping all
this
info into our sudo our sources
list right here for docker and
that's basically all we're doing here
i
know that it seems really confusing
but that's basically what we're doing
here now i'm going to
double check this command because i
just spotted a mistake right here
where i did equal equal instead
of dash dash so let me
double check this command and make
sure that i'm happy with it
so we have arch
eat dollar sign d package our
print architecture we're going to sign
it by our docker asc
file and we're going to go
out to our docker linux ubuntu
and we're going to pull back
the os release
and i misspelled echo right here
you can see i made a
mistake
as always you make a million
mistakes when you do this so
echo
echo so that's e-c-h
-o and then we have our
version code name that we are
echoing into
our release we're pulling back the
stable edition we're going to pipe
that into sudo t
right here into our docker lists
and we're greater than slash dev
null and we'll run that
command e-c-o is not
found that's because i spelled echo
wrong so i guess it's good
thing
that i that it failed immediately
so e c h o and
we will try running it hopefully
this doesn't blow up
all right so we have no
such file or directory so all
right so i think i figured
it out basically there
is an issue with the command
for i think it was this
area here so don't worry just
copy what i have
in my description and just use
that and it will just work
for you so now all i
got to do is type
sudo apt dash get update like
that and that's going to update
all of our packages in our
repo and it's
going to go and fetch out
to the docker system and pull
back the actual docker packages so
you can see
right here it's actually pulling down
that information right there and then
we're going to go ahead
and install docker so sudo apt
dash get install docker dash ce
docker dash ce dash cli
container.io docker dash build dash
plug-in and finally the most
important one of the group docker
dash
compose dash compose dash plug-in
and that's the big one that's
the one that's actually going to
matter for our project for the
most part i mean the rest
of these are obviously important docker
ce
is the docker uh runtime docker
ce cli is this command line
interface the uh container is the
actual
container uh system docker build plugins
is to build your own docker
containers and then docker compose
allows you to actually compose dockers
based off of a docker composition
file if you remember before
when we talked about how to
build nakama that was one of
the big things that you need
to use so we'll
hit enter it's going to go
ahead and try to pull it
it says that it cannot locate
the docker build plugin
my guess is i spelled something
wrong here so let's see docker
build x plugin there we go
hit go
and it should go ahead and
download and install docker now we
might need to upgrade to the
next
step up to the one gigabyte
edition but we're going to see
if we can get away with
the four
dollar a month version first and
if we can't then we'll upgrade
to the six dollar a month
version and
then we can run our docker
setup here so we'll see how
this works but we'll go from
there
so it looks like it is
running if we type ps you
will see that we have a
bash and ps running
so if we type docker is
it going to pop up and
there we go so we do
have docker running so perfect
that's exactly what we want so
now from here we need to
get a docker compose file onto
here so if we
type ls right here you can
see that we have nothing going
on so what we can do
is we can type mk
dur nakama cd nakama like that
and that's going to get us
into that directory so mk dur
makes the
directory cd nakama just brings us
into the nakama directory so now
we can come in here and
basically
compose our docker file so if
we're lucky we'll be able to
just copy and paste our composition
file
so if we go out here
we go to documents and we
find our nakama instance i believe
i have a nakama
server tutorial docker compose.yaml so
if we open this guy up
you'll see this is what our
docker compose
file looks like you can see
right here this is what it
looks like so if we hit
ctrl a ctrl c
and then we go into our
web browser here and we type
nano docker dash compose dot yml
and then we right click paste
it should paste all that data
right into here so that way
we don't
actually have to set up filezilla
because one of the things that's
unfortunate is a lot of times
if you're doing godot networking you
need to actually put files up
into filezilla and into the
ftp and bring them over to
digital oceans to your digital ocean
droplet so thankfully we can just
copy
and paste this and control x
y and it'll be docker compose
dot yaml and now from here
we should be able
to just get it to run
if we're lucky so what we'll
do come in here and type
docker compose up and
you'll see it's going to go
ahead and attempt to pull and
build our docker instance right here
now we
might run out of ram it
just kind of depends but hopefully
with 512 megs of ram it's
going to be
really tight i don't know if
this is going to work we're
probably going to need a gig
but we can see
so we'll let this run and
we'll attempt to run it and
it looks like it might have
worked so what
we can do is if we
go out to our youtube 2
we grab our public ip we
go to our nakama console
and we just put in actually
i'll just make a new thing
colon and we'll put in 7351
so 7351 enter
does it do anything that's the
first question it doesn't look like
it's going to so now we
got to
figure out is it this guy's
fault it looks like this is
running so my question is server
is ready
to receive web requests so it
did spin up properly it started
the rule manager properly so that's
good
news oh you can see it
is just absolutely chugging though so
if we take a look at
our youtube docker
container let's see it looks like
our cpu utilization is pretty high
our disk io is relatively high
as well
we probably need to upgrade to
have one gig of ram but
at least it is running so
there is that the
question is so i was able
to get it to stop so
what we'll do is we'll close
it we'll go to our youtube
we'll go over to upgrade droplet
and then we'll go ahead and
just upgrade that up to
one size larger to the one
gigabyte edition so we'll do that
and then we'll click cpu ram
when it's going to ask us
to turn off our droplet so
we'll go up to power we'll
power it off because
there's nothing on here anyway so
we can just power cycle it
pretty hard there we go it's
powered down
we'll go to resize and we'll
adjust it up one size just
to let it be the proper
size that it needs to
be we're going to let that
run you'll see it's thinking about
it there we go and now
we got a
one size bigger droplet now we
can go ahead and power cycle
that bad boy back on let's
go into our
networking let's come down to our
firewall and create a firewall now
the firewall is just going to
be test
firewall and what we'll do is
we'll have an inbound of ssh
we're also going to allow
a custom one and we're going
to allow for seven three five
one so we'll copy that bad
boy
and we'll go ahead and paste
it like that and then we'll
do the same thing for seven
three five zero
as well and then we're going
to allow another one which is
going to be seven three five
one udp
and seven three five zero udp
that way we can have all
of our stuff all of our
ducks in a row and
everything kind of covered now you
can see here all outbound is
good and we should be good
to go so
we'll go ahead and hit create
firewall and that should create that
firewall onto that networking system so
we go to our droplet and
we go to youtube 2 you
should see right here under our
firewall networking
no firewalls are applied to this
droplet so i need to apply
this firewall so let's see if
we
need droplets we can choose our
droplet add droplet and then we
will search for youtube 2
and we'll go ahead and connect
it to that droplet so now
that should give our droplet the
firewall
it needs to do its job
so now we should be able
to go to console and fire
that up and then hit
cd nakama and then docker compose
up and in theory it should
run a lot faster which it
is you can see
it's actually firing off just well
the init node was successfully done
cockroach database is up so
now we're starting to get the
proper logs that we expect so
my guess is it had something
to do with
the lack of ram that we
had so let's try that we'll
refresh and there we go so
you can see now we have
nakama running out on our website
which is one nine eight nine
one nine nine eighty one one
eight
and you guys of course can
go to this and use it
so if you type admin password
you can see we have
our nakama instance just like before
and it's exactly the same so
you guys can actually use this
for your
own project providing that it doesn't
get shut down immediately because for
some reason it gets
shut down sometimes and that causes
some issues but that's how easy
it is to get this to
fire off
now and in order to detach
let's hit ctrl c we'll stop
our docker connection right here
and you'll see in a second
it's going to gracefully stop so
we'll give it a minute to
kill everything
we'll hit docker compose up dash
dash detach what that should do
is it should allow us to
fire this
up and be detached and there
you go so now we're detached
so if we hit ps you'll
see that it's not
running but if i come in
here and i refresh you can
see that nakama is running if
i close this and i
refresh you will see that nakama
is running even though we are
no longer connected to our docker
instance so that's how we can
actually get that to run without
needing to keep that window open
because if you were to have
closed the window when nakama's running
like that previously without
running the dash dash detach then
it would have closed that docker
instance and then your whole
project would have been gone so
that's basically how that works so
now if we head out to
godot here
we can come up to here
and change this value to our
nakama instance so if we come
in here
you can see here is our
nakama instance right here so we'll
copy that we'll paste this like
so and then
if we hit play you will
see that we can now submit
and log in so you'll see
that i have logged in so
now
if i take a look at
my nakama instance out here on
the web if i refresh you'll
see that when we go
to accounts i have an account
right here just like as if
i was playing the game locally
so this is how
that works and you can come
in here and go test two
and you'll see that if i
click name of match test
join create test join create we
just joined our match and then
if the host says start game
and then
start game you'll see that we
both started our game now something
here is broken but i don't
think that
that's a nakama issue i think
that's just a my code issue
so you can see that we
are transferring the
data as expected here in our
nakama instance so we do have
the presences as expected but i
feel like
something here is wonky a little
bit and i think that's because
i'm not in the right scene
to do
this i think i have to
go to game manager.tscn if
you remember this is our game
manager here so
let's refresh this guy let's try
rerunning it so we'll hit test
test to test join create test
join
create start game start game and
you can see that our game
is now running not locally anymore
so this
will work with your friends across
the web and what i'm going
to do is i'm going to
go get one of my
friends and i will have him
pull my code and then he
will also do this and i'll
show you guys that
it does work out on the
internet so i will be right
back
okay and then hit start game
and as you guys can see
right here my friend and i
are both working
together and playing the same game
at the same time over the
internet using our nakama instance now
you can see here that there
is a little bit of lag
and i think the reason for
that is because we're
flooding the actual nakama instance because
it has a bunch of data
that it's passing through so we
should probably figure out a better
way to optimize this but at
least we have it working for
now
so at this point we've gone
through quite a few things we
talked about groups we talked about
chatting and we talked about how
to get our stuff to work
out on the internet for our
project and allow us to
work on multiple networks with each
other so if you like this
video go and hit that like
button hey
you know if you dislike this
video go and hit that dislike
button because i am here to
make content for
you guys this video was a
viewer suggested video so if you
have any suggestions please leave them
in the
comments below or jump on my
github link is in the description
and put in a service ticket
and i'll be
more than happy to add it
to my list of tutorials for
the future and hey if you
have any questions or
comments about this video go ahead
and leave them in the comments
below or jump on my discord
link is in the
description and i'll be more than
happy to help you out but
that is all i have for
you guys today
so thank you so much again
for watching and i will see
you all next time thanks
so
Thank you.