Hey guys, this is Mitch with Fineboy CGI and today we're going to continue our Nakama tutorial
series where I take you from zero to understanding all the fundamentals of Nakama and in this video
we're going to talk about how to do groups so that's going to allow you to add users to like a guild
or like a group setting then we're going to talk about doing chats and chatting between each other
so sending messages to each other and finally due to popular requests I'm going to talk about how to
host your Nakama instance out on the internet so that you can play games with your friends or of
course you can release your game out to make it into a multiplayer game so that's what I have in
store for you guys today so let's go ahead and get started all right so this tutorial assumes that
you already completed the previous tutorial where we actually integrated Nakama for the most part so
this one's going to be going over more of the features and things like that that are available to
you so let's go ahead and get started with that and the first thing we're going to talk about is
creating groups so groups are basically like a guild or a team of people that want to play with each
other multiple times not necessarily as a party but as an actual group so after the game is ended
and everything is done you still have access to that group of people so the first thing that I'm
going to do is I'm going to come in here and I'm going to hide our friends section because we're
actually running out of space here and I really should name all of these but that's probably going
to break all of my code so we'll go ahead and just hide that panel go ahead and add in a new panel
like so I'm going to go over here make it about this big give or take I'm going to right click add a
child node we'll add in a label like that we're going to make it about this big and we'll have a
name parameter there we'll go ahead and duplicate it and say description
and then we'll come in here right click add in a child node and we'll add in a line edit like so and
we'll make it about this big give or take we'll control duplicate that and we'll make it about this
big I mean technically the description should be a little bit longer but that's okay we'll make it
work for what we're gonna do so that's fine and I'll just kind of organize this properly then we'll
add in a button and this button is going to allow us to create a group now I'm going to need
multiple buttons but for right now we'll just do one I think so we'll go ahead and say create group
like so and I'll probably need to make this panel larger to be honest I'm running out of space here
so we'll go ahead and just make this a touch bit bigger like so now when we want to create a group
all we have to do is if we grab this button name it create group like so we'll go into our node
button down and we'll hook that to our control node just like that now you'll see when I hook it to
the control node it should create a
create group button down function it looks like I already did this in a previous section so I'm
going to go ahead and get rid of that that's my fault that caught me off guard real quick but to
create a group all we have to do is say client dot create group async and then we can pass in our
session like so and then we have to pass in a name now the name is whatever the name is that we put
as our line edit now if we take a look we have our name right here so we'll say group name and then
group description like so and then we'll go back to our script and we'll do dollar sign group name
comma or dot text comma dollar sign group description dot text and then you'll see that they have
the option for an avatar url now you don't have to supply one but you can and that's really cool
because it basically would allow you to have some kind of url for an image that you could load for
their group so I'm going to put that as empty comma and then you'll see that they have a language so
we'll say their main language is en it doesn't really matter necessarily but it is a thing that
exists and actually I need to I'm messing up my little things here we'll put an empty url we'll put
a en for the avatar title and then you can choose whether or not it's an open or if it's not so an
open means if it's a public group so if people can actually see it and index it for other people so
if you say false then it's a private group so if you don't want it to be listable which we'll
discuss listing in a little bit but it allows you to basically say is this a listable group so I'm
going to say true because it makes sense to have a listable group and then you can have a max number
of members now once this is set you cannot change it so make sure you set it to a value that you
want so if a guild can only have 64 members then you set it to 64 if it's 100 members then you can
set it to 100 so in my case I'm going to say 32 just because 32 is just a good round number now
after that there is nothing else that we can do so we'll go ahead and just say 32 now typically this
also returns a group api so you could say var group is equal to await client asynchronous and then
we can just go ahead and print out that group now you don't have to do this but it is a way to get a
hold of that object if that makes sense so if you needed to go ahead and make your group you know
visible or not visible or something like that you could do that right here so now if we go ahead and
make sure that our nakama instance is running so if I take a look at my containers you can see it is
actually running so there we go we'll go ahead and hit play and then we're going to go ahead and
submit we're going to connect to our game we're going to call our group test group description this
is our test group and we'll click create now you'll see that we have a error group name must be set
so I must have messed up on my group name so let's take a look panel five group name oh I made a
mistake because this is the original panel I did some recording earlier that um I didn't keep it but
I never actually removed that panel so we'll change this to panel six and then we'll go from there
so we'll refresh this and try this one more time that's my fault so we'll submit test group this is
a test group create group and you'll see that we get a success right there so now I'm going to
navigate to one two seven nakama console right here so we'll go to our one two seven seven three
five one and then we will connect into our nakama group if we go to groups you will see there is our
test group and you can see this is what we have if we take a look at our members you can see that
there is a super admin so what in the world is a super admin well a super admin is a person that has
full control over that group so this person jj rb v w e x k i is a super admin of that group so what
that means is that they have the ability to delete that group and when you are a super admin you
have full control over that group there are four different membership states there's super admin
which means that you are basically god you can do whatever you want to this group you can delete
people you can do whatever you want and basically you can delete the group and that's a big thing
admin which allows you to update your group and allow you to accept kick promote delete ban or
promote members and then they have members which allows you to actually have a regular group member
they don't have the ability to do anything they cannot accept join requests stuff like that and then
they have the join request mode which basically is when a user wants to join they need to be
accepted so you have to say yes i will accept you as a part of a group and that's how you know the
different states if that makes sense so if we go to our user management we look for the jj r person
if we go into accounts i have a bunch of usernames here because i've been doing a lot of testing on
my end but if i look for jj rb
jj rb well that person let me see jj i have 71 accounts so you can see i have a bunch of accounts
because i've been doing a lot of testing on my end for my own stuff and nakama is being difficult so
let me refresh jj rb well
apparently jj doesn't exist within my vast number of people so i'm not sure why it did that but
that's okay there's probably a master account that it's using
actually it's right here jj rb right here so i'm not sure why it used this specific one unless i
logged in and created it with device authentication which is possible but that's okay we'll figure
that out in a minute but that's basically how we create a group now you can see we also printed out
a group as well so you can see here we have our creator id which is right here the creator id is db
so this is the creator id so our creator is jj so we must have logged in with device authentication
which means i probably didn't reset my client authentication stuff so let me take a look at that
real quick my apologies i may not have reset some of my code so that it worked properly did user
authentication instead of our um device authentication so my guess is that's probably what it is so
if i go to log in yeah right here i'm doing a unique device id right here and i'm logging in with
that socket connection so that's what's going on here so what i'm gonna do is i'm gonna control k to
comment that out and i'm going to go ahead and log in with my username so now i'm gonna go in here
and i'll reset this because it's going to be kind of difficult to have a group that uh exists that's
not tied to an actual user so i'll go ahead and do that i'll refresh and then we're going to
recreate that group just because it makes more sense so i'll say test group description this is a
test group and we'll go ahead and create that group now if we take a look at our nakama console you
will see that because this was created by test that person is the super admin so whoever creates the
group gets super admin status now in order to add users it's actually relatively easy all we need to
do is go in to our project here and you can see right here we have the ability to create a group so
we'll just go ahead and duplicate this and we will come down here and we'll right click disconnect
we're going to go in here connect and say on add user we'll say add underscore user underscore to
group like so button down and we'll go ahead and connect that and i'm going to rename this to add
user to group so with this for us to be able to add users to group it's actually really easy all we
need to do is pass in the group id that we want to add ourselves to so unfortunately we have to
actually pull that user identifier so if you look at this you can see inside of our groups we have a
user id right here this is the identifier that we need to give them to be able to add ourselves to
that group so if we come in here and copy this we can come down here go back into godot and then
basically just say await client dot join group async and then do session comma and then we'll just
pass in that group identifier now if we come in here and we hit play you'll see in a second we'll go
ahead and log in as test 2 we will type test i mean it doesn't really matter and you can see the
text here is wrong but that's okay we'll click create group which is technically add group and
you'll see that we get an authorization token right here we got a 404 group not found so my guess is
that i have the wrong identifier go to group group id i do so we'll go ahead and copy that and we'll
go back here we'll change this guy like so paste control s and the nice thing about godot is that if
you uh just change the code in here you can just click that and you can see that it should work and
that's because godot is a non-compiled language so you can actually get away with changing it and re
-executing the code so now if you look at members you can see test 2 is now a member now you might
be wondering okay so anybody can join my group yes anyone can join your group as long as long as it
is public if it's not public then you have to be approved so that's where the difference comes in so
if i come in here i remove test 2 i go to details and i change this to not open and i save it now if
i go ahead and i hit create group or i guess connect to the group you can see that there is a join
request and that means that i have to approve that before they can be a part of the group so the
question is how do you actually accept that join request well to accept a join request what you need
to do is you need to come in here and actually code out a small subroutine first thing first i'm
going to come in here and change this to add join group like that and then i'm going to go ahead and
duplicate this guy drag this guy down like so and i'm going to say add user to group like so and if
i just hit enter that will help with formatting this button a little bit better now we'll pull this
name parameter to allow ourselves to actually you know go from there and this should probably be
called join group so it'll be fine i guess for now but it's just something i'm not a huge fan of but
that's okay so we'll go ahead and click node right click disconnect connect and then we'll go ahead
and create that little function there now to accept a join request you need to be able to list your
groups or your users inside of that group and that's really easy to do we can basically just say var
users is equal to await client dot list group users async like that we can pass in our session token
and then we can pass in our group id now our group id is right here so we'll go ahead and copy that
and paste it and then we'll hit comma and then we can actually have a different state so this is
where that one two i guess zero one two and three is useful if you wanted to you could list everyone
that is a member of the group everyone that's waiting to join the group and anybody that's a super
user or an admin just by changing this from zero through three in our case we're going to be
grabbing all the people that are awaiting for their joins you can see the state is three so we will
go ahead and do that and then all we need to do is come in here and say for user in users dot group
underscore users colon var you is equal to user dot user and then await client dot add group users
async pass in our session right here comma what our group id is which in this case is this guy right
here so we'll pass that guy in comma and then we'll pass in you and now we'll go ahead and add that
person so now if i refresh and i go add user to group so if i submit i log in as the test user and i
click add user to group you'll see that we got an error here unable to convert uh argument three to
pack string array so u is not correct so let's take a look at what u is real quick i don't think
there's really an easy way to handle this without going bracket bracket and then passing in dot id
and then just using their id i think that that will work it's not the most ideal way to fix it but
if i log in i hit add user you should see a nice request here and then we'll go ahead and refresh
this and you can see that they are now a member and that's because when we built the group we made
it a private group now you might be wondering is there a way for us to make a group private or
public through code right so that way it doesn't have to happen immediately on start and the answer
to your question is yes you can actually do that pretty easily all you need to do is come in here go
in here let's grab this make it slightly bigger again the group section is going to be very large
for this so we'll add in a check box here like so and we'll call it open like that and then we're
going to add in a toggle switch so i'll just put this right here for right now we'll call it open
that's fine and then we'll go ahead and say on button down or i guess on toggled we'll toggle this
on our control node and basically when it gets toggled it'll show you yes or no so we'll say await
client dot update group asynchronously we'll pass in our session token comma our group id which is
this guy right here and we'll talk about how to get that group id uh through code in a second comma
and then the name of the group which i'll pass in null because i don't want to change it and then
we'll pass in toggled underscore on like that and you'll see that if i come in here and i submit and
then i click open you'll see if we refresh our nakama instance here so we'll refresh this page
you'll see it's not open if we close it it should hopefully do it real quick maybe not let's take a
look let's do a break point here i could just be crazy so if i come in here toggle response code 400
specify at least one field to update okay let's see if we come in here comma p name p description
variant null so null comma description null comma avatar null comma language tag en comma now this
is how you update any of your parameters by the way so now we have our p open i think that's why
toggled on and you can see here we have null null null so this is the username right the name of the
group the description of the group and the whether or not it's open or not so you can actually
really play around here and update any of these values so now if we hit play in theory it should
just work so we'll come in here submit we do that and then we take a look at our group here we
refresh you'll see that open is now on if we set it to off and we refresh you'll see that it is now
closed so that's how you can open and close and that's really how you can update any of these values
so if i came in here if i come back to godot here and i grab my description i believe that's name
description avatar url so if i name this the strong gamers and then i change the description to we
are the strong gamers exclamation point if i come in here and i hit this little toggle here well our
session got dc'd so let me refresh this guy real quick let me re-log in and then i'll change it so
now it's going to be open and the titles and everything has been changed strong gamers we are the
strong gamers so that's how you can update those values now again typically you wouldn't use a
toggle switch to do this i'm just showing you guys how to do that so i can show you the open and
close really quickly you can see now it's closed so that's how you can update that group visibility
that's how you can update the group values information values for your group now something else
that's pretty big and pretty important to know is how to actually list groups so nakama groups are a
resource like anything else right so you can actually list them and index them and pull back
information using them so what does that mean well that means that you can use what's called list
groups asynchronously to actually list out your groups so if i come in here i can show you guys how
that works so i'm going to right click add in a panel like so i'll drag this guy over here like this
and i will make an h box container or i guess it'd be a v box container like so and i'll make that
full rect so that way it maximizes the full screen now granted that being said we only have one
group right now so we kind of need to make multiple groups for us to be able to see them all but we
can at least show how that works so if we come in here i grab this add user to group button i
duplicate it bring it down here and i type list groups like so and then i'm going to grab this
description duplicate it pull it down here and this is going to be group
query like so i'll change this to list groups and i'll change this to group query now what we can do
is hit ctrl s we can go into scripting we can grab our list group go to node right click disconnect
right click connect and connect it now what we could do when we want to list our groups is we can
set up a limit so we can say var limit is equal to let's say 10 now we don't have 10 groups to list
but we'll use that as a default value then we'll say var result is equal to await client dot list
groups async now you'll need to pass in your session just like usual and then you'll need to pass in
some kind of name that you're trying to search up now this is a variant so of course you can you
know get back whatever you're looking for so in my case i'm going to hit dollar sign group query dot
text and that'll let me have that limit and then we'll pass in our limit which by the way does
default to 10. now they have a cursor value and that cursor value allows you to say i want the next
10. so think of it kind of like this when you do your query you're going to pull back the first 10
but what happens if the person doesn't see the group that they want on the first 10. well that's
where the cursor value comes in so you can hit zero make that cursor value of zero language tag will
allow you to pick a language in my case i'm going to do en and again you don't have to do that but
it's going to filter out any groups that are not english you can see right here language en so
that's going to allow you to have that limiting factor right because if they're spanish you don't
want to necessarily show them up if they're looking for an english group if they speak english not
spanish it's going to be a problem and then you can look up members which allows you to pick members
i'm going to pass in null for that and then you could choose whether or not it's an open group or
not so a lot of times when you're doing groups you might want to check to see if it's a public group
not a private group because sometimes if you have a group like a guild and you don't want people to
see your guild you probably should make sure that that is false or true depending on your use case
so i'll make it true and that's pretty much everything that you need to know here now with this we
should be relatively good to go so now we could basically we'll have our results we can say for
group in result dot groups like that and then we can basically come in and print out our groups so
you can see that we can go print group dot name like that and from here we should be relatively good
to go so now we can hit play we can log in as test we can come in here and say i believe our group
name is strong gamers so we can say strong and list groups and it should come back well it's not
happy so that's not a good thing our p cursor query parameters strong that's fine nakama serialize
escape and not convert argument one from int to string
i wonder if it's mad because our cursor is an int i think there's an issue here with how they have
their stuff set up so what if we come back here and we do null instead so if we come in here null
just to see if that fixes the problem so we'll come in here we'll type strong and it's still mad oh
that's because i didn't log in so that's fair that's understandable so we'll log in we will say
strong list groups and you can see that we get a 400 the error name filter cannot be combined with
any other filter so it looks like according to nakama's documentation you can combine them but i
guess you can't inside of here so let's try that and see if that fixes it because according to our
documentation you can do this but i guess we can't so let's try that
so we'll hit list groups and you will see that we get an authorization bearing right here i don't
know if that came back with really anything so let me see what happens if i list groups let's see
what our result comes back with after i drop a breakpoint here and it did it came back with nothing
so nakama is not doing what i want it to do because of course it's not welcome to programming let's
see what happens if i do capital s it's probably capital
case sensitive so we'll come in here and we'll take a look at our results still got nothing back so
we'll continue through what happens if i do a percent sign and see if that gives us something back
now because it might be that it needs to be a query of some description so we can check that out
real quick yep it needs to be a query so you can see it pulled back the one that we're looking for
so it pulled back our group so when you do a text just be aware of that you're going to need to make
it into an actual query instead so you need to add that percent sign at the end so that's just
something to keep in mind now you'll see when i hit play it's going to print out strong gamers right
there so that's basically how you can list and filter your groups so that allows us to see those
groups and hunt down their identifier because if you look you can see when i list the groups you can
see when i come in here and i take a look at my results here the group i come back with has their
identifier right here so if you know where their um if you know their name you can pull back their
id so that's how we would populate all these other values right here is by listing it and then
pulling back that group information now since we can pull this information that means that we can
actually come in here and use that info on our panels and things like that so what we could do is we
could come in here and list out their information and populate it in a vbox container so we could do
is we could go var vbox is equal to vbox container dot new like that and then if i need if i do this
correctly equals vbox container dot new and then we could come in here and do the same thing but for
labels so we can say label so var name label is equal to a label dot new like that and then name
label dot text is equal to if we take a look at this right here we can go name so it would be group
dot dot let's take a look at this
what is result dot groups let's see results dot groups so it's going to come back with this so then
it would be dot name like that and then we could say vbox
dot add child and then we could add our name label as a part of that child and then we can come in
here and say dollar sign vbox and we can find out which panel is ours which arguably we should come
up with a better naming convention here but that's fine dot add child and we could add in our vbox
right here like that and that would allow us to effectively add it as a child for our project and
then if we refresh this in theory providing that this is going to work and i don't know if it's
going to work this is kind of me coding this a little bit off the cuff we can hit list groups and
you can see that we now have strong gamers there so that's something that we can actually do and
pull back their information so that could be really useful for us to set up for like a selection
system or something like that and speaking of that what we could do is we could come in here and say
var hbox is equal to hbox container dot new like so and then we can do hbox dot let's see if we
bring this down here instead of doing vbox dot add we can do hbox and then we could add our vbox
dot add child h box like so and then what that means is that we could add in a button and i know
this is kind of weird because i'm actually coding a component instead of doing it the other way but
one of the big things that people have asked me is if you could actually do it this way and i want
to cover that and show you guys yeah you can actually build interface elements inside of code and
then actually have it exist so that's kind of what i'm showing here so if we come in here and say h
var button is equal to button dot new like so then we can come in here and do button dot text is
equal to select group like that and then we can come in here and say h box dot add child button like
that and then we can add that h box and that should allow us to have all of that information that we
were looking for before right here so if we hit submit list groups you can see we have a button
right here so now we can basically connect its on button click right here so you can say button dot
button down like that dot dot connect and then we could just say and here we could call out a
function so if i come in here and say funk on group select button down and i can pass in the group
like that and i could come in here and do dot connect and we could do what's called binding and
binding is actually really cool so we can say on group select button like that dot bind and then i
can bind to parameters so i can actually come in here and bind group and now if we come in here and
we print out that group you'll see providing that we did this correctly and i know that this is like
way beyond what the actual tutorial is but i think that this is pretty cool so i figured i would
show it off if we do this we can come in here and list our groups and then select a group and you'll
see that it passes in that information right there it binds the parameters so you could actually
come in here and set a selected group parameter right here and there you go it would actually work
so what we could do is we could come in here and say all the way up here set our
var var selected group and then we could come down here and just say selected group is equal to
group like that and then we could come in here and do i believe it's group dot id so you could come
in here and go selected
group dot id like that copy this bad boy go like this paste and paste and paste and then you would
be able to effectively update the values in there without needing to actually have that data so if i
come in here i list my groups well first i need to actually hook up my session really quick so if i
submit that there we go i list my groups i select it now i have that selected i can come in here and
do a open and you will see that if i come in here and i refresh this you'll see that that worked and
that's because we bound that parameter right here well if i could find it right here to actually
work so that's a way that we can go about making a group selection system relatively simple and
that's how we can actually list our groups as well so i know that that's kind of a complicated way
to show it but i figured that it was an interesting way to approach it and i figured you guys would
appreciate that so now the question is what if we want to promote a user or maybe demote a user or
kick or ban a user from our group well in order to do that first we need to actually get the user id
of that person so you can see here this person is a member and we want to get that user id back so
if we come back to godot here and we go ahead and come down here we need to basically get a user
name go and fetch their id and then basically promote or demote that person so what i'm going to do
is i'm going to right click my panel i'm going to add in a line edit like so i'm going to drag this
guy down here we'll go like this make it about i don't know about that big we'll come in here we'll
say user user to manage we'll say and then we'll come in here and hopefully we won't run out of
space if we do we'll figure something out but let's right click add in a child node let's add in a
button we'll add in a button for promoting right here like so and if i think about it for a second
with groups we need to promote demote kick and ban somebody and then also leave that group so we'll
need to figure out a way to give ourselves a little bit more space here because i'm running out so
maybe i can drag this guy up butt it up a little bit closer drag this guy down give ourselves a
little bit more space but we can promote duplicate kick
demote and then i believe we would need to ban somebody and then finally the last interaction that
we need to do is to actually come in here and leave so we could just come over ah goodness we're
running out of space here we have so much functionality here it's actually hard to make the space so
we'll drag this guy down a tiny bit maybe give ourselves a bit more space over here drag this guy
over like so there we go and we can change this one to leave group like that now when we want to
promote a user let's change the name of this to promote user kick user demote user and ban user like
that and then leave free so i'm going to go ahead and grab promote user and i'm going to change my
line edit to user to manage and then i'll click on promote user we're going to go ahead and connect
that to our nakama controller here we'll come down here and we'll basically go ahead and promote a
user so first things first we need to actually get our user account now unfortunately you need to
actually go and fetch that user account so first we'll say var user is is type nakama api dot api
users is equal to await client dot get users async and then we can come in here and go session so we
could pass in that session and then we need to pass in ids so when you do this you can pass in ids
or usernames in our case we're going to pass in a username but you can pass in their actual um id as
well so i'm just going to pass in a blank and then for the username i'll just pass in a single
parameter and that's going to be dollar sign user to manage dot text comma and you'll see that they
also have a facebook id in this case we'll pass in null we don't really have a facebook id to manage
a user but they do separate that out and i'm not really sure why they do that but that's a thing so
it's just something to keep in mind now what we can do is say for you in users dot users and that's
a really bad way so we'll say result and then we'll just do result dot users that's going to be a
little bit better than what we're doing right now now once we do this we have the actual user
information so that's how you pull back that user's information so you can actually just do you dot
id and that will be their identification right that'll be their actual information so what we can do
is we can come in here and promote that user so we'll come in here and say await client dot promote
user and group async you can pass in our session token and then we can pass in our group id so in
our case that's going to be our selected group dot id comma and i believe it's selected group dot id
let me double check really quick because sometimes i forget things it is and then we have to pass in
a user identifier so that's going to be u dot id like that and now if we go ahead and hit play
you'll see in a second that if i connect to this and then i list my groups i select my group and
then i type in test two and i click promote well we have an error so the error is cannot convert
argument three from string to a packed array and that's because this can be a group of users it's
not actually just one group it's actually multiple people so we can go ahead and do that and then
try it again so it's because we need we can actually have multiples of somebody so we'll go like
that we'll submit we'll list our groups select group test two we'll promote that person you'll see
that that looks like that was successful we'll head back to our nakama console we'll refresh and you
will see that this person is now an admin so that's huge because it's going to allow us to be able
to create admins and now if we click it a second time you'll see if we refresh they are now a super
admin that means that they can delete this group if they want to now the question might be okay so i
can promote users how do i demote them right well if we come in here we go in right here we go into
demote user button down let's connect that real quick we come in here and basically copy and paste
this code so we'll just copy this guy paste it and instead of promote we can just pass in demote
easy enough and same thing for kick user right we could just kind of bring that in and let's do ban
user as well right so we'll just bring that in as well if we copy this guy we can copy paste and
paste because they're all the exact same functionality so we can come in here and say kick group
users and then ban group users and now if i refresh this you'll see if i submit list groups select
my group test two i go demote you'll see that that worked if we come over here we refresh our users
right here you'll see that they are now an admin and then i can go ahead and ban a user and you'll
see non-existent function ban groups that's probably my fault group users async and it looks like
you actually can't ban a user so we'll remove that that's my fault i um was reading the
documentation earlier but it looks like it got removed so you're not actually able to ban a user
anymore from a group so we'll come in here we'll go ahead and type submit list our groups select our
group we'll go to test two we'll go ahead and demote the user so you'll see if we refresh they are
an admin if we come in here we can go ahead and kick them and then if we refresh you will see they
have been removed from that group and that's basically how you can actually manage your users in
here and you can also delete a group and leave a group so if we want to leave a group we can come in
here and go into our stuff here we can click on leave group button down on leave button down we'll
connect that and to leave a group it's actually relatively simple all we need to do is type
await client dot leave group async we'll pass in our session and then we'll pass in our group id
which is going to be our selected group id now this will allow us to leave our group but the problem
is that if i leave my group i will actually um not have any more users in that group so what i'll do
is i'll log in as test two i will come in here and pass in my group name if i remember correctly
it's if we list groups we can select the group join group and then you should see that we will join
that group so you'll see as a member we can refresh and there we go we're in that group and now we
can come in here and say leave group and then if we refresh we have left that group right there and
now we can actually uh safely delete our group right because we now have shown that that section
works that's how you leave a group it's actually really easy you just do leave group asynchronously
so now what happens if you want to delete a group well we're going to need an additional button for
that so let's duplicate our leave group we'll just pull it down here i guess we're kind of running
out of space here so i'll just put it right here i'll move open over we'll grab leave group and
we'll put delete group now in order to delete a group we'll disconnect this connect in order to
delete a group it's actually really simple as well so when you delete a group all you need to do is
type client await client dot delete group async and then you can pass in the session and the
selected group dot id and that's literally all you need to do so now if i refresh my screen here i
log in as test the super admin and then we'll log in as test we'll come in here we'll log in as test
two we'll submit we will go ahead and hit list groups we'll select that group we're going to join
that group really quick and remember because this is an open group that person should be able to
just join there
we go so the person has joined and now you'll see if i go in as test two right here and i go ahead
and i click delete group which this is leave group but it's delete group in um our code you'll see
request has returned spot response 400 group not found or you are not allowed to delete and the
reason why is because that person does not have the capability to delete this group you can see it's
still here however if i come in here as test or as my super admin and i log in and i click list
groups i select my group and then i click delete group you'll see if we go back to groups it has now
been removed and that's basically everything that you need to know about groups
now when it comes to chats which is actually a whole feature inside of nakama you can actually build
chat rooms right inside of nakama so when it comes to chats how do we actually get that to work well
first things first we are majorly out of space so i am going to hide the group section as you can
see we have all sorts of different areas here where we can actually do our nakama work here so i'm
actually just going to come in here and just start hiding a lot of this because we're running out of
space here so i'll hide this panel and this panel and there we go so when it comes to chats we have
three different types of chats and we'll talk about all three of them and how to send messages and
stuff like that but we have three different chat types we have dynamic rooms group chats and direct
chats okay and we'll talk about the group chats when we get there but one of the big ones that a lot
of people like is the dynamic rooms the dynamic rooms is basically a random room that gets created
for temporary for a temporary for a temporary time span and it only stays open as long as there are
people in that chat room so the nice thing about it is let's say you have a match or something like
that you could put people in that temporary room and then have people communicate and then once the
match is over that room just gets dissolved over time whereas something like a group chat that stays
for as long as the group exists and then they also have direct chats which is basically one-on-one
communications between people which persist once again forever so in order to do dynamic rooms let's
first right click add a child node let's add in a panel here and let's make it about this big now
we're going to have to build a whole chat system so this will take a little bit of time so what i'm
going to do is i'm going to right click add a child node i'm going to add in a button i'm going to
right click add a child node add in a line edit right here we're going to make the line edit about
yay big give or take if my mouse will let me we'll do that we'll add in a button again providing
that i can click on this there we go we'll make it about yay big and for our line edit we'll just
say chat name like that and then we'll come in here and say join chat now you could automate this as
soon as a person goes into a match you could actually go set up the uh room name and automatically
have them join but in this case we're going to manually do it that way you guys get the experience
of how it works so what we'll do is we'll change this to join chat room like that and then the line
at it will be chat name like that and then i'm going to come in here go over here button down and
then i will hit connect now when we want to join a chat room all we have to do is come up with a
room name if it's persistent if it's hidden and if it is a room type so i will show you all of those
things so first things first let's go var channel is equal to await socket dot join chat
asynchronously now what this is going to do is we're going to have a target now that target is what
the name of that chat room is going to be in this case we'll just say actually we already have a
title right here right so dollar sign chat name dot text comma and then you'll see that we have an
int type so what does that actually take what is the type well the type is a nakaba socket chat type
or a channel type so we'll say var type is equal to nakaba socket dot channel type dot and you'll
see that we have different types direct direct message group and room and each one has a different
use so thankfully the code is basically the same but what matters is if it is going to be a room if
it's going to be a group or if it's going to be a direct message in our case it's going to be a room
so i'm going to come in here and say type comma and then if it's persistent so in our case we don't
want it to be persistent so false comma and then if it's hidden it will say false we wanted to make
it a public messaging chat so people can actually go in and message each other and not have to
authenticate or be added to that chat and then what i'm going to do is i'm going to print that chat
information so print channel
like that now this will basically print out our chats information so if i refresh this and i run
this if i join and i say test and i join you'll see that we now have a chat that is right here you
can see it has the id one it has id here it says there's a user test user id is this session id is
this so we can get all the people that are inside of that chat right there now if somebody else
joins test to submit and then they go test and they join you can see here that we also joined
channel id 2 user presence session this status user test so we just got back that user's account
information right so we got test and test 2 in this chat with each other and that's basically what
these guys are saying here now in order to send a message you need to actually be able to receive
that message right so let's go to our script here and let's scroll all the way up to the top and the
reason why i'm scrolling all the way up to the top is because we need to subscribe when we create
our socket to the ability to actually get messages so what we need to do is go find where our socket
gets created
which is right here so we'll come in here we'll say socket dot and providing that godot wants to be
nice to me it will auto complete please maybe not well we'll hit dot received underscore
channel underscore message dot connect like that and then we'll pass in a callable so what this is
going to be is it's just going to be a very basic function that prints out that message currently at
least so we'll say funk underscore on underscore channel on
channel
message like that and we'll pass in a message now this could be a type if you want it to be which is
going to be a nakama api dot api
channel message like that and then we can just go ahead and print that message and there we go now
we're going to connect that message so we'll just pass on channel message like that and that will
actually pass that to this guy right here and we'll go ahead and send out that signal now when we do
our message when we want to send a message we need to actually create a panel for that so let's come
in here let's right click our panel and add in another panel like so i'm going to drag this guy over
here make it about this big give or take it we're going to create a very basic message block system
so it's going to be pretty ugly my apologies but i want to try to get this to work as quickly as
humanly possible so what i'm going to do is i'm going to put in a line edit like so i'm going to
make this go on the bottom stretched across i'm going to pull this back right click add a child node
we'll add in a button i'm going to snap that guy right in the bottom right where we'll make it about
if i can click on it about yay big we'll put a send or maybe just like an arrow like that i think
that'll work we'll put a placeholder chat text here we'll type this as chat text we'll make the
panel title chat and then we'll make the button submit chat like that i'm going to go ahead and
right click add any child node and i'm going to add in a
i am brain farting on what it is it is a text edit like that we'll make it full screen so full
wrecked and we'll make it about yay big that'll go ahead and make it so that it's kind of scalable
and you know easy to use now inside of here i'll scroll down and i will do auto wrap that's fine so
that means that if i put in a bunch of text here it's going to auto wrap so you can see if i do wrap
mode boundary it will go ahead and wrap that and then i will turn on scroll as well so if this
continues so we'll ctrl c ctrl v we'll paste it you'll see that it's going to scroll we also want to
we'll want to shut off editable and i think that will work because i think this is placeholder text
so if i come in here and we paste this text in this will allow us to scroll i'm curious if we can
make it follow the uh actual scrolling but i don't think we can i know there's a way to do it it's
been a while since i've done it but i think i'll just go ahead and skip that part but there is a way
to make it so it automatically scrolls to the bottom but that's okay right now so this is basically
what our chat setup is going to be it's going to be relatively simple but it's going to be something
that we can at least use now i'm going to grab my submit chat button i'm going to go to node button
down i'm going to connect that to my submit chat button now when we want to do a message right we
want to send a message we can come in here and say var await
socket dot write chat message asynchronous now this is going to require a id so we have to actually
have some kind of chat name in this case i'm just going to go ahead and grab this guy right here
copy it and paste it it's not the most ideal situation because once you're connected to that channel
you should probably just be connected to that channel right instead of passing in this value here
but we can basically throw a value up at the top and basically just save it across different
functions and that would solve this problem but for right now we'll go ahead and do this and then we
need to pass in our message content so what we can do is do dollar sign chat text dot text like that
now i think we should probably change this to text edit instead just do chat text box that way we
actually have that value now if we hit play and we go ahead and hit play if we come in here we both
submit join test test number two submit join test if we send a text test test send you'll see that
it is very mad at us cannot convert argument to from string to dictionary so it's going to require a
dictionary for us to be able to do that so what we need to do is we need to pass in an actual
dictionary of objects so we can come in here pass in this dictionary like so and go quote message
colon that and the reason why we have to do this is because we can actually do what's called uh
emotes right and emotes are sent via um json data so that's the reason why it requires it to be a
dictionary so that we can actually send over emote information now i'm not going to cover that just
because uh there's a whole like loading emotes and stuff like that that you need to do and that's
way beyond the basics of this tutorial so if you guys want to look at that you guys can go check out
their real-time chatting section and they'll go over that but i'll go ahead and hit submit test to
submit join test join test test send and you'll see that we actually get an error so it says invalid
chat identifier so what's going on here right well if you take a look at your chat here if we take a
look at our chat you'll see that our chat actually has an identifier id2 you see that so when you
have a chat it actually has an identifier associated with that chat and so you don't want to pass in
the title of the chat you want to pass in the identifier you can see that we have a channel right
here so if i go channel.id we can go ahead and refresh this guy and go submit test submit and you'll
see that we are now printing out and you will see that we have an id right here i added channel id
in post so that way it was nice and quick but you can see right here channel id is two dot dot dot
test so two is the id of the chat and test is the actual id that we gave it so we need to pass that
value in right here for us to be able to send messages so what we can do is we can come in here copy
this var channel go all the way up to the top and go var current channel like that and then we go
all the way back down to the bottom and do current channel is equal to that and then we'll go ahead
and copy this we'll paste it right here dot id and then we can go ahead and do current channel dot
id right here as well now what that will do is that it should allow us to actually send it to the
proper id so we'll hit submit test to submit test join test join test send and you should see right
here we no longer have an error but instead we have an actual message right here i probably should
not have used the word test i should probably use this is a test message that way we can actually
see what it is and you can see here that i send a message and you see right here channel id test
code is zero content message this is a test message and that's basically how we can send and receive
messages now the nice thing is that if since we typed our message section and unfortunately this is
getting pretty large so i might want to abstract some of this out but if we go to right here where
our on channel message is at we have our different messages that we can message information here
that we can actually use so if we type message dot you'll see that it's going to automatically give
us some information here that we can work with so you can see that we have sender id username all
sorts of information so the nice thing is i can come in here and i can go dollar sign chat text box
dot text plus equals message dot user name plus colon space plus message dot and then if we take a
look there should be a content dot message like that like that and we should probably also go ahead
and pass in a new line because we want the user to have a new line here now so let's try this var
content is equal to message dot content and then i wonder if content dot message will work instead
okay there we go we'll try that and see if that works also i'm going to want to put a new line at
the end of this so we'll go ahead and do that slash n for a new line that way every time somebody
sends a message it's going to be a new lined message and now if i refresh this in theory this should
work so we'll go ahead and do submit test join test to submit test join test send and it is very
unhappy so let's take a look you can see the content here is a string data so it looks like we're
going to need to json parse this information so we'll go json dot parse string and we'll go ahead
and pass that in and there we go and that should fix that problem basically content is a json value
so that's something that i didn't think about i'm talking without thinking as i'm doing this
tutorial so forgive me but we need to actually parse that data so now if we hit send you'll see test
test test this is a test message like so test to this is a test message and that's basically how you
could do a very basic communication system so now the question is okay great that's fine but how do
i actually do group chats and in order to do group
chats what we need to do is we need to come in here and we need to go ahead and grab another join
chat here and what i'm going to do is i'm going to unhide my group section and i guess i'll just
move it over so we have a little bit more space let's grab this guy we'll drag him over like this
it's getting a little on the cramped side with our setup here so i might need to readjust some stuff
but i don't think i can fit it really up here so we'll just kind of push it over here and that
should just work i mean it's a little tight but it will work for the demonstration we're trying to
do here so if i grab this guy here i right click disconnect inspector change this to join a group
chat like so when you want to do a group chat all you got to do is come in and basically i move this
guy over there we go all you really need to do is you need to come in here connect your button down
so go ahead and connect that over here and then we can come in here and basically just grab this
exact code right here it's almost a duplication right it's almost exactly the same we'll just drop
that guy in there and all we really need to do is come in here and when we do our join socket
asynchronously we just basically need to pass in our group id so we'll say and i believe we have a
group if i remember correctly so selected group dot id and then we can pass in type for persistence
we're going to want to say true because we want to keep that group around right and then we want it
to be persistent and we also want to change this to a type group chat and then what we can do is we
can come in here hit play come over here submit test we will go ahead and create a group so that way
now our group actually exists so if we refresh our groups i'll have to re-log in because this is
another recording session and you can see we now have a test group and we are now a part of it now
from here we can join that group with test too so we'll come in here and i already did this one so
we'll do test to test join group and it got mad at me because our selected group is not correct and
that's my fault so that's totally fine so i will have to refresh real quick so we'll say submit test
we will go ahead and list our groups we'll select our test group we'll do test to list our groups
select it join that group and then when we join our chat we can just join group chat growing group
chat and then test and you will see that this guy now gets it and if we go this is a test message
and we send that guy you can see that that message gets sent now you might be going okay so why does
this matter right what is the benefit of a group chat versus a dynamic chat well where a group chat
matters and why it's important is because you can do what's called listing the message history so
because it's a persistent chat we're going to be able to pull back all of that information so the
reason why that's cool is because we can come in here and we can say okay when the user joins a
group which we'll have to scroll down here to right here and we'll need to go ahead and come in here
and list out that information so we'll say far result is equal to await client dot list channel
messages asynchronous we'll pass in our session and then we'll pass in our currently selected groups
so selected group dot id we could pass in a limit value so in our case we'll just do 100 that's a
very decent value forward basically forward is forward or backwards right so we can grab the oldest
or the newest and that's what forward is is forward is the newest so we'll say forward so we'll say
true comma and then i believe they have a cursor value as well and cursor is if i remember correctly
it's defaulted let's double check really quick if we hit comma cursor variance is null so cursor
allows you to say i want you to start at this point so if you're picking up the next 100 values
let's say you have 500 messages you can pass in number 200 and then it'll grab from 200 to 300 if
that makes sense so in our case i'll just leave that as null because it's just going to be easier
for us to work with it now we can go for message in result dot message like that messages like that
and then we can basically just go exactly what we did before so we can come up here and grab if you
remember how we actually parsed out our data which arguably i should move this down closer to my
actual message functionality so let's go ahead and just do that really quick we'll come down here
and just drop it right let's see this is group stuff this is chat stuff so we'll go ahead and just
drop it right there and that'll just kind of keep it within the group area so that way i can
basically come in here and do this and say chat room code right here and that'll give me somewhere
to actually look at this now what we can do is we can basically just grab this copy it and paste and
that's all we need to do and then in theory this should just work so now if we hit play in theory if
we're lucky it will work so we'll go here we'll say list groups select group join group chat and we
got an error message return response invalid channel id so we have a failure here that says that our
channel id is incorrect so let's see join chat asynchronously list channel messages that should be
correct is it printing out what i expect let's see so i don't think that this worked 100 here so
let's try by submitting list groups select group that should select our group
and then i should be able to join group chat but it did not take it so the question is is it because
i failed to join the group chat or did it fail here so if we do this the id of the group id is
string get return if not string else string await list channel messages try refresh and it's gonna
run through that real quick but it didn't do anything as expected so if i drop a breakpoint here
what is result result is an object id cacheable null null so we got a nakama exception invalid
channel id so the question is is did our channel get saved let's go ahead and take a look at nakama
really quick chat messages group chat no messages found so our group chat just doesn't exist so
that's not great so that means something went wrong with how we initialized our group chat i think
okay so i figured out the issue so basically when we do our list channel messages async we need to
actually do our current channel dot id instead so when we do our join chat asynchronous we pull back
a channel and that's the channel that we're currently in and basically we need to go and list those
message right here and then i have a section here for messages in result messages if the message
content does not contain an empty so if for some reason a message gets in there that's empty when we
try to parse it it's going to break so i have this little if statement right here that basically
just checks to see if it's empty if it is ignore it and there's no reason to have it so now if i hit
play you'll notice that when i come in here and i hit submit i list my groups i select my groups and
i join my group chat you'll see i pull back those messages and that's one of the big cool features
of nakama is that it keeps track of all of that information because this is after we removed and
rebooted the system right it actually came back with the proper messages that's basically what
persistence does right here this true right here causes it to be saved and to be reusable later
that's one of the big cool advantages here so now the question is okay so how do i do peer-to-peer
messaging well it's not technically peer-to-peer but how do i send messages directly to a user well
again it's relatively simple if we come into our stuff here we control c control v join group chat
and then instead of join group chat we have a join direct chat i go ahead and grab our where is it
join group chat right here and i change this to join direct chat like that we can come in here
disconnect right click connect and connect now in order to do a direct chat it's actually relatively
easy it's exactly the same as everything else you come in here you go join chat room right here copy
it come down here paste well really actually we probably should just grab this to be honest it's
going to save us a bit of trouble so if we paste this guy in here change the channel type to direct
message like that instead of having a selected group id we need to grab the user id in terms of
persistence we want to keep true we also want to keep false for hidden but for this join chat
asynchronous we can go ahead and pass in a user id so we need to get our actual user identifier and
the easiest way to do that is by using the get users asynchronous call if you remember we did that
earlier so we'll just say var users is equal to await client dot get users asynchronous and then
we'll pass in our session and we need to pass in a id pack string array and then the user name that
we're going to be passing in so in our case i think if we take a look at our user interface we have
a chat name we could probably just take that i think that will work so for the chat name what i'll
do is i'll just pull this guy which is chat name so we'll come into our script we'll hit dollar sign
chat name dot text and then that should bring back our users so now we know that it's going to bring
back one user and that's it so since it's going to bring back one user we can basically just do if
users dot size is greater than zero then we can do the rest of this bit of code here and then we
just pass in and say users bracket bracket zero dot id and that'll pass back a user id that we can
actually communicate with so now in theory this should work and of course as always with theory it
doesn't always work but we'll see so we'll submit as test we'll submit as test two and then we'll go
test test two join direct chat it's mad and that's because users came back let's see with an array
it looks like it's users dot users so that's my fault so we'll say users dot users and i should
probably just do this as results then or perhaps user results because we don't want to mess with our
current code down here that has results already we'll just do that and then for this we'll just say
user result dot users
bracket bracket zero because we now know that we need to go a little bit deeper than what we
expected so now if we go ahead and submit test two join direct chat now we're in a direct chat if we
go into test two and we go to test join direct chat we pass test in
okay so i think i figured out what's going on here so i commented this out just so we could check it
out but what i think is going on here is remember in our previous tutorial we had test block test
two and because they're blocked they can't send them messages so it completely stops them from being
able to communicate with each other and that's why this is happening so if i remove this let's see
what happens if i do that so we'll go ahead and come in here we'll control s we'll hit play and then
we'll try it one more time so we'll do submit test to submit test join direct chat test to join
direct chat test we will send a message and that will now work now the reason why this didn't work
was because test had test two blocks so since they're blocked they can't communicate at all so
that's the reason why this happened so it was my fault but that was basically the reasoning now if
we go ahead and stop this and then we come in here and uncomment this with control k and then we run
this bad boy in theory we should be able to see our previous communications so test to join direct
chat and you will see there's all of our messages now i'm getting a little bit additional messages
mostly because of my testing not because of a problem with nakama that's just something that i did
on my own by accident but you can see here are all of the messages that we have so that's basically
how you do messages
back and forth inside of nakama hey guys editor mitch here so something that you should do once you
do your chat system and you get that guy settled when you have this chat right here what you should
also do is subscribe to everybody's channels so if you have friends or some kind of channel system
you need to subscribe to that channel so what i'm gonna do is come up to my on login login button
down so when i press my login i'm gonna go ahead and come in here and i'm gonna have sub to
friend channels like that now i'm gonna scroll down and i have a chat section in here so you can see
we have our little group section right here we scroll down we have a chat room code right here so
this is our chat section so right here just somewhere in this general section here we're gonna go
ahead and add in the ability to sub to the the friend channels right so we'll say funk sub to
friends
channels channels like that and then what i'm gonna do is say var results is equal to await client
dot list friends asynchronously i'm gonna pass in my session and that'll just bring in all of my
friends and then from here i can go ahead and subscribe to their channel so for i in results dot
friends like that and then i'm gonna go ahead and say var type is equal to nakama socket dot channel
type dot direct message and then i can go ahead and pull back my chat that i have so i can sub to
that channel so i can say await socket oh i have sub to friends sub to friend so we'll do friend
channels and that'll fix that little function not found so socket dot join chat async and then i'll
go ahead and pass an i dot user dot id comma type comma true comma false and that'll basically allow
me to pull those sockets back now this should return if i remember correctly a channel so if we
actually hit ctrl f you can see we have a couple of them you can see we have current channel right
here so what i'm going to do is i'm going to come here and say chat channels is equal to a weight
socket okay and actually now that i think about this let's do this so we'll do channel let's do this
channel is equal to this and then we can come down here and just say chat channels bracket bracket i
dot user dot id actually i wonder if i should do dot user name instead that way it's just a more
common value and i could go is equal to channel like that and that'll basically hook our channel
here to this object so i'll say var and then there we go and chat channels doesn't exist yet but now
we have a key value pair here that we can use and that's going to be really big for us if we want to
use those channels later so now i can go ahead and grab chat channels i can go up to the top var
chat channels like that and i can actually come in here and now i have access to all of my chats
right here so if i have like 100 chats i could actually pull back the channel information and switch
between them really easily using this object and i'll probably go through that later but it's a way
to extend our chat to be a bit more useful if that makes sense so if you think about it like this
basically what we could do is we could add in a tab container right here make that guy full screen
and then underneath that tab container you can actually switch between different tabs right and i
think what we could do and again this is going to be a lot of coding and then we could actually come
in here make this about i don't know about this big give or take and then we could put that chat
text underneath here right and this would allow us to in theory do this and then change the title of
this to username like so you can see here here's the username so what we could do at least in theory
is on startup once we subscribe to all of those channels it would just fill this out so for instance
if we come in here and we go and subscribe to those friend channels so if we grab this guy bring it
down here come in here and then basically just say tab container or i guess it's going to be dollar
sign tab container dot
add child and then we can add a child of this text box here so basically if we add a child of this
text box and i'm just kind of thinking this through as i talk to you guys so my apologies for how
confusing this is probably going to end up being but we could do a text box so this is going to be a
text edit so var
current edit is equal to text edit dot new like that and then we could pass in our current edit like
that
so i dot user dot user name like so and then when we log in you'll see that i'm going to have a tab
right here called username but if i click on login and it's mad at me so you can see invalid index
test 2 so let's take a look at this so create chat null so this is a null object it needs to be a
type dictionary that's my guess at least so we'll come in here we'll say colon equals bracket
bracket like that and that'll make it into an object and now if we try it it should in theory work
there we go and you can see we have test 2 and username right here and that means that we would be
able to go and fetch any messages that we want from that person so if we were to go in here sub to
friend chat go down here we could actually go and fetch that person's information if you remember we
actually do that right here we pull back the messages right here so what we could do is if we list
channel messages asynchronously we should probably pull this out and just do
list messages like that do this it's going to want to have a current channel dot id so current
channel like that and then we could come in here and just do current edit dot text is equal to list
messages and then we have to pass in our current channel so that would be our let's see channel
right here so channel so we'll pass to that channel that'll pass back all of the text in that
channel this is a coroutine so it must be called with await that makes sense so await and then
instead of doing this we'll just return that value so we'll just say var text oh i guess i'm gonna
have to create a text so var text is equal to quote and then we'll need to just do text plus equals
blah and then we can just return our text like that and then that will return text right here and
then instead of doing this when we join a chat group we can just go dollar sign or we could just go
in here and add in a panel like what we're doing right here you can see how we're joining chat
asynchronously so we really could just grab this section here and just paste it right here on this
guy like so and that'll basically solve that problem right there now technically this is duplicated
code and that's probably not the most ideal situation but that's probably okay for right now and
instead of doing our chat channel i username what we would do is we would do something like current
channel and then selected group so selected group.id the current name would also be the selected
group id i guess we'd probably want to come up with a better way maybe we could just call it current
group right instead of the name like so and then we could probably come in here and list our current
channel as well and in theory that would work so now if we hit play in theory we would have a
tabular messaging system now we can hit submit and there's all of our messages right there and we
have different tabs that we can work with i think if i do test it's probably going to get mad at me
invalid index id that makes sense because current channel.id
current channel is null my guess is because i'm not in a channel yet so that would make sense so
what we would need to do is we need to make our tab container handle that when the tab gets switched
which i think there is a on tab changed right here so we would have to keep track of which index our
stuff is actually located in so i think that that's okay so we could actually just do this on tab
changed like so and then we could just keep track of what index we're on when the user changes their
tab it kind of keeps track of that so how i would do that is if i go into where the tabs are located
so you can see here and i know this is probably a little bit confusing and my apologies i'm just
kind of working through it with you guys but so you can see right here we have a channel uh selected
group id current channel so what we could do is when we do our tab container we could actually
connect our um tab changed event and then bind the um user id to it so we could do is we could do
dollar sign panel tab container dot add child like so but we could do dot tab changed dot connect
and then we could put on tab changed and i guess i should do on chat tab changed dot bind and i can
pass in the selected group id like so so and then we could come in here and just say func on chat
tab changed like so and then we could pass in int tab comma or i guess it would be i'm sorry i'm
trying to code in c sharp tab colon int comma and then we could pass in group id or channel id
like that and that would pass in that value like that and there we go so what that's going to do is
allow us to print well uh tab comma channel id like that and that will give us the ability to work
with this now when we join a chat group that's how we have to handle that but when we do our sub to
friends channel we got to do that as well so that way we can do it on both so now if i hit play in
theory if i do submit it's mad at me unable to get index id on base nil that's because selected
group is null and that's because i'm dumb and i chose the wrong bind it's going to be i dot user dot
username so we'll grab that and paste it right here let's try that one more time so i'm going to
come in here i'm going to go submit and it once again is going to be mad a non-existent function
bind on base int that's mad about let me see i think i might have figured it out what if i do this
instead and then i have to go and find my other bind which should be i think i need to put it out
inside the the signal connection so i'm connecting i'm binding this to the signal not to the
connection function i think that's what's doing it so let's try that let's grab the other one so you
see how this one connect dot bind instead i think i need to bind and then do that and then i should
be able to make that work and i believe it is index and then channel id so let's try that let's see
what that does there we go and then if i click test two it should have displayed test two right
there so that's perfect so what that means is that we can go current channel is equal to chat
channels bracket bracket channel id like that and then what that means is now we should be able to
since we're binding those parameters i should be able to send a message and it should just take it
in theory invalid get text on null that's fine my guess is that's because chat text box doesn't
exist anymore because now we're going the opposite direction right so we're sending a message if you
see here if you look at the content message is test type is zero and if you take a look at this
object it has the channel id sender id user id 12 and then user name now if we take a look at our
channel objects right here so chat channels you can see test two is our parameter here that's going
to be our players information if that makes sense so i think we could probably get away with since
this is going to give us test as its content and the message is going to say sender id is right here
the channel id is right here i wonder if we should pull because it has a username right here but
that's not going to hook us up to our channel code so i'm curious if we need to change how we send
our data across so we send our data we're sending the message and then the current channel id okay
so i think i know what i'm going to do here so we're actually going to change up a little bit how
we're doing this and the reason why i'll show you if we take a look at right here we're passing in
our current channel what i'm going to do is i'm going to come in here and pass in instead of just a
current channel i'm going to pass in channel like that colon current channel and then i'm also going
to pass in a label value just so i can have the label if i need it for whatever reason and the label
in the selected group id will probably just be group chat because it really doesn't need to have
anything special and if we go to the other one so channel chats we go to the other one which is
right here so this one needs to go dot channel because we're making that adjustment real quick you
can see right here we're doing channel so you can see we'll need to make that adjustment and then
we'll just copy this guy right here we'll paste it like so and then i'm going to go ahead and pass
in ctrl x
channel like that and that will allow us to have an object that has a label here and then for the
actual label itself i'll just pass this guy in like that and then i'll just do channel.id like that
and then if we have this then we should be able to use this to pull back that channel information
instead and i know what you're thinking that doesn't sound like it's going to work but it's probably
not going to work so let's go ahead and say on tab change bind selected group id if i do on tab
changed bind channel id like that and then when we produce our message here we're going to be
fetching back this on channel message parse the content and
right here we will have a chat box so you can see we have chat chat box it'll be tab container dot
get node like that content dot and if we take a look at what our message is going to be right here
so we have our right message asynchronous we'll just say content dot id like so and then here we can
pass in quote id colon and fetch back our channel information so chat channels like so channel id so
it'd be current channel dot id right here like that and that will pass back our channel information
and then from here we could just go dot label and that should allow us to fetch back the correct
node and set the proper information right there and in theory that would work let's try that and see
how that works so if we hit submit test to test send you'll see that we now get our test information
so this is a test message like that and we click go you'll see this is a test message just like that
and that's basically how we can make a tabbed system as well that should actually work for our chat
system so now that we have a basic chatting system that fully works let's talk about how we can host
this out on the cloud because the best way to get your networking working is by hosting it out on
the cloud that means that you have to pay a server to host that information so if you want a
multiplayer game you need to actually pay to host that data somewhere right and that is where
digital ocean comes in digital ocean is a pretty great tools kit that will allow you to host your
projects right here on their servers and it's relatively cheap if you take a look at the pricing you
can see they have some pretty cheap droplets so if you wanted a cheap like five dollar server to
host your game that's more or less what this is for is it allows you to actually host stuff out in
the cloud for relatively cheap and i will drop a link in the description below that if you guys use
it it will give me credits to be able to host my own stuff now i will be hosting stuff for this
tutorial here i'll be giving you guys an ip address and you guys can use it for your testing but
just know that if you want to go out into production you need to use your own server and something
to keep in mind you can host your own server as well locally but it's a lot harder it's not as safe
and people can hack into your networks and things like that so it's really nice just to use
something like this to host it for you so that you can get your game out there and get people
playing it and playing together so let's go ahead and create an account or log in whichever one you
guys have so i'm going to go ahead and log in real quick so this is digital ocean and basically the
nice thing here is this is your dashboard right so this is the digital ocean dashboard so here is
where you can manage all of your resources now you can see up here you have your profile information
and then you have whatever droplets you have now in digital ocean droplets are considered machines
okay and you can see that they have all sorts of really cool features here they have spaces which is
basically like storage they have database stuff so if you actually come in here you can see that you
can spin up databases right here so if you're using nakama you can actually store your database
outside of your droplet and allow for load balancing they actually have a full built-in load
balancing system right here spinning up a load balance so you can actually choose different data
regions and pass data in between different regions and things like that by using their load
balancers now that being said that's way beyond the scope of this tutorial but that's what i'm
trying to say is digital ocean has a bunch of stuff for you to use that can help you get up to the
point where you can use nakama premium and actually have them handle a lot of that for you but this
is a good way to kind of get started into that if that makes sense so let's go ahead and talk about
how to create a droplet so let's go up here to the upper right hand corner click on create click on
droplet you could do an app platform that's technically going to be cheaper but it's a lot harder to
get everything set up properly so i'm just going to do a droplet for right now
and so we can pick what region we want our droplet in so right here i'm going to choose new york new
york is the closest to me so we'll choose that we'll come down here and you could choose an image
now if you have a specific image that you're looking for go ahead and pick it right here in my case
i'm going to go with ubuntu but if you want to you can also look at the marketplace and you could
pick different stuff so docker on ubuntu probably would be a good image to get or maybe something
like lamp if you're trying to do a lamp server or wordpress or something like that they have so many
different droplets that you can actually use have at your disposal you can see here you can also do
custom images so if you have an image you can actually just spin it up and have it work now in my
case i'm going to go with os ubuntu we're going to start from base even though technically docker on
ubuntu probably is a better option so i'm going to go so so i'm going to go with marketplace docker
on ubuntu that's going to save us a lot of trouble and get it all set up for us right so all we have
to do is get our docker composed and then set up our firewall rules and we'll be good to go so we'll
go ahead and add that guy now if you come in here you can see that you have a bunch of different
options for size now it depends on what you're trying to do
and typically what i tell people is you want to pick the lowest value that you can and plus one so
for instance if you think that your game is going to be really small and not a lot of people are
going to play it then something like the 14 a month one is probably pretty good if you're looking
for something really cheap just for testing if you go to regular and you kick it over you can see
that you can just do something like the six dollar a month one or even the four dollar a month one
if you can get away with under 10 gigabytes if you were to come up here and choose os ubuntu then
you could go down to four dollars a month at 512 megabytes now once you get down that low this is
basically only used for testing you want to at minimum have six dollars a month the one gigabyte one
cpu just because it's going to allow you to have a lot more flexibility for your project now since
i'm doing a marketplace image of and now since this is going to be a tutorial i should probably just
do ubuntu with the four because odds are you're not going to have the funding to do this or
something like that so we'll try the four we might have to upgrade to six we'll see and then you can
see here that you can add a volume which will allow you to expand your disk space now in our case we
don't need that because it's fine for right now and you can see that we have authentication so we
have ssh key and password now in my case we're just going to do so i'm going to set my password
right here and we'll scroll down here and you can see that we can do improved metrics and monitoring
for free so may as well turn that on and i don't think we need to do a database cluster here but we
can look at that in the future so you can see here is our host name right here which i'll call it
youtube2 tags i'm not worried about it and then you'll see that it has a project right here now this
project is where it's going to get built under so don't worry it'll just get built under your
account and then we'll click create droplet now this is going to allow us to have a droplet once it
gets built which should be relatively quick there we go you can see it's in the middle of building
it and it is now completed so it actually created your little droplet right here so now at this
point once we click into it you can see here is our youtube 2 droplet you can see we have our graphs
for our bandwidth cpu usage stuff like that we have access which allows us to adjust our access to
it we have power which allows you to turn it off and on we have volumes which allow you to have
block storage resize which allows you to change how big and strong that droplet is so you're welcome
to go in and actually upgrade this later so if you need that one giga memory or that one 10 gigabyte
ssd right that's all stuff that right here is available and then you can come in here and go into
networking you can change your network ip address your firewall stuff you can come in here and back
it up you can get snapshots of it so that way if you need this droplet to be perfect and snapshotted
for backup purposes this is what this is for it allows you to basically go back to that point in
time and apply it to your image so the nice thing is is if you create snapshots and your stuff gets
hacked or something like that you can roll back to that snapshot and stop that hack from happening
kernel is something that you're not going to be using but basically it allows you to upgrade your
linux kernel history is the history of it destroy allows you to destroy that droplet tags allows you
to tag it and recovery allows you to try to recover your droplet now that we've gone through all of
this let's go up to our console here and click on that you'll see that that's going to pop up a
droplet console now this is pretty cool because you actually have a full linux machine here so if
you don't know linux now is the time to learn because linux is very important to know so first
things first inside of ubuntu to install docker what you need to do is you need to type sudo apt-get
update and that's going to update all of your mirrors out there and then we need to go in and
actually add the repository because docker doesn't actually exist in the repo by default so we'll
say sudo apt-get install ca-certificates
curl like that and that's going to go ahead and make sure that we have curl installed and then we'll
sudo install m 0755-d slash etc slash apt slash key rings and then we're going to go in and curl out
to the docker linux ubuntu i will actually leave these commands in the comments below by the way so
you guys can use it but sudo curl
dash f s s dash l f s capital s l https colon slash slash download dot docker dot com slash linux
slash ubuntu slash gpg dash o space slash etc
slash apt slash key rings slash docker dot asc and what that's going to do is it's going to actually
create a docker gpg apt repo for you so that way you can actually go and install docker and then we
need to allow access to it so sudo ch mod a plus r slash etc slash apt slash key rings docker asc
and that basically allows us to execute and use that data that's right there so basically linux is a
permission system that is very very aggressive so you need to make sure that you keep that stuff
under wraps if that makes sense so uh linux by default does not give you permissions to anything and
you have to give yourself permissions to it so that's kind of what we're doing right here so then we
can come in here and finally fire off our apt resources now this command is going to be really
difficult to do so we'll do echo slash enter and that's going to allow us to kind of get a actual
script going here so we'll say quote deb space bracket arch
that's going to be really difficult to do so we're going to do so we're going to do so we're going
to
docker dot docker dot com slash linux slash ubuntu
and then we're going to put that in dollar sign dot slash etc etc slash os dash release and we're
going to echo our version code name
and we're going to pull back the stable version like that we're going to pass in a pipe and we're
going to pipe that into sudo t slash etc slash apt slash source dot list dot d slash docker dot list
greater than sign slash dev slash null and i know that that's a terrible command but basically all
this command is doing is we're going and we're adding in we're going deb all of this information and
we're piping all this info into our sudo our sources list right here for docker and that's basically
all we're doing here i know that it seems really confusing but that's basically what we're doing
here now i'm going to double check this command because i just spotted a mistake right here where i
did equal equal instead of dash dash so let me double check this command and make sure that i'm
happy with it so we have arch eat dollar sign d package our print architecture we're going to sign
it by our docker asc file and we're going to go out to our docker linux ubuntu and we're going to
pull back the os release
and i misspelled echo right here you can see i made a mistake as always you make a million mistakes
when you do this so echo
echo so that's e-c-h-o and then we have our version code name that we are echoing into our release
we're pulling back the stable edition we're going to pipe that into sudo t right here into our
docker lists and we're greater than slash dev null and we'll run that command e-c-o is not found
that's because i spelled echo wrong so i guess it's good thing that i that it failed immediately so
e c h o and we will try running it hopefully this doesn't blow up all right so we have no such file
or directory so all right so i think i figured it out basically there is an issue with the command
for i think it was this area here so don't worry just copy what i have in my description and just
use that and it will just work for you so now all i got to do is type sudo apt dash get update like
that and that's going to update all of our packages in our repo and it's going to go and fetch out
to the docker system and pull back the actual docker packages so you can see right here it's
actually pulling down that information right there and then we're going to go ahead and install
docker so sudo apt dash get install docker dash ce docker dash ce dash cli
container.io docker dash build dash plug-in and finally the most important one of the group docker
dash compose dash compose dash plug-in and that's the big one that's the one that's actually going
to matter for our project for the most part i mean the rest of these are obviously important docker
ce is the docker uh runtime docker ce cli is this command line interface the uh container is the
actual container uh system docker build plugins is to build your own docker containers and then
docker compose allows you to actually compose dockers based off of a docker composition file if you
remember before when we talked about how to build nakama that was one of the big things that you
need to use so we'll hit enter it's going to go ahead and try to pull it it says that it cannot
locate the docker build plugin my guess is i spelled something wrong here so let's see docker build
x plugin there we go hit go and it should go ahead and download and install docker now we might need
to upgrade to the next step up to the one gigabyte edition but we're going to see if we can get away
with the four dollar a month version first and if we can't then we'll upgrade to the six dollar a
month version and then we can run our docker setup here so we'll see how this works but we'll go
from there so it looks like it is running if we type ps you will see that we have a bash and ps
running
so if we type docker is it going to pop up and there we go so we do have docker running so perfect
that's exactly what we want so now from here we need to get a docker compose file onto here so if we
type ls right here you can see that we have nothing going on so what we can do is we can type mk dur
nakama cd nakama like that and that's going to get us into that directory so mk dur makes the
directory cd nakama just brings us into the nakama directory so now we can come in here and
basically compose our docker file so if we're lucky we'll be able to just copy and paste our
composition file so if we go out here we go to documents and we find our nakama instance i believe i
have a nakama server tutorial docker compose.yaml so if we open this guy up you'll see this is what
our docker compose file looks like you can see right here this is what it looks like so if we hit
ctrl a ctrl c and then we go into our web browser here and we type nano docker dash compose dot yml
and then we right click paste it should paste all that data right into here so that way we don't
actually have to set up filezilla because one of the things that's unfortunate is a lot of times if
you're doing godot networking you need to actually put files up into filezilla and into the ftp and
bring them over to digital oceans to your digital ocean droplet so thankfully we can just copy and
paste this and control x y and it'll be docker compose dot yaml and now from here we should be able
to just get it to run if we're lucky so what we'll do come in here and type docker compose up and
you'll see it's going to go ahead and attempt to pull and build our docker instance right here now
we might run out of ram it just kind of depends but hopefully with 512 megs of ram it's going to be
really tight i don't know if this is going to work we're probably going to need a gig but we can see
so we'll let this run and we'll attempt to run it and it looks like it might have worked so what we
can do is if we go out to our youtube 2 we grab our public ip we go to our nakama console and we
just put in actually i'll just make a new thing colon and we'll put in 7351 so 7351 enter does it do
anything that's the first question it doesn't look like it's going to so now we got to figure out is
it this guy's fault it looks like this is running so my question is server is ready to receive web
requests so it did spin up properly it started the rule manager properly so that's good news oh you
can see it is just absolutely chugging though so if we take a look at our youtube docker container
let's see it looks like our cpu utilization is pretty high our disk io is relatively high as well we
probably need to upgrade to have one gig of ram but at least it is running so there is that the
question is so i was able to get it to stop so what we'll do is we'll close it we'll go to our
youtube we'll go over to upgrade droplet and then we'll go ahead and just upgrade that up to one
size larger to the one gigabyte edition so we'll do that and then we'll click cpu ram when it's
going to ask us to turn off our droplet so we'll go up to power we'll power it off because there's
nothing on here anyway so we can just power cycle it pretty hard there we go it's powered down we'll
go to resize and we'll adjust it up one size just to let it be the proper size that it needs to be
we're going to let that run you'll see it's thinking about it there we go and now we got a one size
bigger droplet now we can go ahead and power cycle that bad boy back on let's go into our networking
let's come down to our firewall and create a firewall now the firewall is just going to be test
firewall and what we'll do is we'll have an inbound of ssh we're also going to allow
a custom one and we're going to allow for seven three five one so we'll copy that bad boy and we'll
go ahead and paste it like that and then we'll do the same thing for seven three five zero as well
and then we're going to allow another one which is going to be seven three five one udp and seven
three five zero udp that way we can have all of our stuff all of our ducks in a row and everything
kind of covered now you can see here all outbound is good and we should be good to go so we'll go
ahead and hit create firewall and that should create that firewall onto that networking system so we
go to our droplet and we go to youtube 2 you should see right here under our firewall networking no
firewalls are applied to this droplet so i need to apply this firewall so let's see if we need
droplets we can choose our droplet add droplet and then we will search for youtube 2 and we'll go
ahead and connect it to that droplet so now that should give our droplet the firewall it needs to do
its job so now we should be able to go to console and fire that up and then hit
cd nakama and then docker compose up and in theory it should run a lot faster which it is you can
see it's actually firing off just well the init node was successfully done cockroach database is up
so now we're starting to get the proper logs that we expect so my guess is it had something to do
with the lack of ram that we had so let's try that we'll refresh and there we go so you can see now
we have nakama running out on our website which is one nine eight nine one nine nine eighty one one
eight and you guys of course can go to this and use it so if you type admin password you can see we
have our nakama instance just like before and it's exactly the same so you guys can actually use
this for your own project providing that it doesn't get shut down immediately because for some
reason it gets shut down sometimes and that causes some issues but that's how easy it is to get this
to fire off now and in order to detach let's hit ctrl c we'll stop our docker connection right here
and you'll see in a second it's going to gracefully stop so we'll give it a minute to kill
everything we'll hit docker compose up dash dash detach what that should do is it should allow us to
fire this up and be detached and there you go so now we're detached so if we hit ps you'll see that
it's not running but if i come in here and i refresh you can see that nakama is running if i close
this and i refresh you will see that nakama is running even though we are no longer connected to our
docker instance so that's how we can actually get that to run without needing to keep that window
open because if you were to have closed the window when nakama's running like that previously
without running the dash dash detach then it would have closed that docker instance and then your
whole project would have been gone so that's basically how that works so now if we head out to godot
here we can come up to here and change this value to our nakama instance so if we come in here you
can see here is our nakama instance right here so we'll copy that we'll paste this like so and then
if we hit play you will see that we can now submit and log in so you'll see that i have logged in so
now if i take a look at my nakama instance out here on the web if i refresh you'll see that when we
go to accounts i have an account right here just like as if i was playing the game locally so this
is how that works and you can come in here and go test two and you'll see that if i click name of
match test join create test join create we just joined our match and then if the host says start
game and then start game you'll see that we both started our game now something here is broken but i
don't think that that's a nakama issue i think that's just a my code issue so you can see that we
are transferring the data as expected here in our nakama instance so we do have the presences as
expected but i feel like something here is wonky a little bit and i think that's because i'm not in
the right scene to do this i think i have to go to game manager.tscn if you remember this is our
game manager here so let's refresh this guy let's try rerunning it so we'll hit test test to test
join create test join create start game start game and you can see that our game is now running not
locally anymore so this will work with your friends across the web and what i'm going to do is i'm
going to go get one of my friends and i will have him pull my code and then he will also do this and
i'll show you guys that it does work out on the internet so i will be right back okay and then hit
start game and as you guys can see right here my friend and i are both working together and playing
the same game at the same time over the internet using our nakama instance now you can see here that
there is a little bit of lag and i think the reason for that is because we're flooding the actual
nakama instance because it has a bunch of data that it's passing through so we should probably
figure out a better way to optimize this but at least we have it working for now so at this point
we've gone through quite a few things we talked about groups we talked about chatting and we talked
about how to get our stuff to work out on the internet for our project and allow us to work on
multiple networks with each other so if you like this video go and hit that like button hey you know
if you dislike this video go and hit that dislike button because i am here to make content for you
guys this video was a viewer suggested video so if you have any suggestions please leave them in the
comments below or jump on my github link is in the description and put in a service ticket and i'll
be more than happy to add it to my list of tutorials for the future and hey if you have any
questions or comments about this video go ahead and leave them in the comments below or jump on my
discord link is in the description and i'll be more than happy to help you out but that is all i
have for you guys today so thank you so much again for watching and i will see you all next time
thanks your so
you Thank you.