Hey  guys  this  is  Mitch  with
Fineboy  CGI  and  today  we're  going
to  continue  our  Nakama  tutorial  series
where  I  take  you  from  zero
to  understanding  all  the  fundamentals  of
Nakama  and  in  this  video  we're
going  to  talk  about  how  to
do  groups  so  that's  going  to
allow  you  to  add  users  to
like  a  guild
or  like  a  group  setting  then
we're  going  to  talk  about  doing
chats  and  chatting  between  each  other
so  sending  messages  to  each  other
and  finally  due  to  popular  requests
I'm  going  to  talk  about  how
to
host  your  Nakama  instance  out  on
the  internet  so  that  you  can
play  games  with  your  friends  or
of
course  you  can  release  your  game
out  to  make  it  into  a
multiplayer  game  so  that's  what  I
have  in
store  for  you  guys  today  so
let's  go  ahead  and  get  started
all  right  so  this  tutorial  assumes
that  you
already  completed  the  previous  tutorial  where
we  actually  integrated  Nakama  for  the
most  part
so  this  one's  going  to  be
going  over  more  of  the  features
and  things  like  that  that  are
available
to  you  so  let's  go  ahead
and  get  started  with  that  and
the  first  thing  we're  going  to
talk  about  is
creating  groups  so  groups  are  basically
like  a  guild  or  a  team
of  people  that  want  to  play
with  each
other  multiple  times  not  necessarily  as
a  party  but  as  an  actual
group  so  after  the  game  is
ended  and  everything  is  done  you
still  have  access  to  that  group
of  people  so  the  first  thing
that
I'm  going  to  do  is  I'm
going  to  come  in  here  and
I'm  going  to  hide  our  friends
section  because  we're
actually  running  out  of  space  here
and  I  really  should  name  all
of  these  but  that's  probably  going
to  break  all  of  my  code
so  we'll  go  ahead  and  just
hide  that  panel  go  ahead  and
add  in  a  new  panel
like  so  I'm  going  to  go
over  here  make  it  about  this
big  give  or  take  I'm  going
to  right  click  add
a  child  node  we'll  add  in
a  label  like  that  we're  going
to  make  it  about  this  big
and  we'll  have  a
name  parameter  there  we'll  go  ahead
and  duplicate  it  and  say  description
and  then  we'll  come  in  here
right  click  add  in  a  child
node  and  we'll  add  in  a
line  edit  like  so
and  we'll  make  it  about  this
big  give  or  take  we'll  control
duplicate  that  and  we'll  make  it
about
this  big  I  mean  technically  the
description  should  be  a  little  bit
longer  but  that's  okay  we'll  make
it  work  for  what  we're  going
to  do  so  that's  fine  and
I'll  just  kind  of  organize  this
properly  then
we'll  add  in  a  button  and
this  button  is  going  to  allow
us  to  create  a  group  now
I'm  going  to  need
multiple  buttons  but  for  right  now
we'll  just  do  one  I  think
so  we'll  go  ahead  and  say
create  group
like  so  and  I'll  probably  need
to  make  this  panel  larger  to
be  honest  I'm  running  out  of
space  here
so  we'll  go  ahead  and  just
make  this  a  touch  bit  bigger
like  so  now  when  we  want
to  create  a  group
all  we  have  to  do  is
if  we  grab  this  button  name
it  create  group  like  so  we'll
go  into  our  node  button
down  and  we'll  hook  that  to
our  control  node  just  like  that
now  you'll  see  when  I  hook
it  to  the
control  node  it  should  create
a  create  group  button  down  function
it  looks  like  I  already  did
this  in  a  previous  section  so
I'm  going
to  go  ahead  and  get  rid
of  that  that's  my  fault  that
caught  me  off  guard  real  quick
but  to  create  a
group  all  we  have  to  do
is  say  client  dot  create  group
async  and  then  we  can  pass
in  our  session
like  so  and  then  we  have
to  pass  in  a  name  now
the  name  is  whatever  the  name
is  that  we  put  as  our
line
edit  now  if  we  take  a
look  we  have  our  name  right
here  so  we'll  say  group  name
and  then  group  description
like  so  and  then  we'll  go
back  to  our  script  and  we'll
do  dollar  sign  group  name  comma
or  dot  text
comma  dollar  sign  group  description  dot
text  comma  and  then  you'll  see
that  they  have  the  option  for
an  avatar  url  now  you  don't
have  to  supply  one  but  you
can  and  that's  really  cool  because
it  basically  would
allow  you  to  have  some  kind
of  url  for  an  image  that
you  could  load  for  their  group
so  I'm  going  to  put
that  as  empty  comma  and  then
you'll  see  that  they  have  a
language  so  we'll  say  their  main
language  is
en  it  doesn't  really  matter  necessarily
but  it  is  a  thing  that
exists  and  actually  I  need  to
I'm  messing
up  my  little  things  here  we'll
put  an  empty  url  we'll  put
a  en  for  the  avatar  title
and  then  you
can  choose  whether  or  not  it's
an  open  or  if  it's  not
so  an  open  means  if  it's
a  public  group  so  if
people  can  actually  see  it  and
index  it  for  other  people  so
if  you  say  false  then  it's
a  private  group
so  if  you  don't  want  it
to  be  listable  which  we'll  discuss
listing  in  a  little  bit  but
it  allows  you  to
basically  say  is  this  a  listable
group  so  I'm  going  to  say
true  because  it  makes  sense  to
have  a  listable
group  and  then  you  can  have
a  max  number  of  members  now
once  this  is  set  you  cannot
change  it
so  make  sure  you  set  it
to  a  value  that  you  want
so  if  a  guild  can  only
have  64  members  then  you  set
it  to  64  if  it's  100
members  then  you  can  set  it
to  100  so  in  my  case
I'm  going  to  say  32  just
because
32  is  just  a  good  round
number  now  after  that  there  is
nothing  else  that  we  can  do
so  we'll  go  ahead  and
just  say  32  now  typically  this
also  returns  a  group  api  so
you  could  say  var  group  is
equal  to
await  client  asynchronous  and  then  we
can  just  go  ahead  and  print
out  that  group  now  you  don't
have
to  do  this  but  it  is
a  way  to  get  a  hold
of  that  object  if  that  makes
sense  so  if  you  needed  to
go
ahead  and  make  your  group  you
know  visible  or  not  visible  or
something  like  that  you  could  do
that  right
here  so  now  if  we  go
ahead  and  make  sure  that  our
nakama  instance  is  running  so  if
I  take  a  look  at
my  containers  you  can  see  it
is  actually  running  so  there  we
go  we'll  go  ahead  and  hit
play
and  then  we're  going  to  go
ahead  and  submit  we're  going  to
connect  to  our  game  we're  going
to  call  our
group  test  group  description  this  is
our  test  group  and  we'll  click
create  now  you'll  see  that  we
have
a  error  group  name  must  be
set  so  I  must  have  messed
up  on  my  group  name  so
let's  take  a  look
panel  5  group  name  oh  I
made  a  mistake  because  this  is
the  original  panel  I  did  some
recording  earlier
that  um  I  didn't  keep  it
but  I  never  actually  removed  that
panel  so  we'll  change  this  to
panel
6  and  then  we'll  go  from
there  so  we'll  refresh  this  and
try  this  one  more  time  that's
my  fault  so
we'll  submit  test  group  this  is
a  test  group  create  group  and
you'll  see  that  we  get  a
success
right  there  so  now  I'm  going
to  navigate  to  127  nakama  console
right  here  so  we'll  go  to
our  127
7351  and  then  we  will  connect
into  our  nakama  group  if  we
go  to  groups  you  will  see
there  is  our  test
group  and  you  can  see  this
is  what  we  have  if  we
take  a  look  at  our  members
you  can  see  that  there  is
a  super  admin  so  what  in
the  world  is  a  super  admin
well  a  super  admin  is  a
person  that  has  full  control
over  that  group  so  this  person
jj  rbv  w  e  x  k
i  is  a  super  admin  of
that  group  so  what  that  means
is  that  they  have  the  ability
to  delete  that  group  and  when
you  are  a  super  admin  you
have  full  control  over  that  group
there  are  four  different  membership  states
there's  super  admin  which  means  that
you  are  basically  god  you  can
do  whatever  you  want  to  this
group
you  can  delete  people  you  can
do  whatever  you  want  basically  you
can  delete  the  group  and  that's
a  big  thing  admin  which  allows
you  to  update  your  group  and
allow  you  to  accept  kick  promote
delete  ban  or  promote  members  and
then  they  have  members  which  allows
you  to  actually  have  a  regular
group  member  they  don't  have  the
ability  to  do  anything  they  cannot
accept  join  requests  stuff  like  that
and  then  they  have  the  join
request  mode  which  basically  is  a
when  a  user  wants  to  join
they  need  to  be  accepted  so
you  have  to  say  yes  i
will  accept  you  as  a  part
of  a  group  and  that's  how
you  know  the  different  states  if
that  makes  sense  so  if  we
go  to  our  user  management  we
look  for  the  jjr  person  if
we  go  into  accounts  i  have
a  bunch  of  usernames  here  because
i've  been  doing  a  lot  of
testing  on  my  end  but  if
i  look  for  jj  let  me
see  i  think  it's  jj  let
me  take  a  look
members  name  jj  members  name  jjrb
jjrb  well  that  person  let  me
see  jj  i  have  71  accounts
so  you  can  see  i  have
a  bunch  of  accounts  because  i've
been  doing  a  lot  of  testing
on  my  end  for  my  own
stuff  and  nakama  is  being  difficult
so  let  me  refresh  jjrb
well  apparently  jj  doesn't  exist  within
my  vast  number  of  people  so
i'm  not  sure  why  it  did
that  but  that's  okay  there's  probably
a  master  account  that  it's  using
actually  it's  right  here  jjrb  right
here  so  i'm  not  sure  why
it  used  this  specific  one  unless
i  logged  in
and  created  it  with  device  authentication
which  is  possible  but  that's  okay
we'll  figure  that  out  in  a
minute  but  that's  basically  how  we
create  a  group  now  you  can
see  we  also  printed  out  a
group  as  well  so
you  can  see  here  we  have
our  creator  id  which  is  right
here  the  creator  id  is  db
so  this  is  the  creator  id
so
our  creator  is  jj  so  we
must  have  logged  in  with  device
authentication  which  means  i  probably  didn't
reset  my  client  authentication  stuff  so
let  me  take  a  look  at
that  real  quick  my  apologies  i
um  may  not
have  reset  some  of  my  code
so  that  it  worked  properly  did
user  authentication  instead  of  our  um
device  authentication  so  my  guess  is
that's  probably  what  it  is  so
if  i  go  to  log  in
yeah  right  here  i'm
doing  a  unique  device  id  right
here  and  i'm  logging  in  with
that  socket  connection  so  that's  what's
going
on  here  so  what  i'm  gonna
do  is  i'm  gonna  control  k
to  comment  that  out  and  i'm
going  to  go  ahead  and
log  in  with  my  username  so
now  i'm  gonna  go  in  here
and  i'll  reset  this  because  it's
going  to  be
kind  of  difficult  to  have  a
group  that  uh  exists  that's  not
tied  to  an  actual  user  so
i'll  go  ahead
and  do  that  i'll  refresh  and
then  we're  going  to  recreate  that
group  just  because  it  makes  more
sense
so  i'll  say  test  group  description
this  is  a  test  group  and
we'll  go  ahead  and  create  that
group  now  if  we
take  a  look  at  our  nakama
console  you  will  see  that  because
this  was  created  by  test  that
person  is  the
super  admin  so  whoever  creates  the
group  gets  super  admin  status  now
in  order  to  add  users  it's
actually
relatively  easy  all  we  need  to
do  is  go  in  to  our
project  here  and  you  can  see
right  here  we  have  the
ability  to  create  a  group  so
we'll  just  go  ahead  and  duplicate
this  and  we  will  come  down
here  and  we'll
right  click  disconnect  we're  going  to
go  in  here  connect  and  say
on  add  user  we'll  say  add
underscore
user  underscore  to  group  like  so
button  down  and  we'll  go  ahead
and  connect  that  and  i'm  going
to
rename  this  to  add  user  to
group  so  with  this  for  us
to  be  able  to  add  users
to  group  it's  actually
really  really  easy  all  we  need
to  do  is  pass  in  the
group  id  that  we  want  to
add  ourselves  to  so
unfortunately  we  have  to  actually  pull
that  user  identifier  so  if  you
look  at  this  you  can  see
inside  of  our  groups  we  have
a  user  id  right  here  this
is  the  identifier  that  we  need
to  give  them
to  be  able  to  be  able
to  add  ourselves  to  that  group
so  if  we  come  in  here
and  copy  this  we  can
come  down  here  go  back  into
godot  and  then  basically  just  say
await  client  dot  join  group  async
and  then  do  session  comma  and
then  we'll  just  pass  in  that
group  identifier  now  if  we  come
in  here  and
we  hit  play  you'll  see  in
a  second  we'll  go  ahead  and
log  in  as  test  two  we
will  type  test  i  mean  it
doesn't  really  matter  and  you  can
see  the  text  here  is  wrong
but  that's  okay  we'll  click  create
group
which  is  technically  add  group  and
you'll  see  that  we  get  an
authorization  token  right  here  we  got
a  404
group  not  found  so  my  guess
is  that  i  have  the  wrong
identifier  go  to  group  group  id
i  do  so  we'll  go
ahead  and  copy  that  and  we'll
go  back  here  we'll  change  this
guy  like  so  paste  ctrl  s
and  the  nice
thing  about  godot  is  that  if
you  uh  just  change  the  code
in  here  you  can  just  click
that  and  you  can  see
that  it  should  work  and  that's
because  godot  is  a  non -compiled
language  so  you  can  actually  get
away
with  changing  it  and  re -executing
the  code  so  now  if  you
look  at  members  you  can  see
test  two  is  now  a
member  now  you  might  be  wondering
okay  so  anybody  can  join  my
group  yes  anyone  can  join  your
group  as
long  as  it  is  public  if
it's  not  public  then  you  have
to  be  approved  so  that's  where
the  difference
comes  in  so  if  i  come
in  here  i  remove  test  two
i  go  to  details  and  i
change  this  to  not  open  and
i
save  it  now  if  i  go
ahead  and  i  hit  create  group
or  i  guess  connect  to  the
group  you  can  see  that  there
is  a  join  request  and  that
means  that  i  have  to  approve
that  before  they  can  be  a
part  of  the  group
so  the  question  is  how  do
you  actually  accept  that  join  request
well  to  accept  a  join  request
what  you
need  to  do  is  you  need
to  come  in  here  and  actually
code  out  a  small  subroutine  first
thing  first  i'm
going  to  come  in  here  and
change  this  to  add  join  group
like  that  and  then  i'm  going
to  go  ahead  and
duplicate  this  guy  drag  this  guy
down  like  so  and  i'm  going
to  say  add  user
to  group  like  so  and  if
i  just  hit  enter  that  will
help  with  formatting  this  button  a
little  bit  better
now  we'll  pull  this  name  parameter
to  allow  ourselves  to  actually  you
know  go  from  there  and  this
should
probably  be  called  join  group  so
it'll  be  fine  i  guess  for
now  but  it's  just  something  i'm
not  a  huge
fan  of  but  that's  okay  so
we'll  go  ahead  and  click  node
right  click  disconnect  connect  and  then
we'll  go
ahead  and  create  that  little  function
there  now  to  accept  a  join
request  you  need  to  be  able
to  list
your  groups  or  your  users  inside
of  that  group  and  that's  really
easy  to  do  we  can  basically
just  say  var
users  is  equal  to  await  client
dot  list  group  users  async  like
that  we  can  pass  in  our
session  token
and  then  we  can  pass  in
our  group  id  now  our  group
id  is  right  here  so  we'll
go  ahead  and  copy  that  and
paste  it  and  then  we'll  hit
comma  and  then  we  can  actually
have  a  different  state  so  this
is  where  that
one  two  or  i  guess  zero
one  two  and  three  is  useful
if  you  wanted  to  you  could
list  everyone
that  is  a  member  of  the
group  everyone  that's  waiting  to  join
the  group  and  anybody  that's  a
super  user  or  an  admin  just
by  changing  this  from  zero  through
three  in  our  case  we're  going
to  be
grabbing  all  the  people  that  are
awaiting  for  their  joins  you  can
see  the  state  is  three  so
we  will  go
ahead  and  do  that  and  then
all  we  need  to  do  is
come  in  here  and  say  for
user  in
users  dot  group  underscore  users  colon
var  you  is  equal  to  user
dot  user  and  then  await  client
dot  add  group  users  async
async  pass  in  our  session  right
here  comma  what  our  group  id
is  which  in  this  case  is
this  guy  right
here  so  we'll  pass  that  guy
in  comma  and  then  we'll  pass
in  you  and  now  we'll  go
ahead  and  add
that  person  so  now  if  i
refresh  and  i  go  add  user
to  group  so  if  i  submit
i  log  in  as  the  test
user
and  i  click  add  user  to
group  you'll  see  that  we  got
an  error  here  unable  to  convert
uh  argument  three
to  pack  string  array  so  you
is  not  correct  so  let's  take
a  look  at  what  you  is
real  quick  i  don't  think
there's  really  an  easy  way  to
handle  this  without  going  bracket  bracket
and  then  passing  in  dot  id
and  then  just  using  their  id
i  think  that  that  will  work
it's  not  the  most  ideal  way
to  fix  it
but  if  i  log  in  i
hit  add  user  you  should  see
a  nice  request  here  and  then
we'll  go  ahead  and  refresh
this  and  you  can  see  that
they  are  now  a  member  and
that's  because  when  we  built  the
group  we  made  it  a
private  group  now  you  might  be
wondering  is  there  a  way  for
us  to  make  a  group  private
or  public
through  code  right  so  that  way
it  doesn't  have  to  happen  immediately
on  start  and  the  answer  to
your
question  is  yes  you  can  actually
do  that  pretty  easily  all  you
need  to  do  is  come  in
here  go  in  here
let's  grab  this  make  it  slightly
bigger  again  the  group  section  is
going  to  be  very  large  for
this  so
we'll  add  in  a  check  box
here  like  so  and  we'll  call
it  open  like  that  and  then
we're  going  to  add
in  a  toggle  switch  so  i'll
just  put  this  right  here  for
right  now  we'll  call  it  open
that's  fine
and  then  we'll  go  ahead  and
say  on  button  down  or  i
guess  on  toggled  we'll  toggle  this
on  our  control
node  and  basically  when  it  gets
toggled  it'll  show  you  yes  or
no  so  we'll  say  await  client
dot  update
group  asynchronously  we'll  pass  in  our
session  token  comma  our  group  id
which  is  this  guy  right  here
and  we'll  talk  about  how  to
get  that  group  id  uh  through
code  in  a  second  comma  and
then
the  name  of  the  group  which
i'll  pass  in  null  because  i
don't  want  to  change  it  and
then  we'll
pass  in  toggled  underscore  on  like
that  and  you'll  see  that  if
i  come  in  here  and  i
submit  and  then  i
click  open  you'll  see  if  we
refresh  our  nakama  instance  here  so
we'll  refresh  this  page  you'll  see
it's  not  open  if  we  close
it  it  should  hopefully  do  it
real  quick  maybe  not  let's  take
a  look  let's
do  a  break  point  here  i
could  just  be  crazy  so  if
i  come  in  here  toggle  response
code  400  spec  specify  at
least  one  field  to  update  let's
see  if  we  come  in  here
comma  p  name  p  description
variant  null  so  null  comma  description
null  comma  avatar  null  comma  language
tag  en  comma  now  this  is
how  you
update  any  of  your  parameters  by
the  way  so  now  we  have
our  p  open  i  think  that's
why
toggled  on  and  you  can  see
here  we  have  null  null  null
so  this  is  the  username  right
the  name  of  the  group
the  description  of  the  group  and
the  whether  or  not  it's  open
or  not  so  you  can  actually
really  play
around  here  and  update  any  of
these  values  so  now  if  we
hit  play  in  theory  it  should
just  work  so  we'll
come  in  here  submit  we  do
that  and  then  we  take  a
look  at  our  group  here  we
refresh  you'll  see  that
open  is  now  on  if  we
set  it  to  off  and  we
refresh  you'll  see  that  it  is
now  closed  so  that's  how  you
can
open  and  close  and  that's  really
how  you  can  update  any  of
these  values  so  if  i  came
in  here  if  i  come
back  to  godot  here  and  i
grab  my  description  i  believe  that's
name  description  avatar  url  so  if
i  name  this  the
strong  gamers  and  then  i  change
the  description  to  we  are  the
strong  gamers  exclamation  point
if  i  come  in  here  and
i  hit  this  little  toggle  here
well  our  session  got  dc'd  so
let  me  refresh  this  guy  real
quick  let  me  re -log  in
and  then  i'll  change
it  so  now  it's  going  to
be  open  and  the  titles  and
everything  has  been  changed  strong  gamers
we  are  the
strong  gamers  so  that's  how  you
can  update  those  values  now  again
typically  you  wouldn't  use  a  toggle
switch  to  do  this  i'm  just
showing  you  guys  how  to  do
that  so  i  can  show  you
the  open  and  close
really  quickly  you  can  see  now
it's  closed  so  that's  how  you
can  update  that  group  visibility  that's
how  you  can  update  the  group
values  information  values  for  your  group
now  something  else  that's
pretty  big  and  pretty  important  to
know  is  how  to  actually  list
groups  so  nakama  uh  groups  are
a  resource  like  anything  else  right
so  you  can  actually  list  them
and  index  them  and  pull  back
information
using  them  so  what  does  that
mean  well  that  means  that  you
can  use  what's  called  list  groups
asynchronously  to  actually  list  out  your
groups  so  if  i  come  in
here  i  can  show  you  guys
how  that  works
so  i'm  going  to  right  click
add  in  a  panel  like  so
i'll  drag  this  guy  over  here
like  this
and  i  will  make  an  h
box  container  or  i  guess  it'd
be  a  v  box  container  like
so  and  i'll  make  that  full
rect  so  that  way  it  maximizes
the  full  screen  now  granted  that
being  said  we  only  have  one
group  right
now  so  we  kind  of  need
to  make  multiple  groups  for  us
to  be  able  to  see  them
all  but  we  can  at  least
show  how  that  works  so  if
we  come  in  here  i  grab
this  add  user  to  group  button
i  duplicate  it  bring
it  down  here  and  i  type
list  groups  like  so  and  then
i'm  going  to  grab  this  description
duplicate  it
pull  it  down  here  and  this
is  going  to  be  group  query
like  so  i'll  change  this  to
list  groups
and  i'll  change  this  to  group
query  now  what  we  can  do
is  hit  ctrl  s  we  can
go  into  scripting
we  can  grab  our  list  group
go  to  node  right  click  disconnect
right  click  connect  and  connect  it
now  what  we  could  do  when
we  want  to  list  our  groups
is  we  can  set  up  a
limit  so  we  can  say  var
limit  is  equal  to  let's  say
10  now  we  don't  have  10
groups  to  list  but  we'll  use
that  as  a  default
value  then  we'll  say  var  result
is  equal  to  await  client  dot
list  groups  async  now  you'll  need
to
pass  in  your  session  just  like
usual  and  then  you'll  need  to
pass  in  some  kind  of  name
that  you're  trying  to
search  up  now  this  is  a
variant  so  of  course  you  can
you  know  get  back  whatever  you're
looking  for
so  in  my  case  i'm  going
to  hit  dollar  sign  group  query
dot  text  and  that'll  let  me
have  that  limit
and  then  we'll  pass  in  our
limit  which  by  the  way  does
default  to  10  now  they  have
a  cursor  value  and
that  cursor  value  allows  you  to
say  i  want  the  next  10
so  think  of  it  kind  of
like  this  when  you
do  your  query  you're  going  to
pull  back  the  first  10  but
what  happens  if  the  person  doesn't
see  the
group  that  they  want  on  the
first  10  well  that's  where  the
cursor  value  comes  in  so  you
can  hit  zero
make  that  cursor  value  of  zero
language  tag  will  allow  you  to
pick  a  language  in  my  case
i'm  going  to  do  en
and  again  you  don't  have  to
do  that  but  it's  going  to
filter  out  any  groups  that  are
not  english  you  can  see
right  here  language  en  so  that's
going  to  allow  you  to  have
that  limiting  factor  right  because  if
they're
spanish  you  don't  want  to  necessarily
show  them  up  if  they're  looking
for  an  english  group  if  they
speak  english
not  spanish  it's  going  to  be
a  problem  and  then  you  can
look  up  members  which  allows  you
to  pick  members  i'm  going  to
pass  in  null  for  that  and
then  you  could  choose  whether  or
not  it's  an  open  group  or
not  so  a  lot
of  times  when  you're  doing  groups
you  might  want  to  check  to
see  if  it's  a  public  group
not  a  private
group  because  sometimes  if  you  have
a  group  like  a  guild  and
you  don't  want  people  to  see
your  guild
you  probably  should  make  sure  that
that  is  false  or  true  depending
on  your  use  case  so  i'll
make  it  true
and  that's  pretty  much  everything  that
you  need  to  know  here  now
with  this  we  should  be  relatively
good  to  go  so  now  we
basically  will  have  our  results  we
can  say  for  group  in  result
dot  groups
like  that  and  then  we  can
basically  come  in  and  print  out
our  groups  so  you  can  see
that  we  can  go  print
group  dot  name  like  that  and
from  here  we  should  be  relatively
good  to  go  so  now  we
can  hit  play
we  can  log  in  as  test
we  can  come  in  here  and
say  i  believe  our  group  name
is  strong  gamers  so  we  can
say  strong  and  list  groups  and
it  should  come  back  well  it's
not  happy  so  that's  not  a
good  thing
our  p  cursor  query  parameters  strong
that's  fine  nakama  serialize  escape
cannot  convert  argument  one  from  int
to  string
i  wonder  if  it's  mad  because
our  cursor  is  an  int  i
think  there's  an  issue  here  with
how  they  have  their
stuff  set  up  so  what  if
we  come  back  here  and  we
do  null  instead  so  if  we
come  in  here
null  just  to  see  if  that
fixes  the  problem  so  we'll  come
in  here  we'll  type  strong
and  it's  still  mad  oh  that's
because  i  didn't  log  in  so
that's  fair  that's  understandable  so  we'll
log  in  we
we'll  say  strong  list  groups  and
you  can  see  that  we  get
a  400  the  error  name  filter
cannot  be  combined
with  any  other  filter  so  it
looks  like  according  to  nakama's  documentation
you  can  combine  them  but  i
guess  you  can't  inside  of  here
so  let's  try  that  and  see
if  that  fixes  it  because  according
to  our
documentation  you  can  do  this  but
i  guess  we  can't  so  let's
try  that
so  we'll  hit  list  groups  and
you  will  see  that  we  get
an  authorization  bearing  right  here  i
don't  know
if  that  came  back  with  really
anything  so  let  me  see  what
happens  if  i  list  groups  let's
see  what  our
result  comes  back  with  after  i
drop  a  breakpoint  here  and  it
did  it  came  back  with  nothing
so  nakama
is  not  doing  what  i  want
it  to  do  because  of  course
it's  not  welcome  to  programming  let's
see  what  happens
if  i  do  capital  s  it's
probably  capital
case  sensitive  so  we'll  come  in
here  and  we'll  take  a  look
at  our  results  still  got  nothing
back  so
we'll  continue  through  what  happens  if
i  do  a  percent  sign  and
see  if  that  gives  us  something
back  now  because  it  might  be
that  it  needs  to  be  a
query  of  some  description  so  we
can  check  that  out
real  quick  yep  it  needs  to
be  a  query  so  you  can
see  it  pulled  back  the  one
that  we're  looking  for  so
it  pulled  back  our  group  so
when  you  do  a  text  just
be  aware  of  that  you're  going
to  need  to  make  it
into  an  actual  query  instead  so
you  need  to  add  that  percent
sign  at  the  end  so  that's
just  something
to  keep  in  mind  now  you'll
see  when  i  hit  play  it's
going  to  print  out  strong  gamers
right  there
so  that's  basically  how  you  can
list  and  filter  your  groups  so
that  allows  us  to  see  those
groups
and  hunt  down  their  identifier  because
if  you  look  you  can  see
when  i  list  the  groups  you
can  see  when
i  come  in  here  and  i
take  a  look  at  my  results
here  the  group  i  come  back
with  has  their  identifier  right
here  so  if  you  know  where
their  um  if  you  know  their
name  you  can  pull  back  their
id  so  that's  how  we
would  populate  all  these  other  values
right  here  is  by  listing  it
and  then  pulling  back  that  group
information  now  since  we  can  pull
this  information  that  means  that  we
can  actually  come  in  here  and
use  that  info  on  our  panels
and  things  like  that  so  what
we  could  do  is  we  could
come  in  here  and  list  out
and  populate  their  information  and  populate
it  in  a  vbox  container  so
we  could  do  is  we  could
go  var  vbox  is  equal  to
vbox  container  dot  new  like  that
and  then  if  i  need  if
i  do  this  correctly
we  could  do  this  if  i
need  to  go  to  the  vbox
container  so  we  could  do  this
for  the  vbox  container  dot  new
and  then  we  could  come  in
here  and  do  the  same  thing
but  for  labels  so  we  can
say  label  so  var  name  label
is  equal  to  a  label  dot
new  like  that  and  then  name
label  dot  text  is  equal  to
if  we  take  a  look  at
this  right
here  we  can  go  name  so
it  would  be  group  dot  let's
take  a  look  at  this
what  is  result  dot  groups  let's
see  results  dot  groups  so  it's
going  to  come  back  with  this
so  then
it  would  be  dot  name  like
that  and  then  we  could  say
vbox
dot  add  child  and  then  we
could  add  our  name  label  as
a  part  of  that  child  and
then  we  can  come
in  here  and  say  dollar  sign
v  box  and  we  can  find
out  which  panel  is  ours  which
arguably  we  should
come  up  with  a  better  naming
convention  here  but  that's  fine  dot
add  child  and  we  could  add
in  our
vbox  right  here  like  that  and
that  would  allow  us  to  effectively
add  it  as  a  child  for
our  project  and
then  if  we  refresh  this  in
theory  providing  that  this  is  going
to  work  and  i  don't  know
if  it's  going
to  work  this  is  kind  of
me  coding  this  a  little  bit
off  the  cuff  we  can  hit
list  groups  and  you  can
see  that  we  now  have  strong
gamers  there  so  that's  something  that
we  can  actually  do  and  pull
back
their  information  so  that  could  be
really  useful  for  us  to  set
up  for  like  a  selection  system
or
something  like  that  and  speaking  of
that  what  we  could  do  is
we  could  come  in  here  and
say  var  hbox
is  equal  to  hbox  container  dot
new  like  so  and  then  we
can  do  hbox  dot  let's  see
if  we  bring  this  down
here  instead  of  doing  vbox  dot
add  we  can  do  hbox  and
then  we  could  add  our  vbox
dot  add  child  hbox  dot  add
child  hbox  like  so  and  then
what  that  means  is  that  we
could  add  in  a
button  and  i  know  this  is
kind  of  weird  because  i'm  actually
coding  a  component  instead  of  doing
it  the  other  way  but  one
of  the  big  things  that  people
have  asked  me  is  if  you
could  actually  do  it
this  way  and  i  want  to
cover  that  and  show  you  guys
yeah  you  can  actually  build  interface
elements
inside  of  code  and  then  actually
have  it  exist  so  that's  kind
of  what  i'm  showing  here  so
if  we  come
in  here  and  say  h  var
button  is  equal  to  button  dot
new  like  so  then  we  can
come  in  here  and  do  button
dot  text  is  equal  to  select
group  like  that  and  then  we
can  come  in  here  and  say
h
box  dot  add  child  button  like
that  and  then  we  can  add
that  h  box  and  that  should
allow  us  to  have
all  of  that  information  that  we
were  looking  for  before  right  here
so  if  we  hit  submit  list
groups  you
can  see  we  have  a  button
right  here  so  now  we  can
basically  connect  its  on  button  click
right  here  so  you
can  see  if  we  can  see
button  dot  button  down  like  that
dot  dot  connect  and  then  we
could  just  say  and  here
we  could  call  out  a  function
so  if  i  come  in  here
and  say  funk  on  group  select
button  down  and  i  can  pass
in  the  group
like  that  and  i  can  do
dot  connect  and  we  can  do
what's  called  binding  and  binding  is
actually  really  cool  so  we  can
say  on  group  select  button  like
that  dot  bind  and  then  i
can  bind  parameters  so  i  can
actually  come  in  here  and  bind
group  and  now  if  we  come
in  here  and  we  print  out
that  group
you'll  see  providing  that  we  did
this  correctly  and  i  know  that
this  is  like  way  beyond  what
the  actual
tutorial  is  but  i  think  that
this  is  pretty  cool  so  i
figured  i  would  show  it  off
if  we  do  this  we  can
come  in  here  and  list  our
groups  and  then  select  a  group
and  you'll  see  that  it  passes
in  that  information
right  there  it  binds  the  parameters
so  you  could  actually  come  in
here
and  set  a  selected  group  parameter
right  here  and  set  a  selected
group  parameter  right  here  and  there
you  go  it  would  actually  work
so  what  we  could  do  is
we  could  come  in  here  and
say  all  the  way  up  here
set  our
var  selected  group  and  then  we
could  come  down  here  and  just
say
selected  group  is  equal  to  group
like  that  and  then  we  could
come  in  here
and  do  i  believe  it's  group
dot  id  so  you  could  come
in  here  and  go
selected  group  dot  id  like  that
copy  this  bad  boy  go  like
this  paste  and  paste  and  paste
and  then  you  would
be  able  to  effectively  update  the
values  in  there  without  needing  to
actually  have  that  data  so  if
i  come  in  here  i  list
my  groups  well  first  i  need
to  actually  hook  up  my  session
really  quick  so  if  i
submit  that  there  we  go  i
list  my  groups  i  select  it
now  i  have  that  selected  i
can  come  in  here  and  do
a
open  and  you  will  see  that
if  i  come  in  here  and
i  refresh  this  you'll  see  that
that  worked  and  that's
that's  because  we  bound  that  parameter
right  here  well  if  i  could
find  it  right  here  to  actually
work  so  that's  a  way  that
we  can  go  about  making  a
group  selection  system  relatively  simple  and
that's
how  we  can  actually  list  our
groups  as  well  so  i  know
that  that's  kind  of  a  complicated
way  to  show  it  but  i
figured  that  it  was  an  interesting
way  to  approach  it  and  i
figured  you  guys  would  appreciate  that
so  now  the  question  is  what
if  we
want  to  promote  a  user  or
maybe  demote  a  user  or  kick
or  ban  a  user  from  our
group  well  in  order  to  do
that  first  we  need  to  actually
get  the  user  id  of  that
person  so  you  can  see  here
this  person  is  a
member  and  we  want  to  get
that  user  id  back  so  if
we  come  back  to  godot  here
and  we  go  ahead  and  come
down  here  we  need  to  basically
get  a  username  go  and  fetch
their  id  and  then  basically  promote
or
demote  that  person  so  what  i'm
gonna  do  is  i'm  gonna  right
click  my  panel  i'm  gonna  add
in  a  line  edit
like  so  i'm  gonna  drag  this
guy  down  here  we'll  go  like
this  make  it  about  i  don't
know  about  that  big
we'll  come  in  here  we'll  say
user  user  to  manage  we'll  say
and  then  we'll  come  in  here
and  hopefully
we  won't  run  out  of  space
if  we  do  we'll  figure  something
out  but  let's  right  click  add
in  a  child
node  let's  add  in  a  button
we'll  add  in  a  button  for
promoting  right  here  like  so  and
if  i
think  about  it  for  a  second
with  groups  we  need  to  promote
demote  kick  and  ban  somebody  and
then  also
leave  that  group  so  we'll  need
to  figure  out  a  way  to
give  ourselves  a  little  bit  more
space  here
because  i'm  running  out  so  maybe
i  can  drag  this  guy  up
butt  it  up  a  little  bit
closer  drag  this  guy
down  give  ourselves  a  little  bit
more  space  but  we  can  promote
duplicate  kick
demote
and  then  i  believe  we  would
need  to  ban  somebody
and  then  finally  the  last  interaction
that  we  need  to  do  is
to  actually  come  in  here  and
leave  so  we  could  just  come
over  ah  goodness  we're  running  out
of  space  here  we  have  so
much
functionality  here  it's  actually  hard  to
make  the  space  so  we'll  drag
this  guy  down  a  tiny  bit
maybe
give  ourselves  a  bit  more  space
over  here  drag  this  guy  over
like  so  there  we  go  and
we  can  change  this
one  to  leave  group  like  that
now  when  we  want  to  promote
a  user  let's  change  the  name
of  this  to  promote  user
kick  user  demote  user  and  ban
user  like  that  and  then  leave
free  so  i'm  going  to  go
ahead  and  grab  promote  user  and
i'm  going  to  change  my  line
edit  to  user  to
manage  and  then  i'll  click  on
promote  user  we're  going  to  go
ahead  and  connect  that  to  our
nakama
controller  here  we'll  come  down  here
and  we'll  basically  go  ahead  and
promote  a  user  so  first
things  first  we  need  to  actually
get  our  user  account  now  unfortunately
you  need  to  actually  go  and
fetch
that  user  account  so  first  we'll
say  var  user  is  is  type
nakama  api  dot  api
users  is  equal  to  await  client
dot  get  users  async  and  then
we  can  come  in  here  and
go  session  so  we
could  pass  in  that  session  and
then  we  need  to  pass  in
ids  so  when  you  do  this
you  can  pass  in  ids  or
usernames  in  our  case  we're  going
to  pass  in  a  username  but
you  can  pass  in  their  actual
um  id  as  well
so  i'm  just  going  to  pass
in  a  blank  and  then  for
the  username  i'll  just  pass  in
a  single  parameter
and  that's  going  to  be  dollar
sign  user  to  manage  dot  text
comma  and  you'll  see  that  they
also  have
a  facebook  id  in  this  case
we'll  pass  in  null  we  don't
really  have  a  facebook  id  to
manage  a  user
but  they  do  separate  that  out
and  i'm  not  really  sure  why
they  do  that  but  that's  a
thing  so  it's  just
something  to  keep  in  mind  now
what  we  can  do  is  say
for  you  in  users  dot  users
and  that's  a  really
bad  way  so  we'll  say  result
and  then  we'll  just  do  result
dot  users  that's  going  to  be
a  little  bit
better  than  what  we're  doing  right
now  now  once  we  do  this
we  have  the  actual  user  information
so
that's  how  you  pull  back  that
user's  information  so  you  can  actually
just  do  you  dot  id  and
that  will
be  their  identification  right  that'll  be
their  actual  information  so  what  we
can  do  is  we  can  come
in  here  and  promote  that  user
so  we'll  come  in  here  and
say  await  client  dot  promote  user
and  group  async
you  can  pass  in  our  session
token  and  then  we  can  pass
in  our  group  id  so  in
our  case  that's  going  to  be
our  selected  group  dot  id  comma
and  i  believe  it's  selected  group
dot  id  let  me  double  check
really  quick  because  sometimes  i  forget
things  it  is  and  then  we
have  to  pass  in  a  user
identifier
so  that's  going  to  be  u
dot  id  like  that  and  now
if  we  go  ahead  and  hit
play  you'll  see  in  a  second
that  if  i  connect  to  this
and  then  i  list  my  groups
i  select  my  group  and  then
i  type  in
test  two  and  i  click  promote
well  we  have  an  error  so
the  error  is  cannot  convert  argument
three  from
string  to  a  packed  array  and
that's  because  this  can  be  a
group  of  users  it's  not  actually
just  one
group  it's  actually  multiple  people  so
we  can  go  ahead  and  do
that  and  then  try  it  again
so  it's
because  we  need  we  can  actually
have  multiples  of  somebody  so  we'll
go  like  that  we'll  submit  we'll
list  our  groups  select  group  test
two  we'll  promote  that  person  you'll
see  that  that  looks  like  that
was  successful  we'll  head  back  to
our  nakama  console  we'll  refresh  and
you  will  see  that  this  person
is  now
an  admin  so  that's  huge  because
it's  going  to  allow  us  to
be  able  to  create  admins  and
now  if  we  click  it  a
second  time  you'll  see  if  we
refresh  they  are  now  a  super
admin  that  means  that  they  can
delete  this
group  if  they  want  to  now
the  question  might  be  okay  so
i  can  promote  users  how  do
i  demote  them
right  well  if  we  come  in
here  we  go  in  right  here
we  go  into  demote  user  button
down  let's  connect  that
real  quick  we  come  in  here
and  basically  copy  and  paste  this
code  so  we'll  just  copy  this
guy
paste  it  and  instead  of  promote
we  can  just  pass  in  demote
easy  enough  and  same  thing  for
kick  user
right  we  could  just  kind  of
bring  that  in  and  let's  do
band  user  as  well  right  so
we'll  just  bring  that
in  as  well  if  we  copy
this  guy  we  can  copy  paste
and  paste  because  they're  all  the
exact  same  functionality
so  we  can  come  in  here
and  say  kick  group  users  and
then  ban  group  users
and  now  if  i  refresh  this
you'll  see  if  i  submit  list
groups  select  my  group  test  two
i  go  demote
you'll  see  that  that  worked  if
we  come  over  here  we  refresh
our  users  right  here  you'll  see
that  they  are
now  an  admin  and  then  i
can  go  ahead  and  ban  a
user  and  you'll  see  non -existent
function  ban  groups
that's  probably  my  fault  group  users
async  and  it  looks  like  you
actually  can't  ban  a  user  so
we'll
remove  that  that's  my  fault  i
um  was  reading  the  documentation  earlier
but  it  looks  like  it  got
removed  so  you're  not  actually  able
to  ban  a  user  anymore  from
a  group  so  we'll  come  in
here  we'll
go  ahead  and  type  submit  list
our  groups  select  our  group  we'll
go  to  test  two  we'll  go
ahead  and  demote
the  user  so  you'll  see  if
we  refresh  they  are  an  admin
if  we  come  in  here  we
can  go  ahead  and  kick  them
and  then  if  we  refresh  you
will  see  they  have  been  removed
from  that  group  and  that's  basically
how  you
can  actually  manage  your  users  in
here  and  you  can  also  delete
a  group  and  leave  a  group
so  if  we  want
to  leave  a  group  we  can
come  in  here  and  go  into
our  stuff  here  we  can  click
on  leave  group  button  down
on  leave  button  down  we'll  connect
that  and  to  leave  a  group
it's  actually  relatively  simple
all  we  need  to  do  is
type
await  client  dot  leave  group  async
we'll  pass  in  our  session  and
then  we'll  pass  in  our  group
id  which
is  going  to  be  our  selected
group  id  now  this  will  allow
us  to  leave  our  group  but
the  problem  is  that
if  i  leave  my  group  i
will  actually  um  not  have  any
more  users  in  that  group  so
what  i'll  do  is  i'll
log  in  as  test  two  i
will  come  in  here  and  pass
in  my  group  name  if  i
remember  correctly  it's  if  we
list  groups  we  can  select  the
group  join  group  and  then  you
should  see  that  we  will  join
that  group  so
you'll  see  as  a  member  we
can  refresh  and  there  we  go
we're  in  that  group  and  now
we  can  come  in  here
and  say  leave  group  and  then
if  we  refresh  we  have  left
that  group  right  there  and  now
we  can  actually
uh  safely  delete  our  group  right
because  we  now  have  shown  that
that  section  works  that's  how  you
leave  a  group  it's  actually  really
easy  you  just  do  leave  group
asynchronously  so  now  what  happens  if
you  want  to  delete  a  group
well  we're  going  to  need  an
additional  button  for  that  so  let's
duplicate
our  leave  group  we'll  just  pull
it  down  here  i  guess  we're
kind  of  running  out  of  space
here  so  i'll  just
put  it  right  here  i'll  move
open  over  we'll  grab  leave  group
and  we'll  put  delete  group  now
in  order
to  delete  a  group  we'll  disconnect
this  connect  in  order  to  delete
a  group  it's  actually  really  simple
as  well  so  when  you  delete
a  group  all  you  need  to
do  is  type  client  await  client
dot  delete  group  async
and  then  you  can  pass  in
the  session  and  the  selected  group
dot  id  and  that's  literally  all
you  need  to  do  so  now
if  i  refresh  my  screen  here
i  log  in  as  test  the
super  admin  and  then
we'll  log  in  as  test  we'll
come  in  here  we'll  log  in
as  test  2  we'll  submit  we
will  go  ahead  and  hit
list  groups  we'll  select  that  group
we're  going  to  join  that  group
really  quick  and  remember  because
this  is  an  open  group  that
person  should  be  able  to  just
join
there  we  go  so  the  person
has  joined  and  now  you'll  see
if  i  go  in  as  test
2  right  here  and  i  go
ahead
and  i  click  delete  group  which
this  is  leave  group  but  it's
delete  group  in  um  our  code
you'll  see
request  has  returned  spot  response  400
group  not  found  or  you  are
not  allowed  to  delete  and  the
reason  why  is  because  that  person
does  not  have  the  capability  to
delete  this  group  you  can  see
it's
still  here  however  if  i  come
in  here  as  test  or  as
my  super  admin  and  i  log
in  and  i  click  list  groups
i
select  my  group  and  then  i
click  delete  group  you'll  see  if
we  go  back  to  groups  it
has  now  been  removed
and  that's  basically  everything  that  you
need  to  know  about  groups
now  when  it  comes  to  chats
which  is  actually  a  whole  feature
inside  of  nakama  you  can  actually
build  chat
rooms  right  inside  of  nakama  so
when  it  comes  to  chats  how
do  we  actually  get  that  to
work  well  first
things  first  we  are  majorly  out
of  space  so  i  am  going
to  hide  the  group  section  as
you  can  see  we
have  all  sorts  of  different  areas
here  where  we  can  actually  do
our  nakama  work  here  so  i'm
actually  just
going  to  come  in  here  and
just  start  hiding  a  lot  of
this  because  we're  running  out  of
space  here
so  i'll  hide  this  panel  and
this  panel  and  there  we  go
so  when  it  comes  to  chats
we  have  three  different
types  of  chats  and  we'll  talk
about  all  three  of  them  and
how  to  send  messages  and  stuff
like  that
but  we  have  three  different  chat
types  we  have  dynamic  rooms  group
chats  and  direct  chats  okay  and
we'll
talk  about  the  group  chats  when
we  get  there  but  one  of
the  big  ones  that  a  lot
of  people  like  is  the
dynamic  rooms  the  dynamic  rooms  is
basically  a  random  room  that  gets
created  for  temporary
for  a  temporary  time  span  and
it  only  stays  open  as  long
as  there  are  people  in  that
chat  room  so  the
nice  thing  about  it  is  let's
say  you  have  a  match  or
something  like  that  you  could  put
people  in  that
temporary  room  and  then  have  people
communicate  and  then  once  the  match
is  over  that  room  just  gets
dissolved  over  time  whereas  something  like
a  group  chat  that  stays  for
as  long  as  the  group  exists
and  then  they  also  have  direct
chats  which  is  basically  one -on
-one  communications  between  people
which  persist  once  again  forever  so
in  order  to  do  dynamic  rooms
let's  first  right  click  add  in
a  child
node  let's  add  in  a  panel
here  and  let's  make  it  about
this  big  now  we're  gonna  have
to  build  a  whole
chat  system  so  this  will  take
a  little  bit  of  time  so
what  i'm  gonna  do  is  i'm
gonna  right  click  add
a  child  node  i'm  gonna  add
in  a  button  i'm  going  to
right  click  add  a  child  node
add  in  a  line  edit  right
here  we're  going  to  make  the
line  edit  about  yay  big  give
or  take  if  my  mouse  will
let  me  we'll  do  that  we'll
add  in  a  button
again  providing  that  i  can  click
on  this  there  we  go  we'll
make  it  about  yay  big  and
for  our  line  edit  we'll  just
say
chat  name  like  that  and  then
we'll  come  in  here  and  say
join  chat  now  you  could  automate
this  as  soon  as  a  person
goes  into  a
match  you  could  actually  go  set
up  the  uh  room  name  and
automatically  have  them  join  but  in
this  case  we're  gonna  manually  do
it  that  way  you  guys  get
the  experience  of  how  to  make
this  look  at  it  all  so
you  can  turn  on  the  greenbar
it  works  so  what  we'll  do
is  we'll  change  this  to  join
chat  room  like  that  and  then
the  line  at  it
will  be  chat  name  like  that
and  then  i'm  going  to  come
in  here  go  over  here  button
down  and  then  i
will  hit  connect  now  when  we
want  to  join  a  chat  room
all  we  have  to  do  is
come  up  with  a  room  name
if  it's  persistent  if  it's  hidden
and  if  it  is  a  room
type  so  i  will  show  you
all  of  those  things
so  first  things  first  let's  go
var  channel  is  equal  to  await
socket  dot  join  chat  asynchronously
now  what  this  is  going  to
do  is  we're  going  to  have
a  target  now  that  target  is
what  the  name  of
that  chat  room  is  going  to
be  in  this  case  we'll  just
say  actually  we  already  have  a
title  right  here
right  so  dollar  sign  chat  name
dot  text  comma  and  then  you'll
see  that  we  have  an  int
type  so  what
does  that  actually  take  what  is
the  type  well  the  type  is
a  nakaba  socket  chat  type  or
a  channel  type
so  we'll  say  var  type  is
equal  to  nakaba  socket  dot  channel
type  dot  and  you'll  see  that
we  have
different  types  direct  direct  message  group
and  room  and  each  one  has
a  different  use  so  thankfully  the
code  is  basically  the  same  but
what  matters  is  if  it  is
going  to  be  a  room  if
it's  going  to  be
a  group  or  if  it's  going
to  be  a  direct  message  in
our  case  it's  going  to  be
a  room  so  i'm  going  to
come  in  here  and  say  type
comma  and  then  if  it's  persistent
so  in  our  case  we  don't
want  it  to  be
persistent  so  false  comma  and  then
if  it's  hidden  it  will  say
false  we  want  it  to  make
it  a  public
messaging  chat  so  people  can  actually
go  in  and  message  each  other
and  not  have  to  authenticate  or
be  added  to  that  chat  and
then  what  i'm  going  to  do
is  i'm  going  to  print  that
chat  information  so  print
channel  like  that  now  this  will
basically  print  out  our  chats  information
so  if  i  refresh  this  and
i
run  this  if  i  join  and
i  say  test  and  i  join
you'll  see  that  we  now  have
a  chat  that  is  right  here
you
can  see  it  has  the  id
one  it  has  id  here  it
says  there's  a  user  test  user
id  is  this  session  id  is
this
so  we  can  get  all  the
people  that  are  inside  of  that
chat  right  there  now  if  somebody
else  joins
test  to  submit  and  then  they
go  test  and  they  join  you
can  see  here  that  we  also
joined  channel  id  to
user  presence  session  this  status  user
test  so  we  just  got  back
that  user's  account  information  right
so  we  got  test  and  test
to  in  this  chat  with  each
other  and  that's  basically  what  these
guys  are
saying  here  now  in  order  to
send  a  message  you  need  to
actually  be  able  to  receive  that
message  right
so  let's  go  to  our  script
here  and  let's  scroll  all  the
way  up  to  the  top  and
the  reason  why  i'm
scrolling  all  the  way  up  to
the  top  is  because  we  need
to  subscribe  when  we  create  our
socket  to
the  ability  to  actually  get  messages
so  what  we  need  to  do
is  go  find  where  our  socket
gets  created
which  is  right  here  so  we'll
come  in  here  we'll  say  socket
dot  and  providing  that
godot  wants  to  be  nice  to
me  it  will  auto  complete  please
maybe  not  well  we'll  hit  dot
received  underscore
channel  underscore  message  dot  connect  like
that  and  then  we'll  pass  in
a  callable  so  what  this  is
going  to  be  is  it's  just
going  to  be  a  very  basic
function  that  prints  out  that  message
currently  at
least  so  we'll  say  funk  underscore
on  underscore  channel  on  channel
message  like  that  and  we'll  pass
in  a  message  now  this  could
be  a  type  if  you  want
it  to  be  which  is
going  to  be  a  nakama  api
dot  api  channel  message  like  that
and  then  we  can  just  go
ahead  and  print  that
message  and  there  we  go  now
we're  going  to  connect  that  message
so  we'll  just  pass  on  channel
message
like  that  and  that  will  actually
pass  that  to  this  guy  right
here  and  we'll  go  ahead  and
send  out  that
signal  now  when  we  do  our
message  when  we  want  to  send
a  message  we  need  to  actually
create  a  panel  for
that  so  let's  come  in  here
let's  right  click  our  panel  and
add  in  a  another  panel  like
so  i'm  going
to  drag  this  guy  over  here
make  it  about  this  big  give
or  take  it  we're  going  to
create  a  very  basic
message  block  system  so  it's  going
to  be  pretty  ugly  my  apologies
but  i  want  to  try  to
get  this  to
work  as  quickly  as  humanly  possible
so  what  i'm  going  to  do
is  i'm  going  to  put  in
a  line  edit  like  so
i'm  going  to  make  this  go
on  the  bottom  stretched  across  i'm
going  to  pull  this  back  right
click
add  a  child  node  we'll  add
in  a  button  i'm  going  to
snap  that  guy  right  in  the
bottom  right  where
we'll  make  it  about  if  i
can  click  on  it  about  yay
big  we'll  put  a  send  or
maybe  just  like  an  arrow
like  that  i  think  that'll  work
we'll  put  a  placeholder
chat  text  here  we'll  type  this
as  chat  text  we'll  make  the
panel  title  chat  and  then  we'll
make  the
button  submit
chat  like  that  i'm  going  to
go  ahead  and  right  click  add
any  child  node  and  i'm  going
to  add  in  a
i  am  brain  farting  on  what
it  is  it  is  a  text
edit  like  that  we'll  make  it
full  screen  so  full
rect  and  we'll  make  it  about
yay  big  that'll  go  ahead  and
make  it  so  that  it's  kind
of  scalable  and
you  know  easy  to  use  now
inside  of  here  i'll  scroll  down
and  i  will  do  auto  wrap
that's  fine  so  that  means
that  if  i  put  in  a
bunch  of  text  here  it's  going
to  auto  wrap  so  you  can
see  if  i  do  wrap  mode
boundary
it  will  go  ahead  and  wrap
that  and  then  i  will  turn
on  scroll  as  well  so  if
this  continues  so  we'll
ctrl  c  ctrl  v  we'll  paste
it  you'll  see  that  it's  going
to  scroll  we  also  want  to
we'll  want  to  shut
off  editable  and  i  think  that
will  work  because  i  think  this
is  placeholder  text  so  if  i
come  in  here
and  we  paste  this  text  in
this  will  allow  us  to  scroll
i'm  curious  if  we  can  make
it  follow
the  uh  actual  scrolling  but  i
don't  think  we  can  i  know
there's  a  way  to  do  it
it's  been  a  while  since
i've  done  it  but  i  think
i'll  just  go  ahead  and  skip
that  part  but  there  is  a
way  to  make  it  so  it
automatically  scrolls  to  the  bottom  but
that's  okay  right  now  so  this
is  basically  what  our  chat  setup
is
going  to  be  it's  going  to
be  relatively  simple  but  it's  going
to  be  something  that  we  can
at  least
use  now  i'm  going  to  grab
my  submit  chat  button  i'm  going
to  go  to  node  button  down
i'm  going  to  connect
that  to  my  submit  chat  button
now  when  we  want  to  do
a  message  right  we  want  to
send  a  message  we  can  come
in  here  and  say  var  await
socket  dot  write  chat  message  asynchronous
now  this  is  going  to  require
a  id  so  we  have  to
actually  have  some  kind  of  chat
name  in  this  case  i'm  just
going  to  go  ahead  and  grab
this  guy  right  here  copy  it
and  paste  it  it's  not  the
most  ideal  situation  because  once  you're
connected
to  that  channel  you  should  probably
just  be  connected  to  that  channel
right  instead  of
passing  in  this  value  here  but
we  can  basically  throw  a  value
up  at  the  top  and  basically
just
save  it  across  different  functions  and
that  would  solve  this  problem  but
for  right  now  we'll  go  ahead
and  do  this  and  then  we
need  to  pass  in  our  message
content  so  what  we  can  do
is  do  dollar  sign
chat  text  dot  text  like  that
now  i  think  we  should  probably
change  this  to  text  edit  instead
just  do
chat  text  box  that  way  we
actually  have  that  value  now  if
we  hit  play  and  we  go
ahead  and  hit  play
if  we  come  in  here  we
both  submit  join  test  test  number
two  submit  join  test  if  we
send  a  text
test  test  test  you'll  see  that
it  is  very  mad  at  us
cannot  convert  argument  to  from  string
to  dictionary
so  it's  going  to  require  a
dictionary  for  us  to  be  able
to  do  that  so  what  we
need  to  do  is  we  need
to  pass  in  an  actual  dictionary
of  objects  so  we  can  come
in  here  pass  in  this  dictionary
like  so  and  go  quote  message
colon  that  and  the  reason  why
we  have  to  do  this  is
because  we  can  actually
do  what's  called  emotes  right  and
emotes  are  sent  via  um  json
data  so  that's  the  reason  why
it  requires  it  to
be  a  dictionary  so  that  we
can  actually  send  over  emote  information
now  i'm  not  going  to  cover
that
just  because  uh  there's  a  whole
like  loading  emotes  and  stuff  like
that  that  you  need  to  do
and  that's
way  beyond  the  basics  of  this
tutorial  so  if  you  guys  want
to  look  at  that  you  guys
can  go  check  out
their  real -time  chatting  section  and
they'll  go  over  that  but  i'll
go  ahead  and  hit  submit  test
to  submit
join  test  join  test  test  send
and  you'll  see  that  we  actually
get  an  error  so  it  says
invalid  chat
identifier  so  what's  going  on  here
right  well  if  you  take  a
look  at  your  chat  here  if
we  take  a  look  at
our  chat  you'll  see  that  our
chat  actually  has  an  identifier  id2
you  see  that  so  when  you
have
a  chat  it  actually  has  an
identifier  associated  with  that  chat  and
so  you  don't  want  to  pass
in
the  title  of  the  chat  you
want  to  pass  in  the  identifier
you  can  see  that  we  have
a  channel  right  here
so  if  i  go  channel .id
we  can  go  ahead  and  refresh
this  guy  and  go  submit  test
submit  and  you'll  see  that
we  are  now  printing  out  and
you  will  see  that  we  have
an  id  right  here  i  added
channel  id  in  post  so
that  way  it  was  nice  and
quick  but  you  can  see  right
here  channel  id  is  two  dot
dot  dot  test  so  two  is
the
id  of  the  chat  and  test
is  the  actual  id  that  we
gave  it  so  we  need  to
pass  that  value  in  right  here
for
us  to  be  able  to  send
messages  so  what  we  can  do
is  we  can  come  in  here
copy  this  var  channel  go  all
the
way  up  to  the  top  and
go  var  current  channel  like  that
and  then  we  go  all  the
way  back  down  to  the
bottom  and  do  current  channel  is
equal  to  that  and  then  we'll
go  ahead  and  copy  this  we'll
paste  it  right
here  dot  id  and  then  we
can  go  ahead  and  do  current
channel  dot  id  right  here  as
well  now  what  that
will  do  is  that  it  should
allow  us  to  actually  send  it
to  the  proper  id  so  we'll
hit  submit  test  to
submit  test  join  test  join  test
send  and  you  should  see  right
here  we  no  longer  have  an
error  but  instead
we  have  an  actual  message  right
here  i  probably  should  not  have
used  the  word  test  i  should
probably  use  this  is  a  test
message  that  way  we  can  actually
see  what  it  is  and  you
can  see  here  that
i  send  a  message  and  you
see  right  here  channel  id  test
code  is  zero  content  message  this
is  a  test
message  and  that's  basically  how  we
can  send  and  receive  messages  now
the  nice  thing  is  that  if
since  we
typed  our  message  section  and  unfortunately
this  is  getting  pretty  large  so
i  might  want  to  abstract
some  of  this  out  but  if
we  go  to  right  here  where
our  on  channel  message  is  at
we  have  our  different
messages  that  we  can  message  information
here  that  we  can  actually  use
so  if  we  type  message  dot
you'll  see
that's  going  to  automatically  give  us
some  information  here  that  we  can
work  with  so  you  can  see
that  we
have  sender  id  username  all  sorts
of  information  so  the  nice  thing
is  i  can  come  in  here
and  i  can  go
dollar  sign  chat  text
box  dot  text  plus  equals  message
dot  user  name
plus  colon  space  plus  message  dot
and  then  if  we  take  a
look  there  should  be  a
content  dot  message  like  that
like  that  and  we  should  probably
also  go  ahead  and  pass  in
a  new  line  because  we  want
the  user  to
have  a  new  line  here  now
so  let's  try  this  var  content
is  equal  to  message  dot  content
and  then  i  wonder  if  content
dot  message  will  work  instead
okay  there  we  go  we'll  try
that  and  see  if  that  works
also  i'm  going  to  want  to
put  a  new  line  at  the
end  of  this
so  we'll  go  ahead  and  do
that  slash  n  for  a  new
line  that  way  every  time  somebody
sends  a  message  it's  going  to
be  a  new  lined  message
and  now  if  i  refresh  this
in  theory  this  should  work  so
we'll  go  ahead  and  do  submit
test  join
test  to  submit  test  join  test
send  and  it  is  very  unhappy
so  let's  take  a  look  you
can  see  the  content  here  is
a
string  data  so  it  looks  like
we're  going  to  need  to  json
parse  this  information  so  go  json
dot  parse  string
and  we'll  go  ahead  and  pass
that  in
and  there  we  go  and  that
should  fix  that  problem
basically  content  is  a  json  value
so  that's  something  that  i  didn't
think  about  i'm  talking  without
thinking  as  i'm  doing  this  tutorial
so  forgive  me  but  we  need
to  actually  parse  that  data  so
now  if  we  hit
send  you'll  see  test  test  test
this  is  a  test  message  like
so  test  to  this  is  a
test  message
and  that's  basically  how  you  could
do  a  very  basic  communication  system
so  now  the  question  is  okay
great  that's  fine  but  how  do
i  actually  do  group  chats  and
in  order  to  do
group  chats  what  we  need  to
do  is  we  need  to  come
in  here  and  we  need  to
go  ahead  and  grab  another
joint  chat  here  and  what  i'm
going  to  do  is  i'm  going
to  unhide  my  group  section  and
i  guess  i'll
just  move  it  over  so  we
have  a  little  bit  more  space
let's  grab  this  guy  we'll  drag
him  over  like
this  it's  getting  a  little  on
the  cramped  side  with  our  uh
setup  here  so  i  might  need
to  readjust  some
stuff  but  i  don't  think  i
can  fit  it  really  up  here
so  we'll  just  kind  of  push
it  over  here  and  that
should  just  work  i  mean  it's
a  little  tight  but  it  will
work  for  the  demonstration  we're  trying
to  do
here  so  if  i  grab  this
guy  here  i  right  click  disconnect
inspector  change  this  to  join  group
chat
like  so  when  you  want  to
do  a  group  chat  all  you
got  to  do  is  come  in
and  basically
i  move  this  guy  over  there
we  go  all  you  really  need
to  do  is  you  need  to
come  in  here
connect  your  button  down  so  go
ahead  and  connect  that  over  here
and  then  we  can  come  in
here  and
basically  just  grab  this  exact  code
right  here  it's  almost  a  duplication
right  it's  almost  exactly  the
same  we'll  just  drop  that  guy
in  there  and  all  we  really
need  to  do  is  come  in
here  and  when  we  do
our  join  socket  asynchronously  we  just
basically  need  to  pass  in  our
group  id  so  we'll  say  and
i
believe  we  have  a  group  if
i  remember  correctly  so  selected  group
.id  and  then  we  can  pass
in  type
for  persistence  we're  going  to  want
to  say  true  because  we  want
to  keep  that  group  around  right
and  then  we  want  it  to
be  persistent  and  we  also  want
to  change  this  to  a  type
group  chat  and  then
what  we  can  do  is  we
can  come  in  here  hit  play
come  over  here  submit  test  we
will  go  ahead  and  create  a
group  so  that  way  now  our
group  actually  exists  so  if  we
refresh  our  groups  i'll  have  to
re -log  in
because  this  is  another  recording  session
and  you  can  see  we  now
have  a  test  group  and  we
are  now  a
part  of  it  now  from  here
we  can  join  that  group  with
test  two  so  we'll  come  in
here  and  i  already  did
this  one  so  we'll  do  test
two  test  join  group  and  it
got  mad  at  me  because  our
selected  group  is  not
correct  and  that's  my  fault  so
that's  totally  fine  so  i  will
have  to  refresh  real  quick  so
we'll  say
submit  test  we  will  go  ahead
and  list  our  groups  we'll  select
our  test  group  we'll  do  test
to
list  our  groups  select  it  join
that  group  and  then  when  we
join  our  chat  we  can  just
join  group  chat
growing  group  chat  and  then  test
and  you  will  see  that  this
guy  now  gets  it  and  if
we  go  this  is  a  test
message  and  we  send  that  guy
you  can  see  that  that  message
gets  sent  now  you  might  be
going  okay
so  why  does  this  matter  right
what  is  the  benefit  of  a
group  chat  versus  a  dynamic  chat
well  where  a
group  chat  matters  and  why  it's
important  is  because  you  can  do
what's  called  listing  the  message  history
so  because  it's  a  persistent  chat
we're  going  to  be  able  to
pull  back  all  of  that  information
so  the  reason  why  that's  cool
is  because  we  can  come  in
here  and  we  can  say  okay
when  the  user  joins  a
group  which  we'll  have  to  scroll
down  here  to  right  here  and
we'll  need  to  go  ahead  and
come  in  here
and  list  out  that  information  so
we'll  say  far  result  is  equal
to  await  client  dot  list  channel
messages  asynchronous  we'll  pass  in  our
session  and  then  we'll  pass  in
our  currently  selected  groups
so  selected  group  dot  id  we
could  pass  in  a  limit  value
so  in  our  case  we'll  just
do  100  that's  a  very
decent  value  forward  basically  forward  is
forward  or  backwards  right  so  we
can  grab  the  oldest  or  the
newest  and  that's  what  forward  is
as  forward  is  the  newest  so
we'll  say  forward  so  we'll  say
true  comma
and  then  i  believe  they  have
a  cursor  value  as  well  and
cursor  is  if  i  remember  correctly
it's  defaulted
let's  double  check  really  quick  if
we  hit  comma  cursor  variance  is
null  so  cursor  allows  you  to
say  i
want  you  to  start  at  this
point  so  if  you're  picking  up
the  next  100  values  let's  say
you  have  500  messages
you  can  pass  in  number  200
and  then  it'll  grab  from  200
to  300  if  that  makes  sense
so  in  our  case  i'll
just  leave  that  as  null  because
it's  just  going  to  be  easier
for  us  to  work  with  it
now  we  can  go  for
our  message  in  result  dot  message
like  that  messages  like  that  and
then  we  can  basically  just  go
exactly
what  we  did  before  so  we
can  come  up  here  and  grab
if  you  remember  how  we  actually
parsed  out  our  data
which  arguably  i  should  move  this
down  closer  to  my  actual  message
functionality  so  let's  go  ahead  and
just  do  that  really  quick  we'll
come  down  here  and  just  drop
it  right  let's  see  this  is
group  stuff
this  is  chat  stuff  so  we'll
go  ahead  and  just  drop  it
right  there  and  that'll  just  kind
of  keep  it  within
the  group  area  so  that  way
i  can  basically  come  in  here
and  do  this  and  say  chat
room  code  right  here  and
that'll  give  me  somewhere  to  actually
look  at  this  now  what  we
could  do  is  we  could  basically
just  grab
this  copy  it  and  paste  and
that's  all  we  need  to  do
and  then  in  theory  this  should
just  work  so  now  if
we  hit  play  in  theory  if
we're  lucky  it  will  work  so
we'll  go  here  we'll  say  list
groups  select  group
join  group  chat  and  we  got
an  error  message  return  response  invalid
channel  id  so  we  have  a
failure  here
that  says  that  our  channel  id
is  incorrect  so  let's  see  join
chat  asynchronously  list  channel  messages  that
should  be  correct  is  it  printing
out  what  i  expect  let's  see
so  i  don't  think  that  this
worked  100  here  so
let's  try  submitting  list  groups  select
group  that  should  select  our  group
and  then  i  should  be  able
to  join  group  chat  but  it
did  not  take  it  so  the
question  is  is  it  because  i
failed  to  join  the  group  chat
or  did  it  fail  here  so
if  we  do  this  the  id
of  the  group
id  is  string  get  return  if
not  string  else  string  await  list
channel  messages  try  refresh  and  it's
going
to  run  through  that  real  quick
but  it  didn't  do  anything  as
expected  so  if  i  drop  a
breakpoint  here
what  is  result  result  is  an
object  id  cacheable  null  null  so
we  got  a  nakama  exception  invalid
channel  id
so  the  question  is  is  did
our  channel  get  saved  let's  go
ahead  and  take  a  look  at
nakama  really  quick
chat  messages  group  chat  no  messages
found  so  our  group  chat  just
doesn't  exist  so  that's  not  great
so
that  means  something  went  wrong  with
how  we  initialized  our  group  chat
i  think  okay  so  i
figured  out  the  issue  so  basically
when  we  do  our  list  channel
messages  async  we  need  to  actually
do  our
current  channel  dot  id  instead  so
when  we  do  our  join  chat
asynchronous  we  pull  back  a  channel
and  that's
the  channel  that  we're  currently  in
and  basically  we  need  to  go
and  list  those  message  right  here
and
then  i  have  a  section  here
for  messages  in  result  messages  if
the  message  content  does  not  contain
an  empty  so  if  for  some
reason  a  message  gets  in  there
that's  empty  when  we  try  to
parse  it  it's
going  to  break  so  i  have
this  little  if  statement  right  here
that  basically  just  checks  to  see
if  it's
empty  if  it  is  ignore  it
and  there's  no  reason  to  have
it  so  now  if  i  hit
play  you'll  notice  that  when  i
come  in  here  and  i  hit
submit  i  list  my  groups  i
select  my  groups  and  i  join
my  group  chat  you'll  see
i  pull  back  those  messages  and
that's  one  of  the  big  cool
features  of  nakama  is  that  it
keeps  track
of  all  of  that  information  because
this  is  after  we  removed  and
rebooted  the  system  right  it  actually
came  back  with  the  proper  messages
that's  basically  what  persistence  does  right
here  this  true  right
here  causes  it  to  be  saved
and  to  be  reusable  later  that's
one  of  the  big  cool  advantages
here
so  now  the  question  is  okay
so  how  do  i  do  peer
-to -peer  messaging  well  it's  not
technically  peer -to -peer
but  how  do  i  send  messages
directly  to  a  user  well  again
it's  relatively  simple  if  we  come
into  our
stuff  here  we  control  c  control
v  join  group  chat  and  then
instead  of  join  group  chat  we
have  a
join  direct  chat  i  go  ahead
and  grab  our  where  is  it
join  group  chat  right  here  and
i  change  this  to
join  direct  chat  like  that  we
can  come  in  here  disconnect  right
click  connect  and  connect  now  in
order  to  do  a  direct  chat
it's  actually  relatively  easy  it's  exactly
the  same  as  everything  else  you
come  in  here  you  go  join
chat  room  right  here  copy  it
come  down  here  paste  well  really
actually  we
probably  should  just  grab  this  to
be  honest  it's  going  to  save
us  a  bit  of  trouble  so
if  we  paste  this
guy  in  here  change  the  channel
type  to  direct  message  like  that
instead  of  having  a  selected  group
id
we  need  to  grab  the  user
id  in  terms  of  persistence  we
want  to  keep  true  we  also
want  to  keep  false  for
hidden  but  for  this  join  chat
asynchronous  we  can  go  ahead  and
pass  in  a  user  id  so
we  need  to  get  our
actual  user  identifier  and  the  easiest
way  to  do  that  is  by
using  the  get  users  asynchronous  call
if  you
remember  we  did  that  earlier  so
we'll  just  say  var  users  is
equal  to  await  client  dot  get
users  asynchronous
and  then  we'll  pass  in  our
session  and  we  need  to  pass
in  a  id  pack  string  array
and  then  the  user  name
that  we're  going  to  be  passing
in  so  in  our  case  i
think  if  we  take  a  look
at  our  user  interface  we
have  a  chat  name  we  could
probably  just  take  that  i  think
that  will  work  so  for  the
chat  name  what  i'll
do  is  i'll  just  pull  this
guy  which  is  chat  name  so
we'll  come  into  our  script  we'll
hit  dollar  sign  chat  name
dot  text
and  then  that  should  bring  back
our  users  so  now  we  know
that  it's  going  to  bring  back
one  user  and
that's  it  so  since  it's  going
to  bring  back  one  user  we
can  basically  just  do  if  users
dot  size
is  greater  than  zero  then  we
can  do  the  rest  of  this
bit  of  code  here  and  then
we  can  just  pass  in  and
say  users  bracket  bracket  zero  dot
id  and  that'll  pass  back  a
user  id  that  we  can  actually
communicate
with  so  now  in  theory  this
should  work  and  of  course  as
always  with  theory  it  doesn't  always
work  but
we'll  see  so  we'll  submit  as
test  we'll  submit  as  test  two
and  then  we'll  go  test  two
join  direct  chat
it's  mad  and  that's  because  users
came  back  let's  see  with  an
array  it  looks  like  it's  users
dot  users
so  that's  my  fault  so  we'll
say  users  dot  users  and  i
should  probably  just  do  this  as
results  then
or  perhaps  user  results  because  we
don't  want  to  mess  with  our
current  code  down  here  that  has
results
already  we'll  just  do  that  and
then  for  this  we'll  just  say
user  results  dot
users  bracket  bracket  zero  because  we
now  know  that  we  need  to
go  a  little  bit  deeper  than
what  we
expected  so  now  if  we  go
ahead  and  submit  test  two  join
direct  chat  now  we're  in  a
direct  chat  if  we  go
into  test  two  and  we  go
to  test  join  direct  chat  we
pass  test  in
okay  so  i  think  i  figured
out  what's  going  on  here  so
i  commented  this  out  just  so
we  could  check  it  out
but  what  i  think  is  going
on  here  is  remember  in  our
previous  tutorial  we  had  test  block
test  two
and  because  they're  blocked  they  can't
send  them  messages  so  it  completely
stops  them  from  being
able  to  communicate  with  each  other
and  that's  why  this  is  happening
so  if  i  remove  this  let's
see  what
happens  if  i  do  that  so
we'll  go  ahead  and  come  in
here  we'll  control  s  we'll  hit
play  and  then  we'll  try
it  one  more  time  so  we'll
do  submit  test  to  submit  test
join  direct  chat  test  to  join
direct  chat  test
we  will  send  a  message  and
that  will  now  work  now  the
reason  why  this  didn't  work  was
because  test  had
test  two  blocks  so  since  they're
blocked  they  can't  communicate  at  all
so  that's  the  reason  why  this
happened  so  it  was  my  fault
but  that  was  basically  the  reasoning
now  if  we  go  ahead  and
stop  this
and  then  we  come  in  here
and  uncomment  this  with  control  k
and  then  we  run  this  bad
boy  in  theory  we
should  be  able  to  see  our
previous  communications  so  test  to  join
direct  chat  and  you  will  see
there's
all  of  our  messages  now  i'm
getting  a  little  bit  additional  messages
mostly  because  of  my  testing
not  because  of  a  problem  with
nakama  that's  just  something  that  i
did  on  my  own  by  accident
but  you
can  see  here  are  all  of
the  messages  that  we  have  so
that's  basically  how  you  do
messages  back  and  forth  inside  of
nakama
hey  guys  editor  mitch  here  so
something  that  you  should  do  once
you  do  your  chat  system  and
you
get  that  guy  settled  when  you
have  this  chat  right  here  what
you  should  also  do  is  subscribe
to
everybody's  channels  so  if  you  have
friends  or  some  kind  of  channel
system  you  need  to  subscribe  to
that
channel  so  what  i'm  gonna  do
is  come  up  to  my  on
login  login  button  down  so  when
i  press  my  login
i'm  gonna  go  ahead  and  come
in  here  and  i'm  gonna  have
sub  to
friend  channels  like  that  now  i'm
gonna  scroll  down  and  i  have
a  chat  section  in  here  so
you  can  see
we  have  our  little  group  section
right  here  we  scroll  down  we
have  a  chat  room  code  right
here  so  this  is
our  chat  section  so  right  here
just  somewhere  in  this  general  section
here  we're  gonna  go  ahead  and
add
in  the  ability  to  sub  to
the  friend  channels  right  so  we'll
say  funk  sub  to  friends  channels
like  that
and  then  what  i'm  gonna  do
is  say  var  results  is  equal
to  await  client  dot  list  friends
asynchronously
i'm  gonna  pass  in  my  session
and  that'll  just  bring  in  all
of  my  friends  and  then  from
here
i  can  go  ahead  and  subscribe
to  their  channel  so  for  i
in  results  dot  friends
like  that  and  then  i'm  gonna
go  ahead  and  say  var  type
is  equal  to  nakama  socket  dot
channel  type  dot
direct  message  and  then  i  can
go  ahead  and  pull  back  my
chat  that  i  have  so  i
can  sub  to  that  channel
so  i  can  say  await  socket
oh  i  have  sub  to  friends
sub  to  friend  so  we'll  do
friend  channels  and  that'll  fix
that  little  function  not  found  so
socket  dot  join  chat  async  and
then  i'll  go  ahead  and  pass
an  i  dot
user  dot  id  comma  type  comma
true  comma  false  and  that'll  basically
allow  me  to  pull  those  sockets
back
now  this  should  return  if  i
remember  correctly  a  channel  so  if
we  actually  hit  ctrl  f  you
can  see  we
have  a  couple  of  them  you
can  see  we  have  current  channel
right  here  so  what  i'm  going
to  do  is  i'm
going  to  come  in  here  and
say  chat  channels  is  equal  to
await  socket  okay  and  actually
now  that  i  think  about  this
let's  do  this  so  we'll  do
channel  let's  do  this  channel  is
equal  to  this  and  then  we
can  come  down  here  and  just
say
chat  channels  bracket  bracket  bracket  bracket
bracket  bracket  bracket  bracket  bracket  i
dot  user  dot  id
actually  i  wonder  if  i  should
do  dot  user  name  instead  that
way  it's  just  a  more  common
value
and  i  could  go  is  equal
to  channel  like  that  and  that'll
basically  hook  our  channel  here  to
this  object
so  i'll  say  var  and  then
there  we  go  and  chat  channels
doesn't  exist  yet  but  now  we
have  a  key
value  pair  here  that  we  can
use  and  that's  going  to  be
really  big  for  us  if  we
want  to
use  those  channels  later  so  now
i  can  go  ahead  and  grab
chat  channels  i  can  go  up
to  the  top
var  chat  channels  like  that  and
i  can  actually  come  in  here
and  now  i  have  access  to
all  of  my  chats
right  here  so  if  i  have
like  100  chats  i  could  actually
pull  back  the  channel  information  and
switch  between  them  really  easily  using
this  object  and  i'll  probably  go
through  that  later  but  it's  a
way  to  extend  our  chat  to
be  a  bit  more  useful  if
that  makes  sense  so  if  you
think  about  it  like  this
basically  what  we  could  do  is
we  could  add  in  a  tab
container  right  here  make  that  guy
full  screen
and  then  underneath  that  tab  container
you  can  actually  switch  between  different
tabs  right
and  i  think  what  we  could
do
and  again  this  is  going  to
be  a  lot  of  coding  and
then  we  could  actually  come  in
here  make  this  about  i
know  about  this  big  give  or
take  and  then  we  could  put
that  chat  text  underneath  here  right
and  this
would  allow  us  to  in  theory
do  this  and  then  change  the
title  of  this  to  username  like
so  you  can  see
here  here's  the  username  so  what
we  could  do  at  least  in
theory  is  on  startup  once  we
subscribe  to
all  of  those  all  of  those
channels  it  would  just  fill  this
out  so  for  instance  if  we
come  in  here
and  we  go  and  subscribe  to
those  friend  channels  so  if  we
grab  this  guy  bring  it  down
here  come  in  here
and  then  basically  just  say  tab
container  or  i  guess  it's  going
to  be  dollar  sign  tab  container
dot
add  child  and  then  we  could
add  a  child  of  this  text
box  here  so  basically  if  we
box  and  i'm  just  kind  of
thinking  this  through  as  i  talk
to  you  guys  so  my  apologies
for  how  confusing
this  is  probably  going  to  end
up  being
but  we  could  do  a  text
box  so  this  is  going  to
be  a  text  edit  so  var
current  edit  is  equal  to  text
edit
dot  new  like  that  and  then
we  could  pass  in  our  current
edit  like  that  to  make  that
a  object  and  then  we
click  on  the  text  edit  is
equal  to  our  user  name  right
here  so  i  dot  user  dot
user  name  like  so
and  then  when  we  log  in
you'll  see  that  i'm  going  to
have  a  tab  right  here  called
username  but  if  i  click
on  login  and  it's  mad  at
me  so  you  can  see  invalid
index  test  2.  so  let's  take
a  look  at  this  so  create
chat  null  so  this  is  a
null  object  it  needs  to  be
a  type  dictionary  that's  my  guess
at  least  so  we'll
come  in  here  we'll  say  colon
equals  bracket  bracket  like  that  and
that'll  make  it  into  an  object
and
now  if  we  try  it  it
should  in  theory  work  there  we
go  and  you  can  see  we
have  test  2  and  username
right  here  and  that  means  that
we  would  be  able  to  go
and  fetch  any  messages  that  we
want  from  that
person  so  if  we  were  to
go  in  here  sub  to  friend
chat  go  down  here  we  could
actually  go  and  fetch
that  person's  information  if  you  remember
we  actually  do  that  right  here
we  pull  back  the
messages  right  here  so  what  we
could  do  is  if  we  list
channel  messages  asynchronously  we  should
probably  pull  this  out  and  just
do
list  messages  like  that  do  this
it's  going  to  want  to  have
a  current  channel  dot  id
so  current  channel  like  that  and
then  we  could  come  in  here
and  just  do
current  edit  dot  text  is  equal
to  list  messages  and  then  we
have  to  pass  in  our  current
channel  so
that  would  be  our  let's  see
channel  right  here  so  channel  so
we'll  pass  to  that  channel  that'll
pass
back  all  of  the  text  in
that  channel  this  is  a  coroutine
so  it  must  be  called  with
await
that  makes  sense  so  await
and  then  instead  of  doing  this
we'll  just  return  that  value  so
we'll  just  say  var  text  oh
i  guess
i'm  gonna  have  to  create  a
text  so  var  text  is  equal
to  quote  and  then  we'll  need
to  just  do  text  plus
equals  blah  and  then  we  can
just  return  our  text  like  that
and  then  that  will  return  text
right  here
and  then  instead  of  doing  this
when  we  join  a  chat  group
we  can  just  go  dollar  sign
or  we  could  just  go
go  in  here  and  add  in
a  panel  like  what  we're  doing
right  here  you  can  see  how
we're  joining  chat  asynchronously
so  we  really  could  just  grab
this  section  here  and  just  paste
it  right  here
on  this  guy  like  so  and
that'll  basically  solve  that  problem  right
there  now  technically  this  is  duplicated
code  and  that's  probably  not  the
most  ideal  situation  but  that's  probably
okay  for  right  now
and  instead  of  doing  our  chat
channel  i  username  what  we  would
do  is  we  would  do  something
like
current  channel  and  then  selected  group
so  selected  group .id  the  current
name  would  also
be  the  selected  group  id  i
guess  we'd  probably  want  to  come
up  with  a  better  way  maybe
we  could  just
call  it  current  group  right  instead
of  the  name  like  so  and
then  we  could  probably  come  in
here  and
list  our  current  channel  as  well
and  in  theory  that  would  work
so  now  if  we  hit  play
in  theory  we  would
have  a  tabular  messaging  system  now
we  can  hit  submit  and  there's
all  of  our  messages  right  there
and  we  have  different  tabs  that
we  can  work  with  i  think
if  i  do  test  it's  probably
going  to  get  mad
at  me  invalid  index  id  that
makes  sense  because  current  channel .id
current  channel  is  null  my  guess
is  because  i'm  not  in  a
channel  yet  so  that  would  make
sense  so  what
we  would  need  to  do  is
we  need  to  make  our  tab
container  handle  that  when  the  tab
gets  switched  which
i  think  there  is  a  on
tab  changed  right  here  so  we
would  have  to  keep  track  of
which  index  our  stuff
is  actually  located  in  so  i
think  that  that's  okay  so  we
could  actually  just  do  this  on
tab  changed
like  so  and  then  we  could
just  keep  track  of  what  index
we're  on  when  the  user  changes
their  tab  it  kind
keeps  track  of  keeps  track  of
that  so  how  i  would  do
that  is  if  i  go  into
where  the  tabs  are  located
so  you  can  see  here  and
i  know  this  is  probably  a
little  bit  confusing  and  my  apologies
i'm  just  kind
of  working  through  it  with  you
guys  but  so  you  can  see
right  here  we  have  a  channel
uh  selected  group  id
current  channel  so  what  we  could
do  is  when  we  do  our
tab  container  we  could  actually  connect
our  um
tab  changed  event  and  then  bind
the  um  user  id  to  it
so  we  could  do  is  we
could  do  dollar  sign  panel  tab
container  dot  add  child  like  so
but  we  could  do  dot  tab
changed  dot  connect  and  then  we
can  put  on  tab
changed  and  i  guess  i  should
do  on  chat  tab  changed  dot
bind  and  i  can  pass  in
the  selected  group  id  like  so
and  then  we  could  do  that
so  and  then  we  could  come
in  here  and  just  say  func
on
chat  tab  changed  like  so  and
then  we  could  pass  in  int
tab  comma  or  i  guess  it
would  be  i'm  sorry  i'm  trying
to  code  in  c  sharp  tab
colon  int  comma  and  then
we  could  pass  in  group  id
or  channel  id  like  that  and
that  would  pass  in  that  value
like  that  and  there
we  go  so  what  that's  going
to  do  is  allow  us  to
print  well  uh  tab  comma  channel
id  like  that  and  that
will  give  us  the  ability  to
work  with  this  now  when  we
join  a  chat  group  that's  how
we  have  to  handle
that  but  when  we  do  our
sub  to  friends  channel  we  got
to  do  that  as  well  so
that  way  we  can  do  it
on
both  so  now  if  i  hit
play  in  theory  if  i  do
submit  it's  mad  at  me  unable
to  get  index  id  on  base
nil
that's  because  selected  group  is  null
and  that's  because  i'm  dumb  and
i  chose  the  wrong  bind  it's
going
to  be  i  dot  user  dot
username  so  we'll  grab  that  and
paste  it  right  here  let's  try
that  one  more  time
so  i'm  going  to  come  in
here  i'm  going  to  go  submit
and  it  once  again  is  going
to  be  mad  a
non -existent  function  bind  on  base
int  that's  mad  about  let  me
see  i  think  i  might  have
figured  it  out
what  if  i  do  this  instead
and  then  i  have  to  go
and  find  my  other  bind  which
should  be
i  think  i  need  to  put
it  out  inside  the  the
signal  connection  so  i'm  connecting  i'm
binding  this  to  the  signal  not
to  the  connection  function
i  think  that's  what's  doing  it
so  let's  try  that  let's  grab
the  other  one  so  you  can
see  how  this  one
connect  dot  bind  instead  i  think
i  need  to  bind  and  then
do  that  and  then  i  should
be  able  to  make
that  work  and  i  believe  it
is  index  and  then  channel  id
so  let's  try  that  let's  see
what  that  does
there  we  go  and  then  if
i  click  test  two  it  should
have  displayed  test  two  right  there
so  that's  perfect
so  what  that  means  is  that
we  can  go  current  channel  is
equal  to  chat  channels  bracket  bracket
channel  id  like  that  and  then
what  that  means  is  now  we
should  be  able  to  since  we're
binding  those
parameters  i  should  be  able  to
send  a  message  and  it  should
just  take  it  in  theory  invalid
get  text  on
null  that's  fine  my  guess  is
that's  because  chat  text  box  doesn't
exist  anymore  because  now  we're
going  the  opposite  direction  right  so
we're  sending  a  message  if  you
see  here  if  you  look  at
the  content
messages  test  type  is  zero  and
if  you  take  a  look  at
this  object  it  has  the  channel
id  sender  id
user  id  12  and  then  user
name  now  if  we  take  a
look  at  our  channel  objects  right
here  so  chat  channels
you  can  see  test  two  is
our  parameter  here  that's  going  to
be  our  players  information  if  that
makes  sense
so  i  think  we  could  probably
get  away  with  since  this  is
going  to  give  us  test  as
its  content  and  the
message  is  going  to  say  sender
id  is  right  here  the  channel
id  is  right  here  i  wonder
if  we  should  pull
because  it  has  a  username  right
here  but  that's  not  going  to
hook  us  up  to  our  channel
code  so  i'm  curious
if  we  need  to  change  how
we  send  our  data  across  so
we  send  our  data  we're  sending
the  message  and
then  the  current  channel  id  okay
so  i  think  i  know  what
i'm  going  to  do  here  so
we're  actually  going  to
change  up  a  little  bit  how
we're  doing  this  and  the  reason
why  i'll  show  you  if  we
take  a  look  at
right  here  we're  passing  in  our
current  channel  what  i'm  going  to
do  is  i'm  going  to  come
in  here
and  pass  in  instead  of  just
a  current  channel  i'm  going  to
pass  in  channel  like  that  colon
current
channel  and  then  i'm  also  going
to  pass  in  a  label  value
just  so  i  can  have  the
label  if  i  need  it  for
whatever  reason  and  the  label  in
the  selected  group  id  will  probably
just  be
group  chat  because  it  really  doesn't
need  to  have  anything  special  and
if  we  go  to  the  other
one
so  channel  chats  we  go  to
the  other  one  which  is  right
here  so  this  one  needs  to
go  dot  channel
because  we're  making  that  adjustment  real
quick  you  can  see  right  here
we're  doing  channel  so  you  can
see
we'll  need  to  make  that  adjustment
and  then  we'll  just  copy  this
guy  right  here  we'll  paste  it
like  so
and  then  i'm  going  to  go
ahead  and  pass  in  ctrl  x
channel  like  that  and  that  will
allow  us  to  have  an  object
that  has  a  label  here  and
then  for  the
actual  label  itself  i'll  just  pass
this  guy  in  like  that  and
then  i'll  just  do  channel .id
like  that  and  then  if  we
have  this  then  we  should  be
able  to
use  this  to  pull  back  that
channel  information  instead  and  i  know
what  you're  thinking  that
doesn't  sound  like  it's  going  to
work  but  it's  probably  not  going
to  work  so  let's  go  ahead
and
say  on  tab  change  bind  selected
group  id  if  i  do  on
tab  changed  bind  channel  id
like  that  and  then  when  we
produce  our  message  here  we're  going
to  be  fetching  back  this  on
channel
message  parse  the  content
and  right  here  we  will  have
a  chat  box  so  you  can
see  we  have  chat  chat  box
it'll  be  tab
container  dot  get  node  like  that
content  dot  and  if  we  take
a  look  at  what  our  message
is  going  to  be
right  here  see  how  we  have
our  right  message  asynchronous  we'll  just
say  content  dot  id  like  so
and  then  here  we  can  pass
in  quote  id  colon  and  fetch
back  our  channel  information  so  chat
channels
like  so  channel  id  so  it'd
be  current  channel  dot  id  right
here
like  that  and  that  will  pass
back  our  channel  information  and  then
from  here  we  could  just  go
dot
label
and  that  should  allow  us  to
fetch  back  the  correct  node  and
set  the  proper  information  right  there
and  in  theory  that  would  work
let's  try  that  and  see  how
that  works  so  if  we  hit
submit  test  to
test  send  you'll  see  that  we
now  get  our  test  information  so
this  is  a  test  message  like
that  and  we  click  go
you'll  see  this  is  a  test
message  just  like  that  and  that's
basically  how  we  can  make  a
tabbed  system  as
well  that  should  actually  work  for
our  chat  system  so  now  that
we  have  a  basic  chatting  system
that  fully  works
let's  talk  about  how  we  can
host  this  out  on  the  cloud
because  the  best  way  to  get
your  networking
working  is  by  hosting  it  out
on  the  cloud  that  means  that
you  have  to  pay  a  server
to  host  that  information
so  if  you  want  a  multiplayer
game  you  need  to  actually  pay
to  host  that  data  somewhere  right
and  that  is  where  digital  ocean
comes  in  digital  ocean  is  a
pretty  great  tools  kit  that  will
allow
you  to  host  your  projects  right
here  on  their  servers  and  it's
relatively  cheap  if  you  take  a
look  at  the
pricing  you  can  see  they  have
some  pretty  cheap  droplets  so  if
you  wanted  a  cheap  like  five
dollar
server  to  host  your  game  that's
more  or  less  what  this  is
for  is  it  allows  you  to
actually  host  stuff
out  in  the  cloud  for  relatively
cheap  and  i  will  drop  a
link  in  the  description  below  that
if  you  guys
use  it  it  will  give  me
credits  to  be  able  to  host
my  own  stuff  now  i  will
be  hosting  stuff  for
this  tutorial  here  i'll  be  giving
you  guys  an  ip  address  and
you  guys  can  use  it  for
your  testing  but
just  know  that  if  you  want
to  go  out  into  production  you
need  to  use  your  own  server
and  something  to  keep  in  mind
you  can  host  your  own  server
as  well  locally  but  it's  a
lot  harder  it's
not  as  safe  and  people  can
hack  into  your  networks  and  things
like  that  so  it's  really  nice
just  to  use
something  like  this  to  host  it
for  you  so  that  you  can
get  your  game  out  there  and
get  people  playing
it  and  playing  together  so  let's
go  ahead  and  create  an  account
or  log  in  whichever  one  you
guys
have  so  i'm  going  to  go
ahead  and  log  in  real  quick
so  this  is  digital  ocean  and
basically  the  nice  thing
here  is  this  is  your  dashboard
right  so  this  is  the  digital
ocean  dashboard  so  here  is  where
you  can
manage  all  of  your  resources  now
you  can  see  up  here  you
have  your  profile  information  and  then
you
have  whatever  droplets  you  have  now
in  digital  ocean  droplets  are  considered
machines  okay  and  you  can
see  that  they  have  all  sorts
of  really  cool  features  here  they
have  spaces  which  is  basically  like
storage  they  have  database  stuff  so
if  you  actually  come  in  here
you  can  see  that  you  can
spin  up  databases
right  here  so  if  you're  using
nakama  you  can  actually  store  your
database  outside  of  your  droplet
and  allow  for  load  balancing  they
actually  have  a  full  built -in
load  balancing  system  right  here
spinning  up  a  load  balance  so
you  can  actually  choose  different  data
regions  and  pass  data  in  between
different  regions  and  things  like  that
by  using  their  load  balancers  now
that  being  said  that's  way  beyond
the  scope  of  this  tutorial  but
that's  what  i'm  trying  to  say
is  digital  ocean  has  a  bunch
of  stuff  for  you  to  use
that  can  help  you  get  up
to  the  point  where  you  can
use  nakama  premium
and  actually  have  them  handle  a
lot  of  that  for  you  but
this  is  a  good  way  to
kind  of
get  started  into  that  if  that
makes  sense  so  let's  go  ahead
and  talk  about  how  to  create
a  droplet
so  let's  go  up  here  to
the  upper  right  hand  corner  click
on  create  click  on  droplet  you
could  do  an  app
platform  that's  technically  going  to  be
cheaper  but  it's  a  lot  harder
to  get  everything  set  up  properly
so  i'm  just  going  to  do
a  droplet  for  right  now
and  so  we  can  pick  what
region  we  want  our  droplet  in
so  right  here  i'm  going  to
choose  new  york  new
york  is  the  closest  to  me
so  we'll  choose  that  we'll  come
down  here  and  you  could  choose
an  image
now  if  you  have  a  specific
image  that  you're  looking  for  go
ahead  and  pick  it  right  here
in  my  case  i'm  going  to
go  with  ubuntu  but  if  you
want  to  you  can  also  look
at  the  marketplace  and  you  can
pick  different  stuff  so  docker  on
ubuntu  probably  would  be  a  good
image  to  get  or  maybe  something
like  lamp  if  you're  trying  to
do  a  lamp  server  or  wordpress
or  something  like  that  they  have
so  many
different  droplets  that  you  can  actually
use  have  at  your  disposal  you
can  see  here  you  can  also
do
custom  images  so  if  you  have
an  image  you  can  actually  just
spin  it  up  and  have  it
work  now  in
my  case  i'm  going  to  go
with  os  ubuntu  we're  going  to
start  from  base  even  though  technically
docker  on
ubuntu  probably  is  a  better  option
so  i'm  going  to  go  so
so  i'm  going  to  go  with
marketplace  docker  on
ubuntu  that's  going  to  save  us
a  lot  of  trouble  and  get
it  all  set  up  for  us
right  so  all  we  have  to
do  is  get  our  docker  composed
and  then  set  up  our  firewall
rules  and  we'll  be  good  to
go  so  we'll  go
ahead  and  add  that  guy  now
if  you  come  in  here  you
can  see  that  you  have  a
bunch  of  different
options  for  size  now  it  depends
on  what  you're  trying  to  do
and  typically  what  i  tell  people
is  you  want  to  pick  the
lowest  value  that  you  can  and
plus  one
so  for  instance  if  you  think
that  your  game  is  going  to
be  really  small  and  not  a
lot  of  people
are  going  to  play  it  then
something  like  the  14  a  month
one  is  probably  pretty  good  if
you're  looking
for  something  really  cheap  just  for
testing  if  you  go  to  regular
and  you  kick  it  over  you
can  see
that  you  can  just  do  something
like  the  six  dollar  a  month
one  or  even  the  four  dollar
a  month  one  if
you  can  get  away  with  under
10  gigabytes  if  you  were  to
come  up  here  and  choose  os
ubuntu  then  you  could
go  down  to  four  dollars  a
month  at  512  megabytes  now  once
you  get  down  that  low  this
is  basically  only  used
for  testing  you  want  to  have
six  dollars  a  month  a  month
one  gigabyte  one  cpu  just  because
it's  going
to  allow  you  to  have  a
lot  more  flexibility  for  your  project
now  since  i'm  doing  a  marketplace
image  of
and  now  since  this  is  going
to  be  a  tutorial  i  should
probably  just  do  ubuntu  with  the
four  because  odds  are
you're  not  going  to  have  the
funding  to  do  this  or  something
like  that  so  we'll  try  the
four  we  might
have  to  upgrade  to  six  we'll
see  and  then  you  can  see
here  that  you  can  add  a
volume  which  will  allow
you  to  expand  your  disk  space
now  in  our  case  we  don't
need  that  because  it's  fine  for
right  now  and
you  can  see  that  we  have
authentication  so  we  have  ssh  key
and  password  now  in  my  case
we're  just  going  to  do
so  i'm  going  to  set  my
password  right  here  and  we'll  scroll
down  here  and  you  can  see
that  we  can
do  improve  metrics  and  monitoring  for
free  so  may  as  well  turn
that  on  and  i  don't  think
we  need  to  do
a  database  cluster  here  but  we
can  look  at  that  in  the
future  so  you  can  see  here
is  our  host  name
right  here  which  i'll  call  it
youtube2  tags  i'm  not  worried  about
it  and  then  you'll  see  that
it  has  a
project  right  here  now  this  project
is  where  it's  going  to  get
built  under  so  don't  worry  it'll
just
get  built  under  your  account  and
then  we'll  click  create  droplet  now
this  is  going  to  allow  us
to  have
a  droplet  once  it  gets  built
which  should  be  relatively  quick  there
we  go  you  can  see  it's
in
the  middle  of  building  it  and
it  is  now  completed  so  it
actually  created  your  little  droplet  right
here
so  now  at  this  point  once
we  click  into  it  you  can
see  here  is  our  youtube  2
droplet  you  can  see  we  have
our  graphs  for  our  bandwidth  cpu
usage  stuff  like  that  we  have
access  which  allows  us  to  adjust
our  access
to  it  we  have  power  which
allows  you  to  turn  it  off
and  on  we  have  volumes  which
allow  you  to  have  block
storage  resize  which  allows  you  to
change  how  big  and  strong  that
droplet  is  so  you're  welcome  to
go  in  and
actually  upgrade  this  later  so  if
you  need  that  one  giga  memory
or  that  one  10  gigabyte  ssd
right
that's  all  stuff  that  right  here
is  available  and  then  you  can
come  in  here  and  go  into
networking  you
can  change  your  network  ip  address
your  firewall  stuff  you  can  come
in  here  and  back  it  up
you  can
get  snapshots  of  it  so  that
way  if  you  need  this  droplet
to  be  perfect  and  snapshotted  for
backup  purposes
this  is  what  this  is  for
it  allows  you  to  basically  go
back  to  that  point  in  time
and  apply  it  to  your
image  so  the  nice  thing  is
is  if  you  create  snapshots  and
your  stuff  gets  hacked  or  something
like  that  you  can  roll  back
to  that  snapshot  and  stop  that
hack  from  happening  kernel  is  something
that
you're  not  going  to  be  using
but  basically  it  allows  you  to
upgrade  your  linux  kernel  history  is
the
history  of  it  destroy  allows  you
to  destroy  that  droplet  tags  allows
you  to  tag  it  and  recovery
allows  you
to  try  to  recover  your  droplet
now  that  we've  gone  through  all
of  this  let's  go  up  to
our  console
here  and  click  on  that  you'll
see  that  that's  going  to  pop
up  a  droplet  console  now  this
is  pretty  cool
because  you  actually  have  a  full
linux  machine  here  so  if  you
don't  know  linux  now  is  the
time  to  learn
because  linux  is  very  important  to
know  so  first  things  first  inside
of  ubuntu  to  install  docker
what  you  need  to  do  is
you  need  to  type
sudo  apt -get  update  and  that's
going  to  update  all  of  your
mirrors  out  there  and  then  we
need  to  go  in
and  actually  add  the  repository  because
docker  doesn't  actually  exist  in  the
repo  by  default  so
we'll  say  sudo  apt -get  install
ca -certificates  curl  like  that  and
that's  going  to  go  ahead  and
make
sure  that  we  have  curl  installed
and  then  we'll  sudo  install  dash
m  0755  dash  d
slash  etc  slash  apt  slash  apt
slash  key  rings  and  then  we're
going  to  go  in  and  curl
out  to  the  docker
linux  ubuntu  i  will  actually  leave
these  commands  in  the  comments  below
by  the  way  so  you  guys
can  use  it
but  sudo  curl
dash  f  s  s  dash  l
f  s  capital  s  l  https
colon  slash  slash  download  dot  docker
dot  com  slash  linux
slash  ubuntu  slash  gpg  dash  o
space  slash  etc  slash  apt  slash
key  rings
slash  docker  dot  asc  and  what
that's  going  to  do  is  it's
going  to  actually  create  a  docker
gpg  apt  repo  for
you  so  that  way  you  can
actually  go  and  install  docker  and
then  we  need  to  allow  access
to  it  so
sudo  ch  mod  a  plus  r
slash  etc  slash  apt  slash  key
rings  docker  asc  and  that  basically
allows  us  to
execute  and  use  that  data  that's
right  there  so  basically  linux  is
a  permission
system  that  is  very  very  aggressive
so  you  need  to  make  sure
that  you  keep  that  stuff  under
wraps
if  that  makes  sense  so  uh
linux  by  default  does  not  give
you  permissions  to  anything  and  you
have  to
give  yourself  permissions  to  it  so
that's  kind  of  what  we're  doing
right  here  so  then  we  can
come  in  here
and  finally  fire  off  our  apt
resources  now  this  command  is  going
to  be  really  difficult  to  do
so  we'll  do
echo  slash  enter  and  that's  going
to  allow  us  to  kind  of
get  a  actual  script  going  here
so  we'll  say
quote  deb  space  bracket  arch  equals
dollar  sign  dpkg  dash  dash  print
dash  architecture
signed  by
equals  slash  etc  slash  apt  slash
key  rings
slash  docker  dot  asc  bracket  https
colon  slash  slash  download  dot  docker
dot  com  slash  linux  slash  ubuntu
and  then  we're  going  to  put
that  in  dollar  sign  dot  slash
etc
dot  slash  etc  slash  os  dash
release  and  we're  going  to  echo
our  version  code  name
and  we're  going  to  pull  back
the  stable  version  like  that
we're  going  to  pass  in  a
pipe  and  we're  going  to  pipe
that  into  sudo  t  slash  etc
slash  apt  slash  source  dot
list  dot  d
slash  docker  dot  list  greater  than
sign  slash  dev
slash  null  and  i  know  that
that's  a  terrible  command  but  basically
all  this  command  is  doing  is
we're
going  and  we're  adding  in  we're
going  deb  all  of  this  information
and  we're  piping  all  this  info
into  our
sudo  our  sources  list  right  here
for  docker  and  that's  basically  all
we're  doing  here  i  know  that
it  seems  really
confusing  but  that's  basically  what  we're
doing  here  now  i'm  going  to
double  check  this  command  because  i
just
spotted  a  mistake  right  here  where
i  did  equal  equal  instead  of
dash  dash  so  let  me  double
check  this  command
and  make  sure  that  i'm  happy
with  it  so  we  have  arch
e  dollar  sign  d  package  our
print  architecture  we're
going  to  sign  it  by  our
docker  asc  file  and  we're  going
to  go  out  to  our  docker
linux  ubuntu  and  we're
going  to  pull  back  the  os
release  and  i  misspelled  echo  right
here  you  can  see  i  made
a  mistake
as  always  you  make  a  million
mistakes  when  you  do  this  so
echo
so  that's  e -c -h -o
and  then  we  have  our  version
code  name  that  we  are  echoing
into  our  release
we're  pulling  back  the  stable  edition
we're  going  to  pipe  that  into
sudo  t  right  here  into  our
docker
lists  and  we're  greater  than  slash
dev  null  and  we'll  run  that
command  eco  is  not  found  that's
because
i  spelled  echo  wrong  so  i
guess  it's  good  thing  that  i
that  it  failed  immediately  so  e
-c -h -o  and  we
will  try  running  it  hopefully  this
doesn't  blow  up  all  right  so
we  have  no  such  file  or
directory  so
all  right  so  i  think  i
figured  it  out  basically  there  is
an  issue  with  the  command  for
i  think  it
was  this  area  here  so  don't
worry  just  copy  what  i  have
in  my  description  and  just  use
that  and  it  will
just  work  for  you  so  now
all  i  got  to  do  is
type  sudo  apt  dash  get  update
like  that  and  that's  going  to
update  all  of  our  packages  in
our  repo  and  it's  going  to
go  and  fetch  out  to  the
docker  system  and  pull  back
the  actual  docker  packages  so  you
can  see  right  here  it's  actually
pulling  down  that  information
right  there  and  then  we're  going
to  go  ahead  and  install  docker
so  sudo  apt -get  install  docker
-ce
docker -ce -cli
container .io  docker -build -plugin  and
finally  the  most  important  one  of
the  group  docker -compose -plugin
and  that's  the  big  one  that's
the  one  that's  actually  going  to
matter  for  our  project  for  the
most  part  i  mean  the  rest
of  these  are  obviously  important  docker
-ce  is  the  docker  runtime  docker
-ce -cli
is  this  command  line  interface  the
uh  container  is  the  actual  container
uh  system  docker  build
plugins  is  to  build  your  own
docker  containers  and  then  docker  compose
allows  you  to  actually  compose
dockers  based  off  of  a  docker
composition  file  if  you  remember  before
when  we  talked  about  how  to
build  nakama  that  was  one  of
the  big  things  that  you  need
to  use  so  we'll  hit  enter
it's  going  to  go
ahead  and  try  to  pull  it
it  says  that  it  cannot  locate
the  docker  build  plugin  my  guess
is  i  spelled
something  wrong  here  so  let's  see
docker  build  x  plugin  there  we
go  hit  go  and  it  should
go  ahead
and  download  and  install  docker  now
we  might  need  to  upgrade  to
the  next  step  up  to  the
one  gigabyte
edition  but  we're  going  to  see
if  we  can  get  away  with
the  four  dollar  a  month  version
first  and  if  we
can't  then  we'll  upgrade  to  the
six  dollar  a  month  version  and
then  we  can  run  our  docker
setup  here  so
we'll  see  how  this  works  but
we'll  go  from  there  so  it
looks  like  it  is  running  if
we  type  ps  you  will
see  that  we  have  a  bash
and  ps  running
so  if  we  type  docker  is
it  going  to  pop  up  and
there  we  go  so  we  do
have  docker  running  so  perfect
that's  exactly  what  we  want  so
now  from  here  we  need  to
get  a  docker  compose  file  onto
here  so  if  we  type  ls
right  here
you  can  see  that  we  have
nothing  going  on  so  what  we
can  do  is  we  can  type
mk  dir  nakama  cd  nakama
like  that  and  that's  going  to
get  us  into  that  directory  so
mk  dir  makes  the  directory  cd
nakama
just  brings  us  into  the  nakama
directory  so  now  we  can  come
in  here  and  basically  compose  our
docker  file
so  if  we're  lucky  we'll  be
able  to  just  copy  and  paste
our  composition  file  so  if  we
go  out  here  we
go  to  documents  and  we  find
our  nakama  instance  i  believe  i
have  a  nakama  server  tutorial  docker
compose
dot  yaml  so  if  we  open
this  guy  up  you'll  see  this
is  what  our  docker  compose  file
looks  like  you  can  see
right  here  this  is  what  it
looks  like  so  if  we  hit
ctrl  a  ctrl  c  and  then
we  go  into  our  web  browser
here  and  we  type  nano  docker
dash  compose  dot  yml  and  then
we  right  click  paste  it  should
paste  all  that
data  right  into  here  so  that
way  we  don't  actually  have  to
set  up  filezilla  because  one  of
the  things
that's  unfortunate  is  a  lot  of
times  if  you're  doing  godot  networking
you  need  to  actually  put
files  up  into  filezilla  and  into
the  ftp  and  bring  them  over
to  digital  oceans  to  your  digital
ocean
droplet  so  thankfully  we  can  just
copy  and  paste  this  and  control
x  y  and  it'll  be  docker
compose  dot  yaml
and  now  from  here  we  should
be  able  to  just  get  it
to  run  if  we're  lucky  so
what  we'll  do  come  in  here
and  type  docker  compose  up  and
you'll  see  it's  going  to  go
ahead  and  attempt  to  pull  and
build  our  docker
instance  right  here  now  we  might
run  out  of  ram  it  just
kind  of  depends  but  hopefully  with
512  megs  of
ram  it's  going  to  be  really
tight  i  don't  know  if  this
is  going  to  work  we're  probably
going  to  need  a  gig
but  we  can  see  so  we'll
let  this  run  and  we'll  attempt
to  run  it  and  it  looks
like  it  might  have
worked  so  what  we  can  do
is  if  we  go  out  to
our  youtube  2  we  grab  our
public  ip  we  go  to  our
nakama
console  and  we  just  put  in
actually  i'll  just  make  a  new
thing  colon  and  we'll  put  in
7351  so  7351  enter
does  it  do  anything  that's  the
first  question  it  doesn't  look  like
it's  going  to  so  now  we
got  to
figure  out  is  it  this  guy's
fault  it  looks  like  this  is
running  so  my  question  is  server
is  ready
to  receive  web  requests  so  it
did  spin  up  properly  it  started
the  rule  manager  properly  so  that's
good
news  oh  you  can  see  it
is  just  absolutely  chugging  though  so
if  we  take  a  look  at
our  youtube  docker
container  let's  see  it  looks  like
our  cpu  utilization  is  pretty  high
our  disk  io  is  relatively  high
as
well  we  probably  need  to  upgrade
to  have  one  gig  of  ram
but  at  least  it  is  running
so  there  is  that
the  question  is  so  i  was
able  to  get  it  to  stop
so  what  we'll  do  is  we'll
close  it  we'll  go  to  our
youtube  we'll  go  over  to  upgrade
droplet  and  then  we'll  go  ahead
and  just  upgrade  that  up  to
one  size
larger  to  the  one  gigabyte  edition
so  we'll  do  that  and  then
we'll  click  cpu  ram  when  it's
going  to  ask
us  to  turn  off  our  droplet
so  we'll  go  up  to  power
we'll  power  it  off  because  there's
nothing  on  here
anyway  so  we  can  just  power
cycle  it  pretty  hard  there  we
go  it's  powered  down  we'll  go
to  resize
and  we'll  adjust  it  up  one
size  just  to  let  it  be
the  proper  size  that  it  needs
to  be  we're  going  to
let  that  run  you'll  see  it's
thinking  about  it  there  we  go
and  now  we  got  a  one
size  bigger  droplet
now  we  can  go  ahead  and
power  cycle  that  bad  boy  back
on  let's  go  into  our  networking
let's  come  down
to  our  firewall  and  create  a
firewall  now  the  firewall  is  just
going  to  be  test  firewall  and
what  we'll  do
is  we'll  have  an  inbound  of
ssh  we're  also  going  to  allow
we're  going  to  allow  a  custom
one  and  we're  going  to  allow
for  7351  so  we'll  copy  that
bad  boy
and  we'll  go  ahead  and  paste
it  like  that  and  then  we'll
do  the  same  thing  for  7350
as  well  and  then
we're  going  to  allow  another  one
which  is  going  to  be  7351
udp  and  7350  udp  that  way
we  can  have  all  of
our  stuff  all  of  our  ducks
in  a  row  and  everything  kind
of  covered  now  you  can  see
here  all  outbound
is  good  and  we  should  be
good  to  go  so  we'll  go
ahead  and  hit  create  firewall  and
that  should  create
that  firewall  onto  that  networking  system
so  if  we  go  to  our
droplet  and  we  go  to  youtube
2  you  should  see
right  here  under  our  firewall  networking
no  firewalls  are  applied  to  this
droplet  so  i  need  to  apply
this
firewall  so  let's  see  if  we
need  droplets  we  can  choose  our
droplet  add  droplet  and  then  we
will
search  for  youtube  2  and  we'll
go  ahead  and  connect  it  to
that  droplet  so  now  that  should
give  our  droplet
the  firewall  it  needs  to  do
its  job  so  now  we  should
be  able  to  go  to  console
and  fire  that  up
and  then  hit  cd  nakama  and
then  docker  compose  up  and  in
theory  it  should  run  a  lot
faster  which  it  is
you  can  see  it's  actually  firing
off  just  well  the  init  node
was  successfully  done  cockroach  database  is
up
so  now  we're  starting  to  get
the  proper  logs  that  we  expect
so  my  guess  is  it  had
something  to  do  with
the  lack  of  ram  that  we
had  so  let's  try  that  we'll
refresh  and  there  we  go  so
you  can  see  now  we  have
knock  about  running  out  on  our
website  which  is  one  nine  eight
nine  one  nine  nine  eighty  one
one  eight  and  you
guys  of  course  can  go  to
this  and  use  it  so  if
you  type  admin  password  you  can
see  we  have  our  nakama
instance  just  like  before  and  it's
exactly  the  same  so  you  guys
can  actually  use  this  for  your
own
project  providing  that  it  doesn't  get
shut  down  immediately  because  for  some
reason  it  gets  shut
down  sometimes  and  that  causes  some
issues  but  that's  how  easy  it
is  to  get  this  to  fire
off  now
and  in  order  to  detach  let's
hit  ctrl  c  we'll  stop  our
docker  connection  right  here  and  you'll
see  in  a
second  it's  going  to  gracefully  stop
so  we'll  give  it  a  minute
to  kill  everything
we'll  hit  docker  compose  up  dash
dash  detach  what  that  should  do
is  it  should  allow  us  to
fire  this  up
and  be  detached  and  there  you
go  so  now  we're  detached  so
if  we  hit  ps  you'll  see
that  it's  not
running  but  if  i  come  in
here  and  i  refresh  you  can
see  that  nakama  is  running  if
i  close  this  and  i
refresh  you  will  see  that  nakama
is  running  even  though  we  are
no  longer  connected  to  our  docker
instance
so  that's  how  we  can  actually
get  that  to  run  without  needing
to  keep  that  window  open  because
if  you
is  running  like  that  previously  without
running  the  dash  dash  detach  then
it  would  have  closed  that
docker  instance  and  then  your  whole
project  would  have  been  gone  so
that's  basically  how  that  works
so  now  if  we  head  out
to  godot  here  we  can  come
up  to  here  and  change  this
value  to  our  nakama  instance
so  if  we  come  in  here
you  can  see  here  is  our
nakama  instance  right  here  so  we'll
copy  that
we'll  paste  this  like  so  and
then  if  we  hit  play  you
will  see  that  we  can  now
submit  and  log  in  so
you'll  see  that  i  have  logged
in  so  now  if  i  take
a  look  at  my  nakama  instance
out  here  on  the  web
if  i  refresh  you'll  see  that
when  we  go  to  accounts  i
have  an  account  right  here  just
like  as  if  i  was
playing  the  game  locally  so  this
is  how  that  works  and  you
can  come  in  here  and  go
test  two  and  you'll
see  that  if  i  click  name
of  match  test  join  create  test
join  create  we  just  joined  our
match  and  then
if  the  host  says  start  game
and  then  start  game  you'll  see
that  we  both  started  our  game
now  something
here  is  broken  but  i  don't
think  that  that's  a  nakama  issue
i  think  that's  just  a  my
code  issue  so
you  can  see  that  we  are
transferring  the  data  as  expected  here
in  our  nakama  instance  so  we
do  have
the  presences  as  expected  but  i
feel  like  something  here  is  wonky
a  little  bit  and  i  think
that's  because
i'm  not  in  the  right  scene
to  do  this  i  think  i
have  to  go  to  game  manager
dot  tscn  if  you  remember
this  is  our  game  manager  here
so  let's  refresh  this  guy  let's
try  re -running  it  so  we'll
hit  test  test  to
test  join  create  test  join  create
start  game  start  game  and  you
can  see  that  our  game  is
now  running
not  locally  anymore  so  this  will
work  with  your  friends  across  the
web  and  what  i'm  going  to
do
is  i'm  going  to  go  get
one  of  my  friends  and  i
will  have  him  hold  my  code
and  then  he  will  also  do
this
and  i'll  show  you  guys  that
it  does  work  out  on  the
internet  so  i  will  be  right
back
okay  and  then  hit  start  game
and  as  you  guys  can  see
right  here  my  friend  and  i
are  both  working
together  and  playing  the  same  game
at  the  same  time  over  the
internet  using  our  nakama  instance  now
you  can  see  here  that  there
is  a  little  bit  of  lag
and  i  think  the  reason  for
that  is  because  we're
flooding  the  actual  nakama  instance  because
it  has  a  bunch  of  data
that  it's  passing  through  so  we
should  probably  figure  out  a  better
way  to  optimize  this  but  at
least  we  have  it  working  for
now
so  at  this  point  we've  gone
through  quite  a  few  things  we
talked  about  groups  we  talked  about
chatting  and  we  talked  about  how
to  get  our  stuff  to  work
out  on  the  internet  for  our
project  and
allow  us  to  work  on  multiple
networks  with  each  other  so  if
you  like  this  video  go  and
hit  that
like  button  hey  you  know  if
you  dislike  this  video  go  and
hit  that  dislike  button  because  i
am  here  to
make  content  for  you  guys  this
video  was  a  viewer  suggested  video
so  if  you  have  any  suggestions
please
leave  them  in  the  comments  below
or  jump  on  my  github  link
is  in  the  description  and  put
in  a  service  ticket
and  i'll  be  more  than  happy
to  add  it  to  my  list
of  tutorials  for  the  future  and
hey  if  you  have  any
questions  or  comments  about  this  video
go  ahead  and  leave  them  in
the  comments  below  or  jump  on
my  discord
the  link  is  in  the  description
and  i'll  be  more  than  happy
to  help  you  out  but  that
is  all  i  have  for  you
guys  today
so  thank  you  so  much  again
for  watching  and  i  will  see
you  all  next  time  thanks
miss
y